<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Citizenship</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20240130-citizenship/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Citizenship
January 30th, 2024
----------------------------------------

Tomorrow I have a call with the US Embassy in Iceland. It's an
informal interview in preparation for my renunciation of
citizenship. Friday is the big in-person meeting where I'll make
it official. No more US citizenship for me! In a few days I'll be
Italian and only Italian (at least for now). I'd like to get
Icelandic citizenship when I qualify in a few years.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Doing A Whole Lot Of Nothing</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20240111-doing-a-whole-lot-of-nothing/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Doing a whole lot of nothing
January 11th, 2024
----------------------------------------

Today I've finally lightened up on meetings at work. Monday
through Wednesday were just packed full of phone calls. So today
I was excited to not have a ton of things interrupting my day. But
lo and behold, I have been stricken by the not-give-a-shits.

So I will not be accomplishing anything today. In fact, I'm gonna
get away from the computer and go read a bit. Tonight I'll go to
my hackerspace meetup, and then see a film. Tomorrow can be for
work again.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>I Just Wanna Read</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20240108-i-just-wanna-read/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
I just wanna read
January 08th, 2024
----------------------------------------

WHaaaaa!!

(That's me crying)

I don't wanna today. Gimme coffee, a nice warm blanket, and
a mountain of books. I just want to read.

I just started on Being Arab and it's fascinating! I'm listening
to Jin Yong's 3rd part of the Legend of the Condor Heroes as well.
I love it so much.

Once those are done I have hundreds and hundreds more. All the
entertainment. All the adventures. But no... I need to get on
conference calls like a sucker. Booooooo.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20240102-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
January 02nd, 2024
----------------------------------------

Be it resolved:

The dance-craze of 2024 will be known as "The Tomasino".

2023 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20221231-resolution
2022 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-resolution
2021 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201231-resolution
2020 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution
2019 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions
2018 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What A Year</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20231114-what-a-year/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
What a year
November 14th, 2023
----------------------------------------

What a year it's been. I've barely been on gopher or gemini at
all. So much going on!

What's eating up all my time? Well, at the start of the year it
was work, and then getting sick, and then more work as we took on
a whole extra client that we were pretty sure wasn't gonna stick
around. That turned out to be correct, and by not staffing up to
it we avoided having to fire a bunch of people, which I'm thankful
for. But then I was spent as well.

Summer happened, some travel, some not travel, things started
settling. Then I traveled for work to a different client thing and
got covid again. That sucked. My cough is mostly gone, finally.

Then I decided to take Icelandic seriously and enrolled in the
University of Iceland in a full-time college program. Now that's
dominating my mornings all week every week, followed by my job
dominating the afternoon and evenings. In the small gaps I get
that aren't filled with study, I've been playing in a few TTRPG
games. Well, running them, mostly, but that counts as play.

I'm in my last regular week of classes now, and final exams are
two & three weeks out. Then I have the holiday break before the
second semester. Thankfully this is only a two semester program,
so by June I'll be back to my own life again.

Oh! and Season 2 of Solarpunk Prompts has started up. I'm writing
and recording that somewhere in the middle of everything else.

I miss you, gopher! I'll be back, I promise. *sigh*
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Riot Medicine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20230618-riot-medicine/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Riot Medicine
June 18th, 2023
----------------------------------------

I just added a page to my archives [0] area of this gopherhole for
Riot Medicine [1], an open source medical guide for street medics.

Riot Medicine is a full-length textbook that covers everything you
need to become a medic. The 466 pages include organizing, medcine,
equipment, and tactics. It is written for those with no medical
training and no experience at protests, but medical practitioners
and seasoned protesters will still find it useful.

There's also a field guide: symptoms and treatments without
theory, designed to be included in your field kit. Also available
in Spanish.

And there's a bridge guide for those already working in healthcare
designed to prep for the street environment.

And finally there is a printable Basic First Aid zine.

[0] Archives
    gopher://gopher.black/1/archive
[0] Riot Medicine
    gopher://gopher.black/1/archive/riotmedicine
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Years Cleanup</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20230104-new-years-cleanup/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
new years cleanup
January 04th, 2023
----------------------------------------

I went through moku-pona[0] to clean up some shenanigans today.
A lovely person reached out to me to be added to the list (hi
bandali! [1]) and while I was in there I noticed my perl stuff was
acting up. I guess the XML parsing was broken, so I did some CPAN
work and I think it's good again. I also noticed a handful of
phlogs whose servers seem to be down. I trimmed them for now. If
they return and want re-added I can do that later.

Grex.org in particular is a challenge. That server has long
periods of downtime, but usually comes back. I have a handful of
people there in the list and I've left them for now. We'll see if
it pops back online again at some point.

- - - - -

I've been really sick for the past few weeks. My son got the flu
about a week before school let out. He was in bad shape and we
nearly went to the hospital. Thankfully his fever broke, but by
then my wife caught it, and then it was my turn. My flu, as per
usual, developed into pneumonia and I'm still coming out of that
funk. I think this cough will be with me a while yet.

This weekend I'm going to try to record a new episode of Solarpunk
Prompts [2], my podcast series about the movement. If you haven't
checked it out before please do so. It's for writers, but many
non-writers enjoy it as well. The episodes are only about 10
minutes long. I recommend listening to the intro episode first as
it lays out what the podcast is about and its reason for being.
After that you can listen to the episodes in any order.

Oh! The podcast is not only followable in podcast apps and RSS
like normal, but you can also follow it on Fedi! Check out:
@SolarpunkPrompts@podcast.tomasino.org

I hope you all had a really great holiday and new year.

[0] moku pona
    gopher://gopher.black/1/moku-pona
[1] bendali
    gopher://kelar.org/1/~bandali/
[2] Solarpunk Prompts
    https://podcast.tomasino.org/@SolarpunkPrompts
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20221231-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
December 31st, 2022
----------------------------------------

Be it resolved:

This year I will be responsible for an urgent travel advisory to
the middle east.

2022 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-resolution
2021 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201231-resolution
2020 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution
2019 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions
2018 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
