<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Data Security Ratings/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180810-data-security-ratings/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Data Security Ratings
August 10th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Christina has been posting about data security [0][1] with some
engagement from others [2].

[0] Christina - Infosec And Data Privacy Part 1
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~christina/InfosecAndDataPrivacy.txt
[1] Christina - Infosec And Data Privacy Part 2
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~christina/ISDP_2_SelfRating.txt
[2] Solderpunk - Data Security Ratings
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/data-security-ratings.txt

It's very interesting stuff which started on Mastodon and
continued in gopherspace. It's worth a read.

I had one last thought I wanted to share based on an exchange on
IRC. Some people have brought up threat levels and planning your
security for the type of danger you really face, not ridiculous
levels of paranoia. We're not all Snowden, after-all. That being
said, I wanted to share my email system so you can see what
happens when you go off the deep end with no real reason.

First of all, I use neomailbox for my mail provider. They're
pretty great, in a country with better data privacy laws than the
US, and have solid privacy policies and encryption measures in
place to protect their users. They offer a unique feature that
I've not found in other providers: they will auto-sign incoming
mail with your public key if you request it. While mail that
wasn't encrypted at the source may still be vulnerable in
transmission, after it hits their servers its safety just took
a major step up.

Next, I only connect to neomailbox over a VPN & Tor. Outgoing mail
relayed through their servers wipes metadata anyway, but it's just
another stupid thing to do in protecting the connection itself.
How do I connect? Good old pop3, baby. I don't leave anything on
the server.

Mail is fetched locally and the system auto-disconnects from the
internet. When browsing messages I remain offline. I reply and
queue up my outgoing mail. When ready to send, browsing shuts down
and the machine reconnects safely to send it on its way.

The local maildir is backed up over spideroak, encrypting the
mailboxes of already encrypted messages offsite to another machine
in case of calamity.

That's it! Fun right?

I want to reiterate, this is completely unnecessary for my threat
level and it was done more as a hobby project to see how far
I could push it. Airgapping, redundant encryption, it's too much
for people to bother with. It's a great illustration of why other
people give up and just settle for whatever.

If you're new to infosec, do yourself a favor and get a protonmail
account. That's about as good as you're going to do without
putting in a bunch of work. Is it as good as what Snowden does? Oh
hells no. But you're not on the run from the US government, are
you? It'll keep google off your back, and you're less likely to
fall victim to simple scams.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reunion/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180806-reunion/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reunion
August 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This past weekend I went to the Tomasino family reunion in Ohio.
It was good to see my sister and her family, and to run into all
the other relatives that I haven't seen since I was my son's age.
It was nice for him to experience a reunion as well. He doesn't
see anyone but my wife and I most of the time since we don't live
near any of our family and soon will be moving much further away.

I like to say that my sister inherited all the roots and I got all
the wanderlust. My parents and their parents all grew up in
Youngstown, Ohio, where our immegrant ancestors all settled. They
were fruitful and multiplied and most of the brood has remained
fairly close to that nexus. When my parents married they moved
away chasing work leading to my sister and I being born in
Virginia. We lived there briefly and then a few years in Maryland
before heading to New Jersey where we both completed high school.

That was enough for my Sister. She went to college back in
Youngstown and never left again. All the years growing up she
talked about going "back" and she didn't hesitate. 

I took the other approach. Growing up away from extended family,
I learned to love the move. After high school I did a brief stint
in college before joining the Navy. I moved a lot in the service,
and then a lot more afterwards. After college #2 and grad school,
the moves continued. I've managed to live in 15 states now, and
I'm thrilled to get out of the United States finally.

On the one hand, I think I can thank my sister for my own freedom
of place. She is an anchor in the family that allows me to float
free. While we were in Ohio I spent a few days in her company
wandering Youngstown, Austintown, Struthers, and Lowellville. In
every single place we stopped, be it restaurant or school or
grocery or playground, we met someone that knew her well enough to
stop by and talk. She is so entwined with the place it is a part
of her and she of it. My brother-in-law functions in the same way.
His family owns so much local farm-land and have roots so far back
it doesn't make sense. He is an engineer who built this or that as
we drove around, and who coaches this team and that team, or
helped review the building plans for this guy's daughter's shop.
It's a fascinating life they have, and I'm so happy they get to
have it.

That sort of thing may not appeal to me personally but I can see
the glamour in it and the comfort it can provide. I have no
argument against it. It's just not for everyone.

She and my brother-in-law talk about how exciting it will be for
my family to go abroad, but how they could never do it. I see why,
and it isn't sad at all. We have chosen vastly different paths and
both are thrilling in their own way.

~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~

At the reunion itself we had a few fun surprises:

 - My neice found out her science partner in school last year was
   actually her long lost cousin. If I have my math right, they're
   4th cousin's once removed, but it is a little tricky...

 - My great, great grandfather was married twice. The daughter
   from his first marriage married the brother of his second wife.
   Go ahead and unpack that a little while. I'll wait.

 - My cousin is the production manager for Hamilton on Broadway!

 - My 98 year old grandpa has been listening to the same GE radio
   for 50 years. It still works perfectly. Ridiculous.

 - I'm related to pretty much the entire town of Lowellville,
   Ohio. Here's a video from the 30s and 40s of the town
   celebrating a wedding in the 30s and the Feast of Our Lady of
   Mt Carmel (July 16th, 1946)[0]. I watched this with my grandpa
   and he named pretty much everyone in here at a glance. The guy
   with the suave hair at 13:13 is my great uncle, my grandpa's
   brother. He was a funny guy.

[0] Lowellville Ohio
    http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FMlhECYsxno

 - The best part of the parade is the Baby Doll Dance [1]

[1] Baby Doll Dance
    http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8xyZRLwZSkU#t=1m
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tabs Vs Spaces/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180729-tabs-vs-spaces/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Tabs vs spaces
July 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's a post on lobste.rs right now [0] about tabs & spaces.
Don't go read it, there's no point. You've already read everything
there is to be said on the subject. Seriously. Don't follow this
link to the lobste.rs comments either.
[0] Elastic tabstops - a better way to indent and align code (comments)
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/julienxx/Lobste.rs/1ugcr4.txt

I don't think I have an official Opinion(TM) already floating out
there in the inter-ether, so I'll use this opportunity to give my
two cents. I'm pro tabs, with caveats.

I'll start with the caveats because they're the easy part. I will
use spaces in any of the following situations:

  - The language spec calls for spaces (i.e., python)
  - The team styleguide calls for spaces
  - The codebase I'm interacting with has already established the
    use of spaces over tabs
  - I'm working with someone who is a die-hard advocate for spaces
    and won't shut up about it unless I just give in

Here's why I prefer tabs:

Indentation distance is a visual preference which should be
enforced by the person working with the code, not the maintainer
of the code. If I want to develop using eight spaces as the visual
indentation of blocks, then I should do that. There is no valid
reason(*) that my personal choice of tabstop should be followed by
any other developer who is also working with this code. But how
can we both get it the way we want and not have to constantly
battle over the indentation style? What method could we possibly
use? Oh right... a fucking tab.

Tabs can be set to visually show up at whatever distance you want.
If you like a tiny tiny little increment, set a tabstop to two
characters, or even 1! If you like a giant leap along the line, go
for eight, or ten, or whatever. That's it. Just set it up how you
want to see it.

There's another reason, though I consider it of less importance.
A tab is a single character. Spaces are multiple characters. Why
add multiple characters to something when you don't have to?
Semantically, indent with the single character that accomplishes
that. Then you're done. Tada!

(*) I must address the usual counter-argument here: the alignment
of parameters, equal signs, or other nonsense that cascades down
from an arbitrary point on the line. Spaces can make everything
pretty, like ascii art. That's a plus! If we use tabs we can't do
that and we'd have to suffer endlessly with vertically listed
parameters that don't line up with the spot where the first
parameter fell naturally on the line. This is true. I think using
a single flexible character for code indentation that lets people
do things their own way far outweighs code knolling [1].

[1] Knolling
    http://mitphoto2016.wordpress.com/2016/09/19/knolling-messy-vs-neat/

So, in summary: I don't care how you wanted your code to be
viewed. I want to view it the way I prefer, which lets me work
faster and easier. Use a tab. Let me set my own definition for
what that means.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopherpedia/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180726-gopherpedia/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gopherpedia
July 26th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm having a little squee party. Sometimes I like to pop over to
gopherpedia [0] and see what people have recently been viewing.
Unlike wikipedia which gets a lot of traffic, our gopher corner is
relatively quiet. Of note today was someone who viewed both the
book 1984 and the list of Newspeak words. That caught my eye since
they're related and I amused myself with wondering which of my
gopher friends it was and what they were up to.

The culprit has revealed himself [1]!!!

[0] Gopherpedia
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/1/
[1] On web as newspeak
    gopher://1436.ninja/0/phlog/typezero/20180726.post
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Game Ideas/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180725-game-ideas/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Game ideas
July 25th, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's a new Kickstarter fund going called Your Best Game Ever,
by Monte Cook [0]. He's done a ton of RPG writing in the past,
including the D&D 3rd Edition DM's Guide and about a thousand
others. His most recent work was on Numenera, which is pretty cool
if you haven't checked it out before. This new fund is to create
a book which will help you run a game and a gaming group and get
the most out of the experience. It's not about the rules, but
rather about all the other stuff that's not in the books. Sounds
pretty cool, right?

[0] Kickstarter - Your Best Game Ever
    http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/montecookgames/your-best-game-ever

As I was backing that crowdfunding campaign I started thinking
about my own games that I've run in the past, want to run in the
future and the infinite abyss of lameness that is my time NOT
playing an RPG with friends. Ugh, it's awful!

I want to run a game, but I think I need a new format. My local
crew can't manage to do an in-person game reliably, and it's
really not the same working online. It's too easy for the quiet
folks to stay quiet and the active players dominate. It's too easy
to get lost browsing new skills and spells instead of getting into
the session. It's too easy to do anything other than play.

That's the heart of the experience for me, too. The play. The role
play, in game, in character voices and in their heads; making
decisions that your character would make, not that you would.
I miss that part terribly, even in the games I'm playing now.

So I was thinking about running something different. Screw the
system. Screw all the rules. Screw everything that isn't the
role-playing around a table. When I first started RPGs seriously
it was in a setting like that, with my next door neighbor. We
never bothered to crack a book or worry about skill points or
levels. We let the character explore and become someone new, and
told the story together. I would describe my actions and he would
describe the outcome. Battles weren't about hitpoints. They were
about good tactics and planning.

I also don't want to worry about telling an infinitely open-ended
story. This game is not going to be a richly created world that's
free to explore. It will have a setting that hooks the players
from the start and pulls them along the adventure. They will
change the outcomes, they will change the world, but not by
galavanting off to the next town on a whim. I'm thinking the
setting won't even have another town! I'm thinking of something
otherworldly with a mist of unknown descending upon a remote
hamlet. Adventure is survival in the face of mystery. 

And what fun it will be to create a real mystery, or series of
mysteries, for the characters to figure out and explore. If my
plotting works it will take planning, notes, and active work on
the their part to figure things out in time. "In time for what?"
you ask? Well, that's part of the stakes! In this case, time will
be a major factor in survival, and a major limitation in the
choice of action.

Yes yes... lots of plans coming to me. I'll need to start writing
it all out, mapping out all the ideas, and then find the right
group to explore it with me. Hopefully I can run this one soon.
I really miss role playing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Italian Citizenship/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180721-italian-citizenship/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Italian Citizenship
July 21st, 2018
----------------------------------------

Today I am officially an Italian citizen. I went though an
extremely long process to claim my citizenship via a process
called jure sanguinis. I proved, in essence, that I have always
been an Italian citizen by way of birth since my ancestor who
immegrated had children before becoming naturalized. Thus, his
kids were born as Italians on foreign soil.

My son also has Italian citizenship as a result, and we're going
to file for my wife to get hers via marriage. I'll be getting
a second passport soon, and when the dust settles, we'll be
leaving the United States.

If you read this phlog, you probably already know that our
destination is Iceland, which will allow me residency now since it
is part of the Schengen Agreement, just like Italy. Moving to
Iceland as an American is a giant pain in the butt, but as an
Italian it should be quite simple.

This made my whole day, obviously, but it also helps me out in
some bigger stress areas. I've been stressing about what to do
next in my career. I have an opportunity to potentially move into
a CTO role with a startup, which fascinates me and would challenge
me quite a bit. It would also be an increased investment on my
time, and I already work a lot. The job I'm at now is wearing on
me more and more, and I don't see it as sustainable for very much
longer. The move to Iceland represents a refocusing of priorities
off of work and onto life. I'm planning on taking a significant
pay cut, living more simply, and focusing on the family and
hobbies. Since that timeline is finally "for real", it means that
my current work troubles have an end in sight. That is powerful.

While I finish getting all the papers in order for the family,
we'll also be selling our house and moving into a much smaller
apartment. We'll get rid of most of our things, place most of the
leftovers into storage, and live on what we intend to ship. Once
all that's in place, I'll be quitting my job, heading to Iceland
on my own ahead of the family, and we'll live off the house sale
money until I can find a new job, get us a new apartment, and
arrange to move them over and meet me.

I'm utterly thrilled!

Oh, if any of you reading this are Icelandic, live or know someone
in Iceland, or in any way could help me find something
code-related to do in Iceland to get us settled I'd be extremely
grateful. I run a technology team of web developers, front & back
end. I also act as the digital strategy lead (pharmaceutical
marketing) and head of analytics & reporting. I can code in JS
extremely well, and prefer using vue, but can learn whatever. My
php & python skills are a little rusty, but I can jump back into
that in a heartbeat. Ruby? I guess I could do that too. I'm not
much of a windows development guy, though.

Need a programmer? Need someone to run a dev team? Need an
analyst? I'm also good at balancing stuff on my chin!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hard Things/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180720-hard-things/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Hard things
July 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is just a reminder:

Do the hard thing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Ftp Find/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180720-gopher-ftp-find/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gopher ftp find
July 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

@sparcipx@mastodon.sdf.org found a really nice treasure trove of
gopher goodies on an ftp server [0]. I'm out of the house, so I'm
writing this to remind myself to do some archiving of the content
when I get home.

[0] ftp archive
    ftp://ftp.sunet.se/mirror/archive/ftp.sunet.se/pub/gopher/Unix/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Left/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180717-the-left/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Left
July 17th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I just received the following email on an account I have which
monitors conservative political action. I have similar feelers
into a few different areas so I can keep tabs on things. This one
stood out, especially in light of Trump's recent meeting with
Putin.


----------------------------------------
|   Authorized By Trump Headquarters   |
----------------------------------------

James,

Have you seen the Democrats lately?

They're completely unhinged.

They’re all over this country vowing to go further and further to
the Left. For weeks, they’ve been calling for harassment,
intimidation, even the abolishment of ICE! Now, they’re promising
to block President Trump’s Supreme Court nominee from ever
reaching the bench.

They want to ignore our laws, abuse our people, and obstruct our
agenda by subjecting Judge Kavanaugh to a long, drawn out
confirmation process.

They think their new tactics will chase all “deplorables” into
hiding… but the silent majority is not backing down. We’re getting
together and we’re standing up. We’re knocking on doors and
reaching voters for our National Week of Action to protect our
President and make sure we win big in November.

And we need YOU to join us by going door to door to spread our
message
 
REGISTER TO VOLUNTEER

James, the way I see it, if liberals want to come for our borders,
for our jobs, and OUR Supreme Court, and they’re willing to stop
at nothing to make that happen.

We CAN win for the Silent Majority -- not by stooping down to the
left’s level -- but by volunteering in your neighborhood to turn
out voters and spread our positive message of putting America
FIRST.

Please, join us for the National Week of Action.

Thank you,

Chris Carr
Donald J. Trump for President, Political Director

------------------------------------------------------------------

What struck me most was the blatant use of the Left as an entity
of otherness. Notice that it's the Left coming for OUR borders,
Supreme Court, laws, and jobs. The Left wants to abuse OUR people.
This is an interesting and dangerous shift in rhetoric. It is
essentially calling liberals anti-American and digging deeper the
divide.

In a similar email last month the language used was based on
fighting, shooting, and violence in general. "Strike back!" they
cheer.

This is the stuff that later generations will point to with
disgust and say, "how did they not see it coming?"
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cwondr/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180716-cwondr/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CWONDR
July 16th, 2018
----------------------------------------

yargo writes [0] about a cool Morse/CW project he's working on.
A low-power, pocket-sized CW transceiver for the 430 Mhz band: for
Morse code. I love it! I don't have much interest in getting into
HAM stuff (mainly because I know it would end up being a huge time
sink for me) but I love Morse and I think I could dig something
little and portable like this. If you make it, I'll use one!

[0] yargo - CWONDR, another Morse/CW project
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/yargo/glog/t18414-cwondr.txt

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
