<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>A Little Reminder</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181107-a-little-reminder/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A little reminder
November 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Whether you're thrilled or devestated with the events of the past
few days, I just wanted to remind everyone that representative
government is terrible all around! :D
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dad</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181106-dad/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Dad
November 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

My dad can't feed himself anymore. I want to scream about that or
cry about it depending on the moment. Instead I sit quietly and
think about him through my life. The good moments come to me. I'm
not sure where the bad ones went, with time.

I remember throwing a ball, playing with a tape recorder, being
chased on a field. I hold strong.

His voice calls my name and I answer, "daddy" and I am six years
old. I am my own son, and I see all our eyes. Then I cry.

I'm not ready for him to go.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knives</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181027-knives/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Knives
October 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm on my way out the door to a Halloween party, so I'll make this
quick. Knives are awesome. They are tools first, weapons second,
and infinitely useful. I'm a Mora Classic #1 and #2 kind of guy.
I have some Baretta tactical knives thate are pure beauty and
a karambit that is sex in sickle form, but the work horse knife
for me is the Mora. It runs about $12 retail in the US, and if
well cared for it's multi-generational. The steel is excellent,
the handle is sturdy. Great stuff.

I'm disappointed in knife limiting laws. I don't see much of
a parallel with gun control there. Gun's are instruments of death.
Knives CAN be, but it is not a primary purpose. It's the same with
an axe, or a hammer, for that matter. I like useful things, and
sometimes those useful things are also beautiful. Knives... mmm.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Seasoning</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181019-seasoning/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
seasoning
October 19th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I recently acquired a pair of beautiful pans. You may already be
aware that I have a distinct preference for cast iron cookware,
and so it may surprise you to learn that these pans are different.
Instead of cast iron, these pans are wrought iron!

US-ION ran a kickstarter [0] for what they call "Solidteknics Iron
Skillets". They've developed a machining process allowing them to
mass produce wrought iron instead of cast iron. The result is
theoretically both lighter and more durable. Quite a claim!

[0] Solidteknics Iron Skillets
    http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/495892923/solidteknics-pans-1pc-wrought-iron-not-cast-lighte

Cast iron (and now wrought iron) cookware is an heirloom item.
Rather than buy-it-for-life, it's buy-it-for-generations. That's
value I can get behind! This lifespan doesn't come without some
effort, though. You must care for your stuff if you want it to
last. This is true of pretty much everything, but it bears
repeating. My lovely leather shoes need polish. My knives need
sharpening and oil. Iron needs seasoning.

What is seasoning? In layman's terms, it's a coating of oil that
goes through a chemical bonding to the surface of your pan. It
protects the iron and makes it non-stick. It's safe! It won't
break down and poison you like other **coughTEFLONcough**
coatings.

Is it a lot of work? I don't think so, but others disagree.
There's also about 7,000 different opinions on how best to keep
a pan clean over time, "properly" season it, etc. Here's my
method; you can decide for yourself if it's too much work.

  -  -  -  -  -  -    Initial Seasoning    -  -  -  -  -  -  

Brand new iron is naked and fragile. If you buy an unseasoned pan
it may look like steel or it may be black already. Regardless, it
needs some extra special care right in the beginning to get things
off to the best start. Putting on the initial layers of oil is the
slowest part and requires the most effort. After this, upkeep is
extremely simple.

To season a cast iron (or wrought iron) you'll need the following:

  - sandpaper, fine grit
  - a clean cotton rag or old t-shirt
  - a can/tub of vegetable shortening
  - the pan/skillet/dutch oven/whatever
  - an oven that can reach 480°F

1. Begin by thoroughly scouring the pan clean. It may have shipped
   with beeswax coating to protect it in transit, or there may be
   old layers of seasoning to work off. Hot water, scrub with
   soap, do it to it.

2. Dry the pan by hand, and then in the oven under low heat until
   you're sure there's no moisture on it at all.

3. Lightly scratch up everything with the sandpaper. Roughing the
   surface will help the first layer of oil bonding.

4. Heat your oven to 480°F or there-abouts.

5. Dab your cloth into the shortening, then rub it over the whole
   pan, inside and out. Make sure you get the handle too. Don't
   leave anything untouched. You don't need a lot of shortening or
   a thick coat. In fact, the thinner the better. Wipe it on and
   then use a clean part of the rag to wipe it off again.

6. Place the pan upside down into the oven. Cook it for 90
   minutes.

7. Turn off the heat and allow the pan to cool completely.

8. This is the sucky part. Now that you've put a single coat on
   your pan, it probably doesn't look too different. It may have
   darkened slightly or maybe not. This initial process needs to
   be done at least twice more. If you have the time over the next
   couple days you should do it as much as you can. I usually do
   five or six iterations. Go back and repeat steps 4-7. You don't
   need the sandpaper on every round. You can use it a second time
   after that first seasoning if you want, but I don't bother
   after that.

9. Your pan is now mostly seasoned, but it can use a little extra
   love in the cooking area still. For this secondary seasoning,
   we'll use your stove top! Crank the heat on a burner to high
   and get ready.

10. Add a thin layer of shortening to the inside of your pan and
    also a bit to the base, but don't bother with the handle this
    time. We're focused on the cooking area.

11. Place the pan on the burner, but get ready with your cotton
    rag. Wrap it around a wooden spoon or grab it in some tongs so
    you can use it on the pan while it's on the heat.

12. For the next minute or two, continuously wipe the cotton on
    the pan while it heats up. This will cause it to smoke A LOT.
    Open some windows, turn on a fan, etc. Let it smoke like this
    for up to 30 seconds, then cut the heat.

13. Allow the pan to cool for 10 minutes, then repeat steps 9-13
    a few more times.


Your pan should be uniformly black. It should not feel sticky or
tacky to the touch. If it does, you have too much oil on it still
and it didn't fully bake in. Wipe it down with a clean cloth and
toss it in the oven at 480°F again for another 30 min to get
everything fully baked in.

You can use this thing to cook now! But cook on what? That's the
best part. You can cook on anything from an induction stove to an
open fire. It's so versitile!

You might notice a little sticking of delicate foods like eggs
& fish when you first start using it. That's because your
seasoning is just at its beginning. That effort may have seemed
like a little or a lot, but it's the start of the long road of
maintenance that will make your pan better and better with every
use.

 -  -  -  -  -  -    Maintenance Seasoning    -  -  -  -  -  -  

Every time you use the pan you need to clean it. This should also
go without saying, but people get really weird about cast iron and
logic seems to go out the window. Much conventional wisdom says
that you don't need soap, or SHOULD NEVER USE SOAP, with your pan.
I'm here to tell you that's a bunch of crap. Please use soap.
Clean your pan well. Stay healthy. Don't be gross. But how...

1. Clean of the physical bits from your pan with a hard plastic
   scraper or metal that won't gouge the seasoning. I have a 6"
   square of chainmail that I use. Don't press super hard, just
   get all the stuff off the surface.

2. Soap and water and clean the thing like you would any other
   pan. Seriously. It's fine. If you want to be extra cautious,
   don't use a lemon based cleaner. Acids wear down seasoning (not
   that fast).

3. THE MOST IMPORTANT STEP!!!! Dry the everliving shit out of that
   pan. I hand dry mine and then immediately place them back on
   a burner and crank it to medium heat to cook off any lingering
   water. Soap doesn't harm anything, but it will if little bits
   of it remain on the surface. Water will do much, much worse.
   Rust sucks (though even that can be fixed).

4. While the pan is still warm from the drying heat, dab a bit of
   vegetable shortening on a rag and do a quick surface rub on the
   inside and base (don't do the handle unless you plan on putting
   it back in the oven to bake).

5. Crank a burner to high heat and cook & smoke that shortening
   for a minute or two. Then congratulate yourself on adding yet
   another layer of seasoning to your awesome pan of awesome. This
   is what will build up more and more over time and turn it into
   the only pan you ever want to use for cooking anything ever.
   Ever.

6. Let it cool, and put it away for 20 minutes until you can't
   wait to use it again!


That's it. That's my routine with all my iron. The new wrought
iron pans are on seasoning #4 in the oven cooling. They'll get two
more rounds today before I start the stove top. Does that seem
like a lot of work to you? I bet my grand children will appreciate
it when they inherit the super skillets.

One final note: if you have cast iron that has rusted, it is
probably still fine as long as it hasn't created a pit or hole.
You can sand off the rust, or in extreme cases you can use some
home chemistry to remove all the rust through electrolysis [1].
Once the rust is gone, go to the start of my initial seasoning
instructions and act like it's a new pan. A day or two later and
it's back to working order. If you're a thrifty person you can
pick up old cast iron from yard sales or flea markets for
a dollar, put in some elbow grease with your shortening, and have
a brilliant cookware set!

[1] Cleaning cast iron with electrolysis
    http://www.castironcollector.com/electrolysis.php
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sprezzatura</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181018-sprezzatura/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sprezzatura
October 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Castiglione wrote The Book of the Courtier between 1508 and 1528.
It's a fantastic read, if you've never tried it before. In the
book he introduces a newly created word: sprezzatura, defined as -

  "I have found quite a universal rule which in this matter seems
  to me valid above all other, and in all human affairs whether in
  word or deed: and that is to avoid affectation in every way
  possible as though it were some rough and dangerous reef; and
  (to pronounce a new word perhaps) to practice in all things
  a certain sprezzatura [nonchalance], so as to conceal all art
  and make whatever is done or said appear to be without effort
  and almost without any thought about it."

It defined the ultimate goal of the courtiers at the court of
Urbino. Look amazing at everything without trying.

Ever since reading the book in high school that has been my
personal motto. Even mentioning it "out loud" here in gopher
undermines the effort somewhat. Talking about trying to be awesome
at everything and seem effortless ... you get where I'm going with
this.

Anyway, I wanted to mention it for two reasons:

1) When I was thinking of a show for anonradio, my first idea
   centered around sprezzatura, but I couldn't come up with a way
   to make it a thing without also completely destroying that
   thing. It's tricky! Try it in your head.

2) Some people these days are all too eager to "own" their
   failings. There's a pride in being bad at stuff. It's probably
   a generational thing. Showing vulnerability is cool as shit, or
   something. I'm drunk and an old man when it comes to this
   stuff. I'm of the opinion that if you can be a total badass at
   every fucking thing, then you should be a badass at every
   fucking thing. If you're a badass at 90% of the things, then
   focus and fix that last 10% in the quiet of your bedroom until
   you can be a rockstar there too.

That's it. The whole point of this was to tell you all to go be
badass at everything. Not good at something? Don't tell me about
it. Go fix it. No.. don't fix it, master it. Master the heck out
of that thing and then do it routinely as if it's no big deal.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading Plain Text</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-reading-plain-text/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reading plain text
October 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

While reading moji's phlog [0] I started considering how I read on
gopher, or in plain text in general versus my methods on the web.
Certainly I do more scanning in a web browser, which I attribute
at least partially to the various font and style treatments that
both allow for and promote the bite-sized ingestion of content.
There is also an element of reading fatigue that plays out
differently here in plain text, and thats where my mind went (not
to say that moji was in any way tiring).

When I'm tired of reading on gopher it is instantly apparent.
I skim over blocks of text looking for something to jump out at
me, but that isnt how it works. Warning claxxons blare in my brain
and I shut down figuratively and literally. It's clear I need to
do something else and come back later. I get no such signal on the
web. I peruse long past the point of usefulness. I trade reading
for browsing. Surfing becomes skimming. Infinite scroll is
infinitely useless.

My time in text is short and productive in the sense that I get
something from it, whether information or entertainment. My time
on the web offers sone of that, but the trappings are extreme and
it is all too easy to give more time than necessary or helpful.

This is intentional. Capitalism demands attention, and it is that
monstrosity which guides the design patterns on port 80. Even
informational sites follow the patterns because that is what
drives engagement. Look at the analytics, measure your performance
goals. How do we keep them longer? How do we show them more ads?
How do we get them to spend a little more?

I'm sick of environmental leeches. I want my landscapes clear and
clean. Mow down the billboards and flashing neon and let me get
where I'm going on my own terms, please.

There is no way out on the web. The experience is condemned to
these patterns. People scream when you try to pull that bandage
off. They demand more convenience despite the cost. The masses
want to live like this. We're the weirdos for questioning it.

[0] moji - unlearning
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~moji/phlog/20180928-unlearning.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Little Free Library Part 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-little-free-library-part-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Little Free Library, part 1
October 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Below is a list of notes I've prepared while building my little
free ebook library. What is that, you ask? Well, it's a solar
powered rapsberry pi zero w that will live off-grid with an open
wifi access point. When a user connects to it, Captive Portal will
automatically trigger a "sign-in" page. The page isn't meant to
sign into anything, though. Instead it will present users with
free ebooks for download to their devices! 

My first go will likely be a collection of PDF maps from USGS,
some trail guides and bird identification things that are
appropriate for the trail that runs past my house.

My TODO list remains:
  
  - Test apple devices captive portal
  - Design a static site page to download the ebooks


# Starting from a raspbian lite install on a raspberry pi zero w:

# After setting up your local wifi connection in wpa_supplicant,
# then proceed to make your littlefreelibrary work when away from
# home...

# Update packages to prepare

$ sudo apt update
$ sudo apt upgrade -y

# Install dependencies, but disable by default

$ sudo apt install dnsmasq hostapd nginx -y
$ sudo systemctl disable hostapd
$ sudo systemctl disable dnsmasq

# Configure

$ sudo vi /etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf

    interface=wlan0
    driver=nl80211
    ssid=LittleFreeLibrary
    hw_mode=g
    channel=8
    wmm_enabled=0
    macaddr_acl=0
    auth_algs=1
    wpa=0
    ignore_broadcast_ssid=0
    country_code=US
    ieee80211n=1

$ sudo vi /etc/default/hostapd

    DAEMON_CONF="/etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf" # change only this line

$ sudo vi /etc/dnsmasq.conf # add the following to the end of file

    bogus_priv
    addrdess=/#/10.0.0.5
    interface=wlan0
    no-resolv
    bind-interfaces
    dhcp-range=10.0.0.50,10.0.0.100,12h

$ sudo vi /etc/dchcpd.conf # add the following to the end of file

    nohook wpa_supplicant

$ sudo vi /etc/systemd/system/autohotspot.service

    [Unit]
    Description=Automatically generate an internet Hotspot when a valid ssid is not in range
    After=multi-user.target
    [Service]
    Type=oneshot
    RemainAfterExit=yes
    ExecStart=/usr/bin/autohotspot
    [Install]
    WantedBy=multi-user.target

$ sudo systemctl enable autohotspot.service

$ curl http://www.raspberryconnect.com/images/Autohotspot/autohotspot-95-4/autohotspot.txt > autohotspot
$ chmod 755 autohotspot
$ sudo mv autohotspot /usr/bin/autohotspot

# Change hostname to littlefreelibrary

$ sudo hostname littlefreelibrary
$ sudo vi /etc/hostname

    littlefreelibrary

$ sudo vi /etc/hosts

    127.0.0.1 littlefreelibrary

# Set up a cron to detect changes

$ crontab -e # add the following to the end of file

    */5 * * * * sudo /usr/bin/autohotspot >/dev/null 2>&1

# Set up nginx to work with captive portal

$ sudo vi /etc/nginx/sites-available/default

    server {
            listen 80 default_server;
            listen [::]:80 default_server;
            root /var/www/html;
            index index.html;
            server_name _;

            # For iOS
            if ($http_user_agent ~* (CaptiveNetworkSupport) ) {
                    return 302 http://littlefreelibrary.local/apple.html;
            }

            # For Android
            location /generate_204 {
                    return 302 http://littlefreelibrary.local/index.html;
            }

            location / {
                    try_files $uri $uri/ /index.html;
            }
    }

$ sudo service nginx restart

# Add apple captive portal page

$ sudo vi /var/www/html/apple.html

    <!--
    <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <WISPAccessGatewayParam xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.wballiance.net/wispr_2_0.xsd">
    <Redirect>
    <MessageType>100</MessageType>
    <ResponseCode>0</ResponseCode>
    <VersionHigh>2.0</VersionHigh>
    <VersionLow>1.0</VersionLow>
    <AccessProcedure>1.0</AccessProcedure>
    <AccessLocation>LittleFreeLibrary</AccessLocation>
    <LocationName>LittleFreeLibrary</LocationName>
    <LoginURL>http://littlefreelibrary.local/index.html</LoginURL>
    </Redirect>
    </WISPAccessGatewayParam>
    -->

# Create your library page

$ sudo vi /var/www/html/index.html

    TBD HTML code

# To manage device when in AP mode

$ ssh pi@10.0.0.5
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bug Out Bag</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181012-bug-out-bag/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Bug-Out Bag
October 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I promised that I would revisit my current bug-out bag and here
I am to follow through. Much of this was first outlined on my web
blog and the gear remains much the same. I've augmented some
things, added some new stuff, cut back on others. Let's dive in!

                  ________         ___
                 /_  __/ /  ___   / _ )___ ____ _
                  / / / _ \/ -_) / _  / _ `/ _ `/
                 /_/ /_//_/\__/ /____/\_,_/\_, /
                                          /___/

Somewhere along the way I scored a free ign.com branded gym bag.
It's made of a heavy duty material and almost feels like a bag for
a bowling ball. It holds everyhing on the list below (just
barely). There may be a time to come where I'll need to upgrade.
I'm considering moving to a pelican case for added protection, but
it will also add to the weight.


                     __  ___       ____    _ __
                    /  |/  /__ ___/ / /__ (_) /_
                   / /|_/ / -_) _  /  '_// / __/
                  /_/  /_/\__/\_,_/_/\_\/_/\__/


Why have one when you can have two (or 11)? I have the most
redundency in my medical kit selection.

- Swiss Safe Premium First Aid 200 Piece

  This thing has a lot of the basics: cotton swabs, bandages,
  alcohol wipes, antiseptic wipes, sting relief pads, PVC gloves,
  tape, moleskin, scissors, CPR facemask, a trauma pad, emergency
  whistle, compass, sewing kit, and so on. This is a base-line for
  first aid. It also has a little first aid guide in there, though
  I have a better one.

- Emergency First Aid - A Pocket Naturalist Guide

  This is a folded, waterproof pamphlet outlining the basics on
  a number of first aid scenarios. Primary responses to water
  hazards, vehicle accidents, lightning, leaking gas or smoke,
  rescue breathing, CPR, choking, shock, eye injury, burns,
  poisoning... you get the idea. It packs a lot of info into
  a very small space. While I am comfortable in pretty much
  everything on the list, my wife isn't and neither is my son. If
  something were to happen and I were not around or incapacitated,
  I can trust that they have access to the basic info.

- ZET Rapid Spinning Tourniquet

  I squeeze this little guy inside the Swiss Safe kit to save on
  space. Hoping I won't need it.

- MTM Survivor Dry Box with O-Ring Seal

  My secondary and more serious medical kit all sits within the
  nearly indestructable and completely waterproof MTM case. Pretty
  hardcore? Not yet! Inside the MTM are three Otterbox 1000 Series
  Waterproof Cases, also waterproof and nearly indestructable on
  their own. It is inside these three cases that I keep the
  contents of...

- Medique 40061 First Aid Kit, 61-Piece

  Another fantastic assortment of medical thingies! Much like the
  first list, it sports an impressive array. But it's not enough
  on its own. Also in the MTM Dry Box with it is...

- Adventure Medical Kits Trauma Packwith QuikClot

  For everything up to and including gaping chest wounds from
  gunshots. Nice right?

- Quake Kare Emergency Thermal Blankets (4 Pack)

  A lot of serious medical injury is compounded by exposure. These
  can help in a pinch. 

- Potable aqua iodine for water treatment

  I used to consider this part of the water kit, but I've
  supplimented that elsewhere. This is more of the "oh shit" water
  treatment, which in my head belongs in the medkit for reasons.

Were you paying attention? All that fits into two containers!

                     _      __     __
                    | | /| / /__ _/ /____ ____
                    | |/ |/ / _ `/ __/ -_) __/
                    |__/|__/\_,_/\__/\__/_/

- waterBOB Emergency Drinking Water Storage

  I love this thing. It's basically a giant, heavy-duty plastic
  bag with some access ports and pump areas that is designed to
  sit in your bathtub. You fill it up when the power goes out
  before water pressure drops. It can hold over a hundred gallons,
  which is like 375 liters or so. That's a nice backup!

- Lifestraw (3 pack)

  These things are engineering miracles. The company has some
  seriously good cred with their work in Africa too. If you're not
  familiar with it, it's a tube about the size of a relay baton.
  You stick one end in water--pretty much any water--and just
  drink out of the other end. It filters amazingly well and lasts
  over 5 years in regular use. The shelf-life is pretty much
  forever before first use, so they're great for a bag of this
  sort.

See, I told you I had something better than iodine.

                       ______          __
                      /_  __/__  ___  / /__
                       / / / _ \/ _ \/ (_-<
                      /_/  \___/\___/_/___/


- Hand Axe / Hatchet

  If your kit needs to help you out past a day or two, being able
  to work with the natural resources around you is imperitive.
  Chop up some downed branches for a fire. Clear a space for your
  family. Make some posts for hanging a trash bag (instant trash
  bin). Be creative and live in outdoor luxury with this.

- Chainmate CM-24SSP 24-Inch Survival Pocket Chain Saw With Pouch

  If you find yourself working with tough wood that needs
  clearing, having the right tools makes all the difference. Your
  hatchet can do a lot, but sometimes its nice to have a saw too.
  This thing is tiny and super light. Add it to the bag and then
  hope you don’t need it.

- ADC Medicut Shears, 7-1⁄4”

  Most scissors are weak and useless when it comes to anything
  other than wrapping paper. These things have some real power,
  and they’ll get the job done again and again. You can even
  sharpen them! I'd put this on the medical list, but their
  utility goes way beyond that. Besides, I have a dedicated
  medical set inside the waterproof box that I didn't even mention
  because they're so small and insignificant. There's tongue
  depressors in there too. You don't need to know everything!

- Entrenching Tool

  My advice for survival scenarios: Learn how to make a latrine.
  Seriously. It’ll take you five minutes to watch a video on
  youtube and it will make your outdoor living much, much easier.

- Folding Camp Saw  

  Another backup for your chainsaw. Or maybe the chainsaw is the
  backup. If you’re going to stay outdoors for any length of time,
  bring a saw.

- Mora Sweden Classic #1 Red Wood Handle Carbon Steel Knife

  Very few knives are better than this one. At 15$, you can afford
  to get extras too. Treat them well: sharpened, oiled, not
  chipped. They’ll last a lifetime.

               ______        __      _     _ __
              / __/ /__ ____/ /_____(_)___(_) /___ __
             / _// / -_) __/ __/ __/ / __/ / __/ // /
            /___/_/\__/\__/\__/_/ /_/\__/_/\__/\_, /
                                              /___/


I'm all about roughing it, but even so it's good to have a few
items that use POWER. Sometimes you need to see at night, or know
what's going on with the weather.

- Etón FR160R Microlink Self-Powered AM/FM/NOAA Weather Radio with
  Flashlight, Solar Power and Cell Phone Charger (Red)

  This thing is a beast. I charged it with the hand crank for just
  over ten seconds and then sat listening to the radio all day
  long. If you plan on staying in touch with the outside world (or
  at least informed), having a backup radio with NOAA stations is
  important. Besides, this little guy will charge your cellphone
  too! 
  
- Petzl E97 Tikka Plus 2 Headlamp

  In the redundency department, along with your knives, add light
  to the list. A headlamp will keep your hands free to do work.
  They last a really long time with LEDs.

- Gerber Infinity Ultra Task Light

  Bring a flashlight, but not one with huge, honkin’ D batteries.
  They’re harder to find replacements than AA, and much heavier.

             ___                               _
            / _ |___________ ___ ___ ___  ____(_)__ ___
           / __ / __/ __/ -_|_-<(_-</ _ \/ __/ / -_|_-<
          /_/ |_\__/\__/\__/___/___/\___/_/ /_/\__/___/


- Rothco 550lb. Type III Nylon Paracord

  I’m an Eagle Scout, and thus I never feel lost if I have a good
  length of rope. Paracord is extremely strong for its size, but
  it packs down light and tight. Use it for everything and
  everything from a clothesline to animal traps in the worst of
  situations. 

- Other Paracord

  I got a handful of free paracord bracelets at some festival and
  tossed them in the bag. A little extra rope never hurts.
  
- Size #36 Dyed Black & Tarred Twine, 1lb

  This is work-horse line. The other stuff is special and high
  quality. When you just need to tie something up, this is what
  you use. It lasts well with a tensile strength of 320lbs.

- 3M Scotch Heavy Duty All-Weather Duct Tape

  Don’t settle for the cheap duct tape. Get the good outdoor
  all-weather stuff. One roll should be more than enough to patch
  things up, bandage you up, make a stretcher, or any number of
  other tasks. 
  
- Smith’s PP1 Pocket Pal Multifunction Sharpener

  A dull knife is almost as bad as no knife. If you’re going to be
  using them… really using them, keep them sharp. This will also
  help you in cases of accidental cuts. A clean cut heals much
  faster and with less chance of infection.

- Youngstown Glove General Utility Lined with KEVLAR Glove

  The most common place to injure yourself working in survival
  situations is on your hands. Protect them with more than a pair
  of designer cotton gloves. These guys have Kevlar on the insides
  and outsides of your hands. Fantastic, and worth the price. Test
  them out with some yard work and you’ll see what I mean.

                         ____             __
                        / __/__  ___  ___/ /
                       / _// _ \/ _ \/ _  /
                      /_/  \___/\___/\_,_/


I used to keep MREs and other rations in my bag, but that became
a hassle to keep in good condition. Instead, I have some gear that
will help me find food when I need it.

- Improvised Trapping - Pathfinder Outdoor Survival Guide

  Another waterproof pamphlet that outlines how to build snares
  and deadfall traps, how to gut & clean small game and fish, and
  other necessary info for basic food prep. It even shows how to
  dry meat for long-term storage. I love these guides. There's one
  on Mushrooms that I'm eyeing up.

- Spectra® Braided Cord 1050lb test - Heavy Duty Speargun Line

  This cord is great for any number of uses, but it is in the kit
  especially for hanging a bear-bag. I use the PCT method myself,
  so I have the tools to fit it. In a pinch, though, you can get
  away with just a bag and line. Wildlife have incredible senses
  of smells. Remember, if you are outside, you don’t have walls
  keeping your food and gear safe. Be wary and hang your food.

  This line is also great for setting snares and traps. It's
  extremely thin & strong, a great combo.

- Stuff Sacks (Bear Bag, etc)

  To go along with the line above, these stuff sacks from zpacks
  are wonderful. They weigh almost nothing and are very sturdy.

- Solo Stove

  This little wood burner is a beast. Go check out a youtube video
  or something. They're amazing and cheap for what they offer.
  I hate holding on to gas. It's dangerous and hard to get more.
  Wood is plentiful.

- Some other generic metal frame stove thing

  I'm not sure where I got it, but it's two half-round pieces of
  metal that intersect and form a platform to hold a pot. You
  build a fire in it or drop some embers in there and you're set.
  I don't use it that way most of the time. Instead, I use it as
  a wind-screen for the solo stove. It's wide enough to encircle
  the whole thing. Neat, right?

                         __  ___
                        /  |/  /__ ____  ___
                       / /|_/ / _ `/ _ \(_-<
                      /_/  /_/\_,_/ .__/___/
                                 /_/


I touched on this in an earlier phlog [0], but maps are an often
overlooked part of a survival bag. I use the 7.5 minute maps from
USGS as well as a fantastic survey series of my county. I keep
these all in a transparent waterproof map case. I guess I'll have
to look around for new ones of Iceland pretty soon, though.

               _  __     __    _        ___
              / |/ /__  / /_  (_)__    / _ )___ ____ _
             /    / _ \/ __/ / / _ \  / _  / _ `/ _ `/
            /_/|_/\___/\__/ /_/_//_/ /____/\_,_/\_, /
                                               /___/

All of the things mentioned live in that ign.com gym bag, as
I mentioned, but that doesn't represent all of my bug-out stuff.
In an immediate emergency that is indeed what I grab and take out
the door. 

In fact, a few months ago our Carbon Monoxide alarm sounded at two
in the morning. We jumped out of bed, grabbed the kid, grabbed the
bag and went out to the car. I called emergency services from
there and they came and cleared the house. (Note: carbon monoxide
detectors accumulate CO over time, weakening their ability to
identify a "spike" in the gas. It's important to replace them
every few years.)

In addition to the bag I grabbed, I also have a toolbag in the
back of my car that's always present. It has some extra helpful
tools, camping gear, etc. I keep it all in a well-waxed canvas
bag. There's more rope, another wood-fire stove, blades, saws,
car-tools, and so on. If it weren't late and if I were wearing
pants I'd go grab the bag and do an inventory here. I also keep
two fleece blankets and a fantastic quality 100% wool blanket from
Hudson Bay Company in the back of the car. Exposure kills.

Upstairs in my house is my backpacking/camping gear:

- Jacks-R-Better Sierra Sniveler

  I have horrible restless leg syndrome, and most sleeping bags
  feel like a coffin to me. A nice power-down quilt gives me the
  warmth I need at night without the restrictive footbox. Pick
  whatever works for you. The single most dangerous thing when you
  are forced to sleep outside is exposure. You will die from
  exposure in a single night. Make sure you have good shelter
  before you even worry about water or food.

- Z Lite Mattress

  Sleeping on the ground can be rough. Go easy on your back with
  a little layer. More importantly, get some insulation between
  your body and the ground. The earth will suck the heat right out
  of you.

- Snow Peak Ti-Mini Solo Combo Cook Set

  Have something to heat up water. In survival situations, many
  times “cooking” literally means, “add hot water”. Heat to
  purify. Heat to rehydrate. Heat!

- Snow Peak Ti-Double H600 Stacking Mug

  This mug stacks nicely with the cookset above, so I have a pot
  for heating the water, and a cup for eating. It keeps my cooking
  pot clean.

- Bibler Tempest Tent (4-season)

  There’s a lot of ways to make a shelter outdoors. This is
  a pretty hardcore 4-season lightweight tent. It’s not the
  cheapest solution, nor the best in all situations. I use it for
  a variety of camping conditions outside of my emergency kit. If
  you aren’t much of an outdoorsman, there’s probably a better
  shelter for you. Ask around at Gander Mtn or REI, or bug your
  local scouts when they try to sell you popcorn.

- Gossamer Gear Mariposa Ultralight Backpack

  I adore this bag. It's so light weight it feels like nothing at
  all. The padding and supports are great and it has a huge number
  of ways to distribute weight. Just brilliant.

There's other stuff in there too. I line the inside of my bag with
plastic to isolate dry stuff from wet. There's some other
fancy-schmancy gear I could go into, but it's all meant for
camping, not survival. Still, I wanted to mention that I have it
around. If the emergency provides a bit more planning all of that
gets bundled up too. If we will take the car, then the cast iron
stuff is coming with me, especially the dutch oven. If we're
running from zombies, I'll probably leave the weight behind.

   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   

That was a lot to cover, and I feel like I must be forgeting about
something important. Clothes? Solar panels? Probably some of that
stuff. Regardless, it's a nice reference to have out there in
gopherspace. 

What do you have in your bag?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Another Sdf Hiccup</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181012-another-sdf-hiccup/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Another sdf hiccup?
October 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

It looks like gopher.club isn't resolving again. SDF.org is
showing up. It's usually the other way around when it comes to
gopher. I'm sick of switching the phlogroll back and forth. I'm
going to leave things as they are for now and hope it resolves
itself in the next day or two. If you notice your phlog not
updating for a while, send me a note and I'll try to work around
it.

Also, welcome to a few new phloggers on the roll!

inpefess
    gopher://boris.shminke.me/1/
bradfonseca
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/bradfonseca/

Some good content brewing there!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Maps</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181007-maps/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Maps
October 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I intend to do a longer phlog soon with an update on my bug-out
bag and other emergency preparations, but in the meantime I wanted
to highlight one thing I value that many people probably overlook.
In the United States the USGS provides extremely detailed and well
maintained maps for free (digital) or cheap (print) covering
pretty much every inch of the country. The most popular of these
maps are the 7.5 minute stretches, which cover about 64 square
miles in each one. Here's the one that covers my house [0]!

[0] 7.5 Minute Map (large file warning)
    http://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/StagedProducts/Maps/USTopo/PDF/NJ/NJ_Trenton_West_20161025_TM_geo.pdf

In addition, I also have a map of the full county with topographic
information and water systems clearly labeled. I keep both of
these in a waterproof map case in my bag. I have a road atlas in
my car for the whole country, but around home there may be need to
understand the land more intimately in case of emergency. 

In short, maps are cool.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
