<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Music As Milestone</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190816-music-as-milestone/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
music as milestone
August 16th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Passing through major change makes itself manifest in a number of
ways. For me, one of the most notable is a musical genre shift.

At the end of a long and tumultuous relationship I set out on
a thirteen hour drive home, newly single, skipping through
stations at 5am in search of something to capture the hole I felt
inside. I caught the beginning of Mountain Stage on NPR (National
Public Radio) as a trio was just starting out. The band, The Be
Good Tanyas [0], are a folk/Americana band from Canada. They
started out their set with a cover of the gospel song, "In My Time
of Dying", most famously performed by Led Zeppelin & Blind Willie
Johnson [1].

[0] The Be Good Tanyas
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/The Be Good Tanyas
[1] In My Time of Dying
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=352KDhl4i4c

There it was, the resonating echo of my inner self. I was hooked
and would go on to binge the bluegrassy/folk/Americana
scene--especially the likes of Jolie Holland--to great depths over
the next few years. It was a music for the time.

Years earlier I experienced something similar with Enya that you
can all thank for my multi-hour "All Enya" streams on tilderadio.
Joining the Navy took me on a wild ride of electronica and
euro-vocal-trance. My time in Alaska introduced me to the depths
of Nordic electronic minimalism.

And so, with the move to Iceland I expected something to develop.
I know that my tastes would shift. I already adore so many
Icelandic bands, would that grow and encompass a major part of my
life? Would I slide deeper into the fediverse's obsession with
vaporwave? Apparently the answer is no.

Somehow--illogically--I've found myself listening to Reggae [2,3].

[2] Mike Love - Permanent Holiday
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fU7hZ3smj0g
[3] Chronixx - Here Comes Trouble
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LfeIfiiBTfY

I'm not sure if I can say definitively that this is my new jam,
but it sure is happening a lot. I guess it proves that you can't
predict what the future will hold.

What are your signs of change? Do you change tastes in music like
me, or is it something else? Change nicknames? Take up new
hobbies?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Vf 1 Sexy</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190806-making-vf-1-sexy/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Making VF-1 Sexy
August 06th, 2019
----------------------------------------

VF-1 is fast, but it's also pretty basic. It doesn't (yet) do
pretty colors by types or anything sweet like that. Many of you
are probably fine with that. "Colors are useless" people... I 
hear you, but I don't agree.

In fact, even if the colors aren't structured, I still want them!
I've been piping my VF-1 output through lolcat for a few months.
It's brilliant, but was incomplete.

Not to mention any names, but some of you don't wrap your text. I
try not to be picky about whether wrapping happens at 80cols or at
67cols, but when a gopher doesn't wrap at all it makes it very
hard to read. I'll be honest, I usually just skim those posts as a
result.

"Why," I ask myself, "don't they just run it through fold(1)?"

"Duh," I answer myself, "they don't want to or don't care."

"But self, it would make my reading more convenient!"

"Come'on, tomasino. What part of _don't care_ did you not get?"

"I suppose you have a point. You're pretty smart."

"Damn right..."

"So..."

"Oh crap--"

"Why don't you solve it on the client end?"

And I sigh and say, "Of course. VF-1 lets me lolcat. Why not fold
as well? It should be simple."

If you don't care about lolcat and only want to fold output
automatically in VF-1, here's what you do. Add the following line
to your ~/.vf1rc:

  $ cat ~/.vf1rc

  handler text/plain fold -sw 80 %s


If you want to lolcat it too, like me, then you need to do a
little bit more. I'm not sure what method VF-1 uses internally to
parse the handlers, but it chokes hard on pipes. So, I wrote a very,
very basic shell script to do it for me.

  $ cat ~/bin/goph

  #!/bin/sh
  FIN=${1:-"/dev/stdin"}
  fold -sw 80 "$FIN" | lolcat -f
 
Put that in your PATH and now you can pipe anything you want to
'goph' and have it be pretty. It'll also take a file input. Then,
in your ~/.vf1rc, you can add:

  $ cat ~/.vf1rc

  handler text/plain goph %s

Let there be color, and pretty wrapping. Enjoy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gemini First Impressions</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190729-gemini-first-impressions/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gemini first impressions
July 29th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I finally spent the 5 minutes necessary to download one of the few
available Gemini clients. I went with AV-98 [0] from solderpunk.
It's interface is basically the same as VF-1, so it had that going
for it. Also, I didn't need to download a rust compiler. ;)

[0] AV-98
    https://tildegit.org/solderpunk/AV-98

While there's not a lot of content around gemini-space (more on
this in a second), it was still nice to have a way in to poke
around. I see some journal activity already taking shape, and
that's a great place to start.

I'll be honest. At first I thought of Gemini as a neat but
ultimately useless side project of the already-tiny gopher
community. The more I've seen it worked on and thought about it
the more I've come to consider it a "real thing" of some
importance. But lets come back to that idea in a minute.

First, lets talk about the naming of things.

"Gemini" is the protocol. It appears to be capitalized in all
occurences within solderpunk's FAQ. 

"Gemini maps" are the temporary term for the document format of
a Gemini server. It's coined by solderpunk here [1] and only named
that "until a better name comes along."

[1] Gemini maps
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/gemini/gemini-maps.txt

"Geminiholes" - mentioned by solderpunk, but noone is using it.

"Gemini server/client" are the defacto name for individual tools
that power it.

"Gemini-verse / Gemini-sphere / Gemini ecosystem" - I haven't
noted any special term for this akin to "the web" or
"gopherspace". Is there something already in use?

"Journal" - weB LOG / goPHer LOG like structure. Is there
a playful term for these yet?

What other terms are we missing?

Okay, enough of that. Time for THOUGHTS OF IMPORTANCE!

The built-in TLS by design of Gemini is great, and combined with
the natural ability to run it unpriviliged and require very little
bandwidth I can see it serving a valuable purpose in safely
providing a platform for authors in situations where the web is
not. Take Khazikstan, for instance, who is MITMing the entire
country. Gopher was always a nice idea to help in these
situations, but the lack of reliable security on it meant major
problems for real applications. Gemini fixes that. What's more,
Gemini over tor adds in anonymity.

I have more thoughts on the tor thing, and around real-world
applications for a minimalist hyperlinkable publishing protocol
with built in anonymity and safety, but my internet connection is
dying and I have to finish this post while tethered to my phone.
Thank goodness for low bandwidth stuff like gopher and Gemini,
right?

In the meantime, what are your thoughts on using Gemini (one day)
in a setting that's not just hobby play?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Zine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190719-zine/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
zine
July 19th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I'm going to make a zine.

SDF said they were going to do one last year and I volunteered to
contribute, but it seems like nothing came of it. So, what the
hell, lets get our zine on.

Are you unfamiliar with zines? A zine is a small-circulation
self-published work of original or appropriated texts and images,
usually reproduced via photocopier. (Thanks Gopherpedia) [0] They
were really big in the early 90s. They also went digital and there
was a whole Usenet alt for them at one point. Here, check out
a famous hacker one. [1]

[0] Zine
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Zine
[1] Phrack
    gopher://fnord.one/1/Mirrors/Phrack/Archive/Issues/

I've got some ideas around this zine, so let me blast you in the
face with some awesome. 

1. Issues will be published in entirely arbitrary times. I'm not
   going to make this a regular thing, and I'm not promising
   you'll see an issue number 3.

2. The format is mutable. You may get a PDF for one, a weird
   side-scrolling website for another, or a weird port listener
   interactive experience [2] that fails to meet any common
   definition.

8[2] Allegra	help	cosmic.voyage	1822

3. There will be a theme to each issue. The glue that binds it all
   together will be the theme (and possibly horse parts). Expect
   wild takes on the theme, possible nonsense.

4. It must be community driven.

   Here's where you come in! See, I want to put it all together
   and have fun and stuff, but I don't want to create 100% of the
   weird crap on my own. So, I figure I'll announce the theme and
   give you guys a way to contact me if you're interested in
   contributing.

   In fact, lets just cut to that part right now.

The yet-to-be-named zine will have its inaugural issue soon. If
you'd like to be a contributor, it's easy! Here's what you do:

- Contact me via email. You can find my addresses in the About
  page on this gopher hole [3].

[3] About me!
    gopher://gopher.black/1/about

- Tell me that you want to contribute something. You don't need to
  tell me what it is you want to contribute. I don't care what
  format it is in, whether it's words or art or music or a dance.
  I don't care if you're cutting out cardboard creatures and
  snaping pics of them doing naughty shit. If it fits the theme,
  go to town.

- Meet the deadline. I'll set a date when I need stuff by. Gimme
  access to whatever you've done by then or I'll assume you flaked
  out again, Jeff.

- Let me know if you want to be identified, or how you want to be
  identified for your work.

- Bask in the glory. Seriously. This is a requirement. No sitting
  back and gracefully accepting praise is allowed. You MUST bask
  in the glory. I'll be watching.

So, what's the theme of this first issue, already? What format
will it take? When's the deadline? What other questions can I ask
as I type out this phlog because I'm stalling while I try to make
a decision on the fly? Who else expected that I knew these answers
before I started this post? Did anyone really expect me to have
a well thought out plan here, or is it obvious this is coming out
of my butt right now? Is my internal monologue-turned-gopher-phlog
making you smile at least?

The theme is...

                            HAMMER

Yep, Hammer. What sort of Hammer am I talking about? Is it the
former M.C.? Or maybe the tool? Or the sport? Or maybe the
weapon!? Or maybe it's the part of a gun you cock (teehee). Or the
tiny bones in your ear. Or maybe it's something else entirely. I'm
not saying! You figure it out, suckas.

As for the format of the first zine... that depends on what sort
of shit I get back. I'm not telling you, so you can go off the
deep end if you want. I'll just have to deal with whatever comes
in. 

Again, absolutely ANYTHING is okay to submit if it fits the theme
in any way. If you have a stirring and deviant fursona fanfic of
Logan's Run that you've been dying to share, then find a way to
make it about HAMMER and you're in. If you want to draw me
a picture of a HAMMER, cool. Maybe you have a really good
technique for keying in MORSE? That arm thingy is kinda like
a HAMMER, right? Be creative, be technical, be personal, be
awesome.

Also, I'm not censoring anything here. If you have stuff that's
wildly inappropriate, bring. it. on.

So, when's the due date? Hmmmmm....

                          Tomorrow!



                       no. not really.

      That sounded fun in my head, but it would be idiotic.


                       Let's go with...



                         August 31st.
                        
Got it? That's just over a month to put together something,
anything, that can be shoved into a weird-ass package and put out
into the intertubes. Once I get all the shizzle, I'll make
something fo-rizzle. Capice?

Now, my minions, GO FORTH AND CREATE! (and also email me if you're
doing something so I know that this is gonna work).
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Some Replies From Iceland</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190705-some-replies-from-iceland/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Some replies from Iceland
July 05th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Hi everybody! I'm in Iceland now. We moved this past weekend and
we're settled in an airbnb for July getting everything in place.
If you're interested in my expat adventures, that's something I'm
writing over in web-land so my parents and wife's friends can
follow. Check it out [0].

[0] tomasino blog
    https://blog.tomasino.org

Tonight I thought it would be fun to take stock of recent things
happening on gopher and send some feedback. So, here goes:

moji, over on circumlunar, has detailed their efforts to cut back
on the caffeine [1]. It's a solid post and raises some good
thoughts on what it means to be reliant on something like coffee.
Addictions, even relatively benign ones, have some hold on you.
I can totally respect the effort. More power too you.

[1] moji - caffeine
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~moji/phlog/20190107-caffeine.txt

pkotrcka, whose name I have to be very careful typing out, wrote
a neat phlog about cameras that put my head in weird places [2].
Mainly it made me sad that photography is pretty much dead.
I mean, not really at all, but as a profession it's gone from this
highly technical artform with super expensive equipment, years of
training required and it's been overrun by quick snaps with your
phone and bottled filters. There's little spots left for the art,
like wedding photos and... is that it? Really though it's a "dead"
technology in the same way gopher is.

There's the part where my mind turned happy again. When we say
it's dead that just means that capitalism stopped seeing monetary
value. That's not the same thing at all. Why is there no money in
gopher? Well, not enough people to be worth the effort investing.
Photography? Same thing. Niche stuff sure, but other than than
just let it return to the afficianados. Let the pkotrckas of the
world have their fun, right? Keep on keeping on, pkotrcka.

[2] pkotrcka - cameras
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/pkotrcka/0022

The amazing, incredible visiblink did some hard work recently
cleaning up insulation and maybe asbestos [3]. Well done. That's
not what I wanted to comment on at all, though. At the very end of
the phlog they mention that the gopher hole switched over to a pi
zero w, saving more power. I love this ultra-low power stuff.
I have some basic notes on how I stripped my pi zero down to the
minimum draw for the little free library project. I recommend
checking it out in my archives for tidbits.

[3] visiblink - asbestos
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~visiblink/phlog/20190702

Ubergeek kayaking with son

ubergeek got his son out kayaking and that's so awesome [4].
I adore kayaking. It was really sad having to sell my kayak when
we moved. There's something really ... perfect about being out on
the water. I can close my eyes and feel myself relax just thinking
about it.

I learned to kayak in Alaska in Resurrection Bay, near Seward. It
was cold and beautiful. I saw bears and salmon and eagles and was
forever in love. I love lakes now. They're so smooth and you can
just pull yourself a bit with the paddles and drift away.

Anyway, I can see why his son is connecting with it. I wish you
both the best. It's some special stuff, there. Good dad-ing.

[4] ubergeek - kayaking
    gopher://yourtilde.com/0/~ubergeek/feels/20190703.txt

Our pal heavysquare sent me an email the other day asking me to
point his phlog roll post to the root directory where he's added
a really killer gophermap. There's so much more to see than just
the "noise" phlog I had there before. Check him out [5].

[5] heavysquare
    gopher://heavysquare.com/1/

Finally, there was a lot of talk this past week about Gemini's
link syntax [6,7,8]. Out goes the [|] and in comes the =>. I'm
into it, guys. It's cool as heck. Here's my 2-cents:

1. Spaces optional. You can split on whitespace easy enough with
   regex alone and not care if it's one space, zero, or
   a tab-space-tab-space salsa.

2. Link first. We're talking about clients doing some magic in the
   gemini world, but how much should we rely on the client's
   display choices to fulfill that important note that a URL
   should always be shown. If we have it at the end it could get
   cropped off screen or hidden in a wrap or any number of things.
   Link first is more likely to be seen, easier to parse across
   languages, and MOST importantly, means that the label can be
   optional. 

   You see how I'm linking to things paragraph by paragraph in
   this post? I have numbers referencing things with the square
   bracket syntax because it's my convention, but the position of
   the links in context to the copy says enough about what they
   are. In many cases I just described the link in a paragraph and
   the label on the link is redundant. If the label in gemini is
   optional then you can just do something like:

   => gemini://cosmic.voyage

   And let it live on its own.

[6] solderpunk - quick update on link syntax
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/gemini/quick-update-on-link-syntax.txt
[7] ascraeus - peter frampton reference
    gopher://ascraeus.org/0/phlog/019.txt
[8] sloum - commentary on link syntax
    gopher://colorfield.space/1/~sloum/phlog/190704-21.txt

Thanks gophers. Keep gophin' around.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nobody Leaves Without Singing The Blues</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190615-nobody-leaves-without-singing-the-blues/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Nobody leaves without singing the blues
June 15th, 2019
----------------------------------------

In the film Adventures in Babysitting (1987), Elisabeth Shue and
the kids she's watching find themselves unexpectedly on stage in
a blues club. When she tries to just pass through the old man in
charge of the band challenges her, "Nobody leaves without singing
the blues." [0]

[0] Babysitting Blues
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkThz92lkwE

Well, tag this post as "meta-gopher" because that's how I feel
about port 70. The ratio of consumer to creator is remarkably
matched as observed over on lambda lab [1]. We have a significant
technical barrier to use (for good or ill), but a very low
secondary barrier to contribution. I think of it like a reef that
protects the cove of port 70. If you know how to navigate into our
safe little space then you already have more than enough skill to
become an active part of the community. That's cool.

[1] lambda labs - dwarves and gophers
    gopher://lambda.icytree.org/0/phlog/2019-06-15-Dwarves-and-Gophers.txt

You all remember a few months back when solderpunk was all like,
"go make stuff, suckas"? [2] Let's not lose sight of that.

[2] solderpunk - hey you, host something
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/hey-you-host-something.txt

New blood, welcome. If you're sitting there with a phlog entry or
two brainstorming how you can do something special and stand out,
don't let that cripple you from just jumping in. Big ideas are
cool when they come, but cat needs daily phlogs to feed him or
he'll DIE! Save the cat, phlog regularly.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher 2 0</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190607-gopher-2-0/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gopher 2.0
June 07th, 2019
----------------------------------------

ratfactor has been writing on the age-old topic of updating the
gopher protocol. [0][1] Many others have covered off on this stuff
recently, like solderpunk.

[0] Gopher 2.0 Pros 'n' Cons
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/ratfactor/phlog/2019-06-04-gopher-2.0-pros-cons
[1] Gopher 2.0 - The protocol
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/ratfactor/phlog/2019-06-07-gopher-2.0-protocol

At this point I think my 2-cents are that these folks should be
aiming at a new protocol, not an update to gopher. Call it
something else, give it a new port, define it with an RFC all
you'd like. Let it be similar or not. Just leave gopher alone.

We can plug things in creatively to get gopher over TLS and tor
already in its current state. New stuff is cool, but just call it
something else. 
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Strike A Pose</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190605-strike-a-pose/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
strike a pose
June 05th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I was reading a twitter thread about the history of linked-list
questions in interviews [0] and a commenter asked how the poster
added a strikethrough to a tweet. He linked to a neat little site
that lets you type a message and generate a unicode strikethrough
version [1]. You can then copy the g̶o̶o̶f̶y̶ ̶s̶h̶e̶n̶a̶n̶i̶g̶a̶n̶s̶ well-formatted
unicode and it should show up for you.

I obviously had to p̶r̶o̶v̶e̶ ̶m̶y̶ ̶n̶e̶r̶d̶i̶n̶e̶s̶s̶ test it out!

[0] twitter thread
    https://mobile.twitter.com/hillelogram/status/962424365819277312
[1] strike through generator
    http://adamvarga.com/strike/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Everything Is Evil</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190601-everything-is-evil/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
everything is evil
June 01st, 2019
----------------------------------------

There's a link on tilde.news [0] to a blog post by Nolan Lawson on
"Tech Veganism" [1]. It is, in his summary:

 - a preference for open-source software over proprietary software
 - a suspicion of big tech companies 
 - a high bar for privacy and security

[0] tilde.news
    https://tilde.news
[1] Tech Veganism
    https://nolanlawson.com/2019/05/31/tech-veganism/

My initial reaction was a visceral gagging at the name. I readied
my angriest typing fingers and opened up the lobste.rs style
comments ready to dive in as soon as I consumed this article.
I opened it up, clicked on my Stutter [2] icon and binged it in
a minute.

[2] Stutter
    https://github.com/jamestomasino/stutter

What came out deflated me. He argues some good points early on in
the ways that the behavior of open source purists, security
experts, and digital conspiracy theorists comes across to others
in the same ways as veganism (or crossfit). And, while the article
loses some focus toward the end, it did a decent job of what it
set out to do.

It got me thinking about the whole situation from a different
perspective. For a moment I was running in place like Fred
Flinstone [3] trying to snap an argument into place so I could
fill in that comment box, but eventually I gave up.

[3] Flinstones Running
    https://www.hooktube.com/watch?v=TudMykewh_I

Instead, I imagined the mid-century world with its post-war
optimism and renewed sense of manifest destiny in the United
States. In place of a territorial expansion it was an expansion of
the confidence of indifatigable America and its moral democracy
and powerful innovation. You can feel it in the pride of the
newsreels. The awe capped off with a man standing on the moon.
Progress is perfect. Capitalism and the democratic republic,
combined with the "cowboy" ideal and puritan ethics is the
ultimate way forward. Every child will have a better life than
their parent and the world will grow in all things exponentially.

And so with the invincible self-confidence of a teenage boy on
a half-pipe, America jumped head first. Its power on the world
stage was unequaled militarily and in terms of media. Regulation
and timidity took a back seat and we all went barrelling down the
ramp.

But the mid-century sci-fi authors taught us something else. It
lingered in their messages, only to hit main stream pop culture
years later. We saw the danger of machines, of a runaway state, of
unchecked power, of the masses deciding for all. Literature,
comics, art, they put a spotlight on all aspects of life, not just
the "big dream" of a nation. They help us see the cracks. Even
post-war, things were not perfect by any means, as those who
suffered outrageous oppression (and still do) can attest. They
were not part of that narrative. Unchecked capitalism devours
everything it touches, and so it did to the American economy in
the 70s. The counter-culture of disco, an attempt at glamour in
the squalid realities of life, is art screaming for help.

Here we are three quarters of a century on from that ridiculous
vision of a country who can do no wrong. We see those ideals
spread far, far beyond the US boundaries. The ideas themselves are
an identity for many, disconnected from their birthplace. Even now
we hear the same tripe of trickle-down economics cross the lips of
idiots. Even now we have those who believe in their hearts that
technology will save us from ourselves, as if innovation could
ever outpace hubris.

That was the daydream of thoughts that overtook me from this
little article on tech veganism. And with that lense I look again
and see something different. I don't see angry white men sitting
at their computers bitching about Google spying on them. I see
people who are walking with the rest of the world across
a landscape of ease and luxury, but have stumbled and looked down
and realized what we're crushing under our feet with each step.

Progress isn't perfect.

Everything we do has the infinite consequences that come from
being a part of this insane system of reality, a piece of humanity
as a whole, and a spec of unique life in the midst of a biosphere
hugging an oblique spheriod tumbling through the vacuum of space
like mildew around a shower handle. Everything about us is messy,
gross, and complex. It's hard enough to change something
intentionally for the good without unintended consequences
crushing your idea of progress. And it is so much easier to do
immesurable damage to our world and ourselves with the reckless
abandon of innovation for its own sake (or worse, for money).

I think back to the optimism of the space age and the pulp view of
"good" that it represents. It is not an objective reality, but it
had a presence and an effect at the time. In that way it was
"real". Today our tech advancements promise us pleasure and ease
and luxury at the cost of data, access, information, exposure, and
all the other little things that seem intangible and "no big deal"
in marketing-speak. Many, many people will take that deal. Why
not? Why pay for TV when you can sit through ads and let the
company know what you like. You'll just get better targeted ads.
Where's the harm? Right?

Where the dewey-eyed comic view of the 40s and 50s had eyes on
shiny rockets and travels to the moon, these days we know the
ineffible terror of an all-powerful algorithm, a machine
intelligence, churning numbers about each of us and uncovering
secrets we didn't know we had. We know governments use these for
their own aims, often against the individual. We know hackers can
exploit this. We know that advertisers care about money, not what
we want to see. We know that consumerism will push us toward
a place where we spend every dollar and borrow more to spend
ourselves into debt. We know that the world will enslave us in
a thousand ways to keep power with those in power.

We know, in effect, that the whole world is driven by evil
intentions. Evil in selfishness and in dehumanization and in the
lack of concern for future generations, environment, and the world
in general. 

Everything is evil.

It might not be objective reality, but it has a presence and
effect on everything. In that way it is our "reality". It's almost
enough to make me accept the vegan label without cringing. Almost.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Board Games</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190529-board-games/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
board games
May 29th, 2019
----------------------------------------

cat just dropped a nice phlog [0] about board and card games that
he loves. He wrapped up by asking others what they enjoy.

[0] cat - top 3 board & card games
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20190528.txt

I'll try to keep this to just 3 games as well (with an honorable
mention or two). Unlike cat, who favors the solo or two player
games, I'm a fan of the epic.

1. The Republic of Rome (Avalon Hill)

Avalon Hill is famous for making complex war simulation board
games that take hours to set up, let alone play. It is a company
at the forefront of destroying friendships. Diplomacy is probably
the game responsible for the most gamer-feuds in history, which
makes Republic of Rome remarkable in that it was created
specifically for gamers who thought it too tame. Avalon Hill had
a rating system for complexity in their games and at the time of
its release, RoR was the first game to max it out. These days we
can enjoy a few that have since jumped the shark in terms of
complexity [1].

[1] The Campaign for North Africa
    https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/4815/campaign-north-africa

For all its ridiculous complexity and legal-code rulebook, it's
a brilliantly fun game to tackle with a group of friends. The
players control factions of senators in either the early, middle,
or late republic time periods of Roman history. They struggle
against one another for money, influence, popularity, and military
might until one comes out dominant enough to meet one of several
victory conditions. But they must be careful! If the factions
don't cooperate, Rome itself can fall and everyone loses.

This has been responsible for so many amazing nights of board game
fun I can't sing its praises enough. As I'm gearing up to leave
the country, my friends here planned one last get together to say
farewell and what better way could they have done so than with
a game of RoR.


2. Carcassonne (Hans im Glück)

This tile-laying game is fast (20-30 min), easy-to-learn, and
endlessly amusing. It's a great lunch-time game if you work with
another board game geek. You are building a sprawling city and
trying to occupy the buildings you create to score points when
they are completed. You farm the lands servicing these buildings
and set up monestaries. Oh, and don't forget to build roads! All
of this is done with puzzle-like square tiles that connect and
extend the existing city into a new crazy puzzle of awesome. Score
keeping is a little tricky at first, but it becomes second nature.


3. Once Upon a Time: The Storytelling Card Game (AMIGO)

I adore storytelling and this game really scratches that itch.
It's a card-game with fantastic creatures and items all fantasy
themed. You will find character types like the witch, or princess,
and items like magic swords. You'll also find story elements like
a broken promise. With these building blocks you and your friends
will create an epic tale. Together. Entirely improv style.

The way it works is really cool. Someone starts telling the story.
As they tell their story they will begin to play cards in their
hand that match the story they're telling. If they introduce
a swarthy princess who runs an illegal footwear consortium, then
they may lay down the princess card. If that princess discovers
a way to hide switch blades in the magical Air Jordans she's
creating, then the player may play the magical sword card. But
it's not as simple as just making up gibberish and laying down
your cards!

If the story fails to make sense, contradicts itself, or if the
player pauses too long (as determined by the other players) then
the story moves to the next clockwise player and the previous
storyteller must draw a new card to their hand for having "lost"
the story. There's also a tricky way to steal a story from
a storyteller. If the storyteller mentions a story element that
matches a card in your hand, you can play that card and take over
the story. But you better be ready to start right away or you may
pause too long and lose it.

All of this storytelling and card playing/drawing is leading
toward and ending that's unique to each player. You draw secret
ending cards at the start of the game. Your ending is different
from the other players and you need to steer the narative in the
right direction to get there. If your story ends with "The twins
were cooked in the pie." and the story doesn't even have twins
introduced, you have some catching up to do.

This game requires outgoing friends and benefits from some
moderate drinking. It also has a special place in my game
collection because of our house rule on "who goes first." 

No matter what game we're playing, the choice of who goes first
comes down to the Once Upon a Time deck. Everyone cuts the deck
and takes out one card. Whichever card is "Closest to Unicorn"
goes first. We love the ambiguity and determining whether the
Princess or the Magic Sword is closer to unicorn (magic sword,
obviously). It starts every game out with a smile.


Honorable Mentions:

A. Chess

A classic, and I'm totally addicted, but it didn't feel right to
include in this list.

B. Tabletop RPGs

Pathfinder, D&D, Fate, The Riddle of Steel, Alternity, Fiasco, and
all the rest are the very best games in the world. As much as
I love a board game, a D&D campaign has no equal. I guess I'll
probably have to write more about that soon.


Okay, people... what's your top 3?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
