<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Planet Of The Apes</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220320-planet-of-the-apes/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Planet of the Apes
March 20th, 2022
----------------------------------------

I just watched the new-ish Planet of the Apes trilogy with my son.
He loved them and so did I. I saw the second film a few years back
and remember thinking it was just an incredible piece of
filmmaking. The cinematography was brilliant, as was the acting,
pacing, and the classic betrayal story. Now that I've finally seen
the third I can say without reservation that it's one of the
better trilogies of the 21st century. Matt Reeves contributions on
2 and 3 are a marvel.

If you are interested in seeing it, try and find subtitles for the
ape-parts. It will help convey some of the depth of story.
I watched subtitle-free the first time and while it's possible to
follow and enjoy, there's a distance that grows between you and
the apes.

Also, there's something wonderfully cathartic about seeing these
films and unreservedly rooting for the humans to all die already
so the apes can inherit the Earth.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sensory Deprivation</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220316-sensory-deprivation/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sensory deprivation
March 16th, 2022
----------------------------------------

Today I spent an hour in a sensory deprivation tank for the first
time. My wife bought me a gift certificate to a local place that
has the tanks and some fancy chair massages, but with the COVID
situation as it was I was waiting to cash in. This week happens to
be light at work so the time finally felt right.

My appointment was at 11:30 and I managed to show up right on
time. The door was locked, oddly, so I knocked and was welcomed
inside by another American transplant. He runs the shop and said
he was just getting in and getting another visitor set up in the
next room. She was a very pregnant 20-something. I heard their
conversation and recommendations for comfort. The guy knew his
stuff. It turns out his wife is also quite far along in her
pregnancy, so they've been getting a lot of practice.

Once it was my turn I was led into a private room and given the
tour. Here is the shower for getting clean and rinsed before
entering the tank (just as is the custom at the pools in Iceland).
Here is a table with towels and a spray bottle. When you are in
the tank if you touch your face or rub your eyes, the salt water
will get all over you and it's impossible to clean off without
some help. Thus the spray bottle and the hand towel. And here are
a pair of earplugs. They're not really necessary for the sound, as
the room and tank are well insulated, but they do keep the salt
water from going deep in your ear canal. I was sure to put those
in right away.

Finally I met the tank itself. It was bigger than I expected,
which was a welcome relief. I was a little worried about feeling
claustrophobic, but this gave me room to stretch out nicely. It
was lit from within and looked clean and inviting with a little
motion to the water as the pumps did their thing. The lid opened
from the front, by the head, much like a car's trunk. You could
step in, squat down, and use the handle inside to pull the lid
closed above you. The owner of the shop recommended settling in
with the door ajar first, then closing it if comfortable. He said
leaving it open to the air might make you cold.

The lights and sound are on a timer. Everything dimmed quite low
and soothing spa sounds were barely audible in the background.
After I washed and got into the tank I quickly settled into
position and lowered the lid. The light faded first, about five
minutes in. Then the sounds faded out too, perhaps ten minutes
later. It was around this time I decided I was actually quite hot
with the lid closed, and the cool air would be welcome. I pushed
it open a foot or so, and found my happy temperature. The whole
room was blacked out at this point, so there was no functional
difference to the experience other than heat.

Now that I was alone with my thoughts it was game-on. I have,
thankfully, participated in a number of silent retreats in the
past. I think these have prepared me well for being alone and the
difficulties of quieting the mind. 

I can remember my very first three-day silent retreat: I arrived
on a Friday evening and all the participants greeted each other
normally. We had dinner with conversation, getting to know one
another a bit. Silence began when the meal ended. We were to
remain in silence until the end of Mass on Sunday, at which time
we would have a lunch together with conversation again. That first
night my mind was on fire with cool ideas and things I wanted to
remember to say when silence ended. I wrote a huge amount of notes
in my Moleskine notebook. Saturday continued that way until the
early afternoon. I was walking in the garden and I found a single
leaf dangling about 10 feet below its tree, attached only from
a single strand of a spider's web. No spider was in sight but
I was enraptured. My whole attention went on that leaf and the
spider silk strand. In those minutes I forgot about my notebook
and remembering things for later. I finally started to let go of
my rapid-paced mental dialogue and just be present. And that's
when I finally met the silence, truly. 

Once I found the silence it became an old friend. I try my best to
find it as quickly as I can on retreats now. I generally don't
take a notebook at all anymore, unless the retreat has some sort
of focused agenda to work on at specific times. Instead I try to
settle into that emptiness and just exist there.

A sensory deprivation tank is the perfect place to do that.
I dusted off an old trick I used on an 8 day retreat a few years
back: I thought about a book I want to write, and about a specific
character. I focused my attention on that character and what makes
her unique. What defines her, what part of her personality gets
her into trouble? And after just a couple minutes of that focused
thinking, not about anything that was bothering me, or about my
actual life, I felt my attention begin to wander. And so I let it
wander away from the book, and towards the silence. There it was.

The rest of the time passed quickly. The lights began to fade back
up, and there was the spa sounds again. In another minute they
were on in full and I knew it was time to get out, wash up, and
head home. Washing that much salt out of my hair took a while, but
there was no rush. I spoke some pleasantries with the owner on my
way out, but I was still carrying the silence with me. That's one
of my favorite parts of retreats as well. How long can I keep the
silence there with me, present underneath everything going on.
Sadly it seems the answer is roughly as long as I spent in silence
in the first place. One hour gets me one more. Three days get me
three more. Thirty days got me a bonus month.

I love the silence. I love the peace it brings, even when I'm back
in the thick of things.

I really enjoyed my time in the tank. I may do it again, but
probably not right away. They offer a monthly pass, but it doesn't
feel like the right fit, personally. Maybe once a quarter or twice
a year? It's a lovely ritual, though. If you have the opportunity
to try it out I would recommend it. Try to be at peace and let go.
It's surprisingly easy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Buying Books</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220306-buying-books/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Buying Books
March 06th, 2022
----------------------------------------

A fedi post from @DL6MHC@mastodon.radio I just read said:

"I've started to abuse Amazon for browsing articles, getting
inspirations, reading (hopefully non-fake) reviews and finding out
what a solid price for an article is. Then I buy my stuff
somewhere else."

For years I would go to big booksellers like Barnes & Noble or
Borders (before it shut down) to browse books and discover
interesting things only to then purchase them online from Amazon
where it was much cheaper. Sometimes I'd even purchase while I was
still there browsing. I felt so clever.

My battle then was against the big bookseller who came in and
killed so many beloved tiny bookshops. Amazon was the scrappy
alternative in my mind, and a means of revenge.

These days I will browse Amazon for things, read reviews, gather
intel, and then purchase else where, just like the fedi user
above. I wish I could say that it was an act of will power and
ethical justice at work, but it's mostly because ordering from
Amazon to Iceland is prohibitively expensive.

I take solace in the world of coffee, though. When Starbucks swept
in and killed many of my beloved local coffee shops I did not bow
down, but fought back by supporting those who remained or
abstaining completely. When the third wave of coffee brought back
the renaissance of local shops I was ready to dive right in. 

But books... sadly, my options are less stellar. For one thing
I try not to gather too many physical books. I can't move them
easily or cheaply and I end up giving them away. So I favor ebooks
or library books. Those I could still get cheaply from Amazon,
I suppose. The general mentality that "Amazon isn't affordable"
I've developed here seems to have clouded that issue in my head.
I'm more likely to seek a 3rd party site, direct-from-author
purchase, or grab from the library. For older works, out-of-print
stuff, or obscure things I dust off my tor browser and visit
z-library.

Anyway, not sure where I was going with this, but there ya go.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ukraine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220221-ukraine/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Ukraine
February 21st, 2022
----------------------------------------

Oh no. Poor Ukraine.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Computer Science</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220202-computer-science/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
computer science
February 02nd, 2022
----------------------------------------

I came across one of those lists of free computer science classes
curated in a github gist or some other such place. I knocked it
around in my tabs for a couple hours and let my mind go back to my
own CS education.

I started at Rowan University in 1998 in the Computer Science
department following the coattails of a friend from Boy Scouts who
had been doing well for a year already. In high school I didn't
really have any direction at all or idea of what I wanted to do.
Computers happened to be a thing I was familiar with, spent a bit
of time on, and it appeared likely to have a future that paid
well. My dad's only restriction on my choice was, "No art."

He had gone to Kent State and studied in the Visual Communications
department there and was unable to turn that into a career. He
instead took the long way through a retail job and eventually into
sales. Because of his experience he hoped to save me the trouble.

The thing is, had he not had that restriction I likely would have
gone into some form of art education. It was the course track
I enjoyed most in school, continuously excelled in, and got me
motivated. But, in the long run the joke is on both of us. As I'll
explain in a moment. But first, back to Computer Science!

In 1998 I got my start. I had some great introduction to
programming classes that dove right into C. I had a killer lab
techniques practical course that taught me the ins and outs of the
command line, jobs, rediection of outputs, and all sorts of mighty
cool things I use every day. I also had some heavy-duty math
classes which bored the ever-living snot out of me.

My first semester went well. My second semester saw a marked dip
in my grades, though. I was getting involved in stuff that was
taking my focus away from class, and part way through that year
I developed an extreme clinical depression and insomnia. Entering
my sophomore years I find it difficult to relate details because
I have some intense memory loss due to the insomnia. I basically
accomplished nothing is school, failed everything, and was on the
edge of academic probation when I somehow signed up to enlist in
the US Navy. That gave me an excuse for a leave-of-asence from
school (delaying repaying those loans!) and in a matter of weeks
I was gone.

All in all my computer science education is the equivalent of two
pretty solid semesters of foundations.

In the Navy I was a nuclear electronics technician, so I picked up
more skills in hardware which was really cool, but didn't do much
to further my computer expertise.

Finally, after the Navy, I ended up returning to school and
beginning anew at Indiana University. I transfered pretty much
nothing from my first school as I wasn't going into a CS
department. I think 2 of my math classes may have worked and
that's it. But, this time around I had a Navy work ethic and also
the a limited time payment due to my medical discharge. The Navy
had me covered for about 3 years of school, so I went to town.
I managed to go from nothing at all to a masters degree in those
three years. Fun part about it? It was in this lovely new program
that just launched called "New Media". It was, in fact, a visual
communications degree + computers. Hah!

So, as I'm remember all this stuff I'm also lementing how I can
whiz through and code really well and professionally at a senior
level in a few niche areas, but if you need skills that get past,
say, data structures and algorithms level, I never learned it.
Systems programming? No idea. Operating systems? Nope. Parallel
computing? Huh?

I'll sum it up this way: I never got to learn how to link to
a system library. Not sure what to do to make that happen.

I can muddle around in about 15 languages, but without that
conceptual level to fall back on there's not a lot I can actually
DO outside of the web.

So yeah, I need more education. And here are all these free
courses. My formal education was a quarter century ago, so I'm not
going to rely on memory. I've decided to start from the beginning.

The following is a list of courses with video lections I found
which roughly run in linear order. I may end up shuffling one or
two things later on, but for now I'm just watching lectures one by
one and soaking it in. I'm pretty sure I won't need any note
taking for the first couple of courses, but we'll see.

Stanford CS106A - Programming Methodology
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS106A
Stanford CS106B - Programming Abstractions
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS106B
Stanford CS107 - Programming Paradigms
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS107
Stanford CS110 - Principals of Computer Systems
    https://web.stanford.edu/class/archive/cs/cs110/cs110.1202/
MIT - Mathematics for Computer Science
    https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/
Wheaton - Discrete Mathematics and Functional Programming
    http://cs.wheaton.edu/~tvandrun/dmfp/
Stanford CS161 - Design and Analysis of Algorithms 1
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXFMmlk03Dt7Q0xr1PIAriY5623cKiH7V
Stanford CS161 - Design and Analysis of Algorithms 2
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXFMmlk03Dt5EMI2s2WQBsLsZl7A5HEK6
Stanford CS261 - A second Course in Algorithms
    http://timroughgarden.org/w16/w16.html
Stanford EE261 - The Fourier Transform and its Applications
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/EE261
CMU 18-447 - Introduction to Computer Architecture
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5PHm2jkkXmhayPxddp9z5MixV8Q5Ty8u
CMU 15-418 - Parallel Computer Architecture and Programming
    http://15418.courses.cs.cmu.edu/spring2015/
CMU 15-721 - Database Systems
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLSE8ODhjZXjbisIGOepfnlbfxeH7TW-8O
CSE 421/521 - Introduction to Operating Systems
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLE6LEE8y2Jp-kbEcVR2W3vfx0Pdca0BD3
Berkeley - SICP Python
    https://cs61a.org/
MIT - SICP Scheme
    https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-001-structure-and-interpretation-of-computer-programs-spring-2005/index.htm

The last two entrants are both courses based around SICP. There's
the famous Scheme original from MIT, but also one in Python which
I grok better. In April I'm picking up the Javascript SICP book
too. Between two courses and a book in three different languages
I hope I'll be able to muddle my way through.

I hope I finish it all. I think it's doable. I'll keep pressing
forward as best I can. If you read this and think about it at some
point in the future, feel free to ping me on IRC or Mastodon
sometime and ask how I'm doing. Who knows, I may be stalled and
need a little nudge back on track.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cheating At My Reading Goal</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220101-cheating-at-my-reading-goal/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cheating at my reading goal
January 01st, 2022
----------------------------------------

A new year is here and a new reading goal is set. I'm sticking
with my goal of 100 books like the last few years. It's attainable
even if I hit a slump. Even so, to start my year off on a good
note I like to read easy, quick stuff. Last year I read like 10-15
books of this Witch P.I. series that's honestly pretty terrible,
but I just tear through it. It helps that the books are cozy as
hell and nothing serious is ever at stake more than a knitting
contest.

This year I was thinking about what series to binge to get ahead.
I'm just getting started on the Jill Kismet series (I have the
whole thing in an omnibus). I also have the Alex Verus series of
which I've read book one and will likely binge quickly. But
instead of either of those I realized that my Calibre library has
page numbers in it (because I'm diligent about good data). So...
I'm going to sort by shortest book and clean house on a bunch of
novellas I've been sitting on for years. I have about 20 books
under 50 pages! If I want to read a bunch of the Shadow stories
this year I could do my entire 100 and stay under 150 pages each.
Wild! Such cheating! Hahaha.

I'll mix it up soon enough and I don't stop at 100 books, so I'm
not really cheating anything. This is just a little mental trick
to help me feel like I'm well invested in reading for the year. My
own motivation wanes if I fall behind schedule and it becomes
increasingly hard to pick up my Kindle. It's best to stay well
ahead of goal.

Anyway, here I go!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
December 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Be it resolved:

This year the name 'tomasino' will become a standard unit of
measurement.

2021 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201231-resolution
2020 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution
2019 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions
2018 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bbs</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-bbs/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
BBS
December 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I installed WWIV on one of my VMs. I walked through all the set up
and got it all configured out of some spark of nostalgia. Then
when it was done and ready to start adding content I decided I had
no content I wanted to share in a BBS. I have enough channels for
my creative outputs already. Too many, really.

So I deleted it.

It was too easy to conflate the installation and configuration of
a BBS as "having a BBS" in my head. I wanted to recapture the
feeling of the BBS days and the setup process faked its way into
my day masquarading as a solution. The BBS experience was one of
community, though, and of reaching out for a bit of nerdy contact
that pierced a veil of separatation. 

That veil doesn't exist anymore. The internet killed it. And so
what is left to penetrate? I already have contact with you here.

Do I add door games to this little corner of the internet and
entice you with FIDONet access? Maybe I dust off Phrack archives
or ANSi art galleries? With a lot of work I could decorate my
space like the ones of my youth and possibly entice visitors for
a drive-by of the museum I'd created, but that's still a pale
approximation.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Merry Christmas</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211224-merry-christmas/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Merry Christmas
December 24th, 2021
----------------------------------------

It's just about bed time here on Christmas Eve. The tree is
decked, the presents stuffed gloriously below. We have cookies and
milk for Santa on the table (and a few red pepper slices for the
reindeer). Soon this little boy will lie down and rest and we can
all wake up bright and early.

It's a peaceful moment. Merry Christmas from our peace to yours.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
