<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Remind</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210330-cli-tricks-remind/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CLI Tricks: remind
March 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

remind - a sophisticated reminder service

One of the little cool CLI utilities I've been meaning to use is
remind(1). It's a tool with a plain text, human readable calendar
format and some hefty power under the hood.

Let's look at an example entry in a reminder file:

  REM July 6 +7 MSG tomasino's birthday %b%

In looking at this line you can have a pretty good guess what it
means without any help at all. These insructions can become far
more complex and esoteric as you start using the powerful
programming features built into remind, but most of your entries
are probably going to be as simple as this.

The main structure of a remind entry is:

  <trigger> <action> <body>

In the example above the trigger is:

  REM July 6 +7

The action is:

  MSG

And the body is:

  tomasino's birthday %b

Technically the "REM" at the start is optional, except in some
weird cases where the line might begin with OMIT or RUN. It's
safest just to keep it. Every line ends in % also.

Want the full list of options for a REM line? Sure...

REM  [ONCE] [date_spec] [back] [delta] [repeat] [PRIORITY prio]
[SKIP | BEFORE | AFTER] [OMIT omit_list]  [OMITFUNC  omit_func‐
tion] [AT time [tdelta] [trepeat]] [SCHED sched_function] [WARN
warn_function] [UNTIL expiry_date | THROUGH  last_date]  [SCAN‐
FROM scan_date | FROM start_date] [DURATION duration] [TAG tag]
<MSG | MSF | RUN | CAL | SATISFY | SPECIAL special | PS  |  PS‐
FILE> body

The trigger section is often a date and they follow some really
simple and intuitive rules. If you list a full date including day,
month, and year, then it will trigger on that day. If you omit the
year then it will remind you on that calendar day every year. Omit
the month and it will remind you on that day every month. Simple,
right?

What if you want the reminder to occur for several days leading up
to the date? Just like in my example above, the +7 following
a date will do that. In my case you get a full week's worth of
reminders leading up to my birthday.

Date's can be more than just calendar days, though. For instance:

  REM SUN 1 --7 at 23:30 MSG Tilde Trivia with Tomasino %

Here I'm setting the date to the first Sunday of the month, minus
seven days at 11:30pm. Well, if you move backwards one week from
the first sunday that gets you the last sunday of the month.
A nice trick, right? Here we have a reminder for my radio show on
tilderadio.org. I should note that all times in remind(1) are in
your local timezone. If you are scripting something with external
data and need to convert timezones there are functions built in
for that, though.

So far I've just shown off the MSG action, but there are several
others. Most notably there's the RUN action, which lets you
execute a program on your machine when the trigger occurs. Perhaps
you want to use that to output your todo list every Monday? Or
maybe you have it automatically email you a system report on the
second Tuesday of the month. There's no limit to the options
available.

So how do you use it?

Well, first you install remind(1). It's available in apt and most
other package managers. There's a package for MacOS as well. It
will come with two executables: remind(1) and rem(1). The latter
is a shortcut that will run remind(1) with the default remind file
(normally ~/.reminders, but you can change it with an ENV var).

In my .profile I have the environment variable set to use a remind
file in XDG_CONFIG_HOME since I like a clean home dir.

  export DOTREMINDERS=$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/remind/reminders

Then inside that 'reminders' file I use a tiny script to
automatically include any files that match "*.rem" inside
a special syncthing folder:

  SET HOME getenv("HOME")
  include [HOME]/.syncthing/remind/

This means I can organize my stuff into relevant files like
"work.rem" and "birthdays.rem".

There's an incredible amount of depth you can get into with this
thing. It can output to a terminal calendar or even an html
calendar or just the plain reminders. It can generate a postscript
printer file and allows advanced commands for shading. It has
a robust programming language built in as well that will make you
scratch your head at first and then scoff at the childish
limitations of Outlook and Google Calendar. You can even build
your own custom functions in this thing.

The remind(1) man page is well written and packed full of
examples, but there's also some great tutorials online. Here's
a few to start your explorations:

Keep your calendar in plain text with Remind
    https://lifehacker.com/geek-to-live-keep-your-calendar-in-plain-text-with-rem-186661
Roaring Penguin's Remind FAQ
    https://www.roaringpenguin.com/wiki/index.php/Remind_FAQ
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stallman</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210326-stallman/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Stallman
March 26th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Richard Stallman is back on the board of directors at the Free
Software Foundation (FSF) after having resigned eighteen months
ago under mounting public pressure for him to be removed for his
controversial comments about consent in reference to Jeffrey
Epstein sex-trafficking charges. 

Virginia Roberts Giuffre was a 17 year old victim of Epstein who
in her deposition stated that she was directed to have sex with
Marvin Minsky, a member of the MIT faculty. In response to an MIT
CSAIL (Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory)
email thread planning a protest at MIT over the institution's
relationship with Epstein, Stallman raised issues with the term
"assaulting", stating, "The word 'assaulting' presumes that he
applied force or violence, in some unspecified way, but the
article itself did say no such thing. Only that they had sex."

In addition to the immediate backlash, statements from Stallman's
blog added fuel to the flames. I am skeptical of the claim that
voluntarily [sic] pedophilia harms children." (Stallman, 2006)

In 2019 he later amended, "Through personal conversations in
recent years, I've learned to understand how sex with a child can
harm per psychologically. This changed my mind about the matter:
I think adults should not do that. I am grateful for the
conversations that enabled me to understand why."

Though often accused of defending Epstein, Stallman has made it
clear that he sees the man as a serial-rapist and condemns his
acts. It is instead these statements surrounding the ideas of
consent and sexual violence that have sparked the majority of the
outrage.

Many people feel it is appropriate to separate Stallman from the
FSF and other libre software movements as these personal
statements and views reflects negatively on that community and
their efforts. Others see in him a champion unmatched in calling
for libre software engagement and adoption. Many groups in the
field have been forced to make a public stance in favor or against
his involvement, such as Mozilla and the Tor Project [0].

[0] Mozilla and Tor join calls to oust ...
    https://www.fastcompany.com/90618666/mozilla-and-tor-join-calls-to-oust-richard-stallman-from-free-software-foundation

                           - - -

So what do I think? I think the man is a mixture of good ideas and
bad. I think he's naturally brusque and his elevated position in
his narrow community has fed his ego dangerously, as any power is
wont to do. 

I am also guilty of having been wrong in the past. I'm thankful
that most of my wrongness isn't in permanent written form and
I don't have enemies who seek out my own poor behavior in the past
to drag it into the light today. It's hard enough to change your
mind without being anchored to those past decisions through
constant reminder.

Stallman has lived his life in a tech world with tech solutions,
logic, and a type of pseudo-logical rhetoric that can make his
statements seem detached or disingenuous. It's something I see
commonly in communities dominated by autistic people, though it's
not limited to those or necessarily present among all autistics.
Whatever the case, it doesn't mesh well with the highly emotional
topics such as sexual predation. The tone itself harms, which is
something I suspect Stallman is both unaware of and incapable of
addressing. Coming from a white man in position of power adds to
the harm and further alienates those who hear what he says. All
this harm comes separate from and in addition to the comments
themselves. He was rightfully argued against in that email list
and I think the escalation of the issue into a public forum was
necessary to balance the scales of power. Unfortunately in an
institution like MIT and in a group like CSAIL the opinions of
Richard Stallman are not in balance with the others speaking.

We do not currently have a mechanism in our society to address
these public social grievances of powerful people beyond seeking
punishment through their employment, platform, sponsorship, and
other mechanisms that enable their power. Our public speech is
unbalanced in power in favor of the rich and powerful, and so some
measures will necessarily be taken to counter it. 

Is it right? Is it just? It is literally our only recourse. It's
hard to make an ethical judgement without alternatives. I would
love a world where there were other means of public censor.
History doesn't provide us many options without blood to model
after, though. Perhaps getting someone removed from a board of
directors isn't such a bad course.

And now that he has returned, just 18 months after the incident of
note and without much change in public opinion, what are we to
think? Is his short statement on his blog about learning that
pedophilia is wrong sufficient to let him off the hook for his
statements minimizing sexual abuse? No, I don't think so. That may
address his 2006 statements, but not those regarding Virginia
Roberts Giuffre.

                           - - -

But what of the FSF and libre software in general? Without
Stallman at the helm will that effort fail?

Here first I will make an ethical statement that libre software is
not important when juxtaposed by the physical safety of a human
being. It is not important when juxtaposed with the safety of
minors, of women, or in relation to sexual abuse. If Richard
Stallman was the one and only human being who could make libre
software succeed or fail it is still not worth giving the man
power if it leads toward the increase in actual harm to actual
human beings.

Thankfully Stallman isn't that important. He has done quite a bit
of work in the field. That is unarguable. 

In political theory there is the idea of the Overton window [1].
There is a spectrum of political discourse from far extreme to
moderate to far extreme in the other direction. The Overton window
represents the scope along this spectrum of politically acceptable
policies. Notably, though, is the need for actors that exceed the
boundaries of this window to widen it in their given direction.
For instance, an extreme leftist view allows for a more moderate
leftist view to be politically acceptable. Without that extremist
view the window will shift to the right and the moderate practice
will seem extreme.

[1] Overton window
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Overton window

I think this idea is applicable to more than politics, or perhaps
more than traditional politics. The politics of technology and
thir place in the world has extremists and Richard Stallman is
one. The idea that all software and hardware on a user's system
must fit his libre definition is one such view. It enables us to
have more reasonable discussions about the importance of the open
source community, of public access to code, and intellectual
property in general.

For this reason I appreciate the Stallmans in the world, but not
enough to give him a pass on other behavior. Thankfully we still
have plenty more assholes expanding our Overton window. We don't
need Stallman for that anymore.

In some cases it is difficult to separate art from artist when the
artist does something heinous. This is most often if the art
represents a substantial and important cultural work, or if, as is
more often the case, it is not an individual work but the work of
many people. Take the Cosby Show as an example here. Do we
write-off that television series because of the acts of Bill
Cosby? That unjustly punishes all of the other actors, staff, and
production crews that put their work into a very good program to
spite one man. This is a difficult ethical choice. In the case of
Richard Stallman it was fairly simple to punish the man and ignore
the FSF itself 18 months ago. The choice of the board to reinstate
him, however, now stains the rest of them with the conscious
choice to value him over the harm his statements cause.

So that's my extremely long-winded way of saying I agree with
Mozilla and the Tor Project. We must censor Stallman and the FSF
board of directors. The means of doing so is their removal from
that position. Let it be done and done peacefully. Let them learn
from it as Stallman learned that his 2006 statements were
dangerous and damaging. Maybe by removing them from power others
will learn as well. These ideas they're arguing are widening an
Overton window around sexual consent that doesn't need widening.
Lets quiet the extremists and bring that window to a healthier
place.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cold</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210227-cold/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cold
February 27th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I've got a cold. It's just a regular one, don't worry. Even so,
it's so frustrating. I go to few places, mix with very few people,
wear a mask in public, wash my hands and disinfect things, and
still I get a cold. It's not the first one either. I've been sick
a lot this past year.

The source is probably the kid and his friends. Little kids bring
all the illnesses with them and I tend to get them all. Even
taking that into account, though, they're isolated and their
spaces are cleaned religiously. They should be a smaller vector
now too. But my sniffly nose disagrees.

I've started taking in-person Icelandic classes this past week.
No, the illness isn't from there. Nobody there is sick and we're
all distanced and whatnot. I go back on Monday and I hope I'm
feeling better by then. I can't willingly bring a cold into that
room and I know if I start missing classes I'm not going to keep
up.

Hurry up, nose!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bun Day</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210213-bun-day/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Bun Day
February 13th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Monday is Bun Day here in Iceland. Bollur, the buns of the day,
are sort of like cream puffs. Folks get jams and whipped cream and
mix them together and stuff the buns to overflowing, then smother
them in chocolate sauce. It's a healthy time!

There's also a super-duper Icelandic tradition with bun day that
many parents choose to not teach their kids. Early on Monday
morning children in the know will wake up early, sneak into their
parents' bedroom and WHACK WHACK WHACK them in their bed with
sticks! However many whacks they get in before the parents get up
is how many buns they get. Lovely!

Following Bun Day is a sort of Fat Tuesday-like holiday that
involves gorging yourself on all sorts of special foods that are
terrible for you. I forget the name of that one, but it's nice
too. 

Finally we get to Ash Wednesday. Here in Iceland Ash Wednesday is
the costume & candy holiday. Halloween is a relatively recent
phenomenon here and not very popular mostly because they already
have most of those traditions at the start of lent. Kids dress up
in all sorts of costumes, go to school that way, and then later go
around begging for candy. But here they don't go to individual
homes and say "trick or treat". Instead they go to businesses and
sing songs for their treats! If you head downtown to Reykjavik on
Wednesday you'll see this in full swing. It's really cute and so
strange to see bank-branded popcorn bags and the like.

Needless to say the next 3 days are pretty much party-time for the
kids. No school work will get done and that's a joy in itself.
Everyone is going to be on a crazy sugar rush. Good for them. :)


</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Inauguration</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210120-inauguration/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
inauguration
January 20th, 2021
----------------------------------------

A tangible weight has been lifted from my chest.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201231-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
December 31st, 2020
----------------------------------------

Be it resolved: 

This year I shall have a statue built in my honor AND torn down
in disgrace.

Oh, and regarding that resolution from 2020... 
Taylor Swift (featuring tomasino) - TomasWillow
    https://tomasino.is/music/assorted/taylorswift-tomaswillow.mp3

2020 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution
2019 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions
2018 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Seeing Colors</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201129-seeing-colors/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
seeing colors
November 29th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I don't know what possessed me to try, but I've been sitting here
for the last five minutes trying not to see color. I stared at my
Goodreads page (that's what was up at the time) and managed to get
the color to fade away in parts at a time but no luck on the full
color spectrum yet. The reds & greens were doable together, but
the blue is harder. If I focus on just not seeing blue then the
red pops back in.

Please don't ask me to explain what I'm even doing to try this.
The best way I can explain would be to say it's like blurring your
eyes, but they stay focused. Not helpful, right? It's also much
easier to do in the periphery than directly in the center of
vision. I understand we have more cones in the center of vision
than rods, so that's probably why. If I'm doing something to be
selective about that in good ol' brain meats, that would make
sense.

Have you ever tried this? Any luck?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Star Trek Discovery</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201126-star-trek-discovery/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Star Trek Discovery
November 26th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Holy shit, this show is the worst. It's physically painful for me.
Uggggghhhhhhh.

I was thinking about doing a systematic take-down laying out all
the failings in a logical way and truly sticking it to the
writers, but who has the energy for all that. Instead, here's
a rambling whine of why I think this is officially the worst trek
that has ever been.

First and foremost, Star Trek has always been an ensemble story*.
Discovery is a major departure for that and tries to lie to itself
that it's not. But James, what about the shaved-head pilot girl,
and the red-head, and the squid-faced guy, and the mushroom drive
guy and his husband the doctor? Fine. Name them. Seriously. What
is anyone's name on this damn show? Don't know, don't care. Nobody
gets more than half an episode of back-story except our darling.

Michael Burnham is the main character. She is, quite frankly,
a Mary Sue of the worst variety. Not only is every problem faced
by the universe something that she needs to fix personally, but
she will mutiny and disobey direct orders to do so only to be
forgiven time and time again because "she had no choice."
Bullshit. Utter crap. This character is relentlessly self-absorbed
and pig-headed. She acts recklessly and has gotten her own best
friend and captain killed in the process but learned nothing from
it. The worst of it is that she as this false modesty. "We'll do
it as a team," she says to the crew of nameless people after she
just went off solo and spoke for the whole federation without
consulting anyone on shit.

And what is with that? Everything Discovery does is saving the
entire universe or starting or ending galactic wars, the end of
all life, or some massive thing like that. The show starts out
with the Klingon wars which they either started or ended or both,
I can't keep it straight. Next up they're destroying empires in
the mirror universe and then I guess they ran out of history to
mess with so they've jumped forward in time so the Federation is
failing again so they can save it anew. This is a bad fanfiction
where everything needs to be the 100% most dramatic bullshit at
any moment. Why is one ship that nobody has ever heard of or
mentioned at all at the heart of every fucking event in history?
Why even mention the ship, how about we just mention Michael
Burnham, who has saved everything countless times and deserves
a whole planet to be carved into a statue of her. Except she is
also so meaningless that nobody ever mentioned that Spock had
a sister and she was human and did all this stuff. Yeah. that's
right. Spock's sister. Cause fanfic.

Okay, okay, so the plots are dumb and the characters illogical,
non-trek in style, and flat. But at least it's well constructed,
right? Well... sorta, except how the big bad Klingon lady in the
first season had such a shitty mask on she couldn't speak clearly
through it and everything came out muffled. Or there's the lens
flares on everything as if JJ Abrams didn't get his ass chewed out
over that a decade ago. Or silly things like having the saucer
section spin. Why does it do that? What purpose does that possibly
serve? And why does the ship flip upside down when it travels on
the mushroom super-highway.

Riiiiight, did I not mention the mushroom super-highway before?
That's the show's mcguffin right there. It can go anywhere
instantly. Nice, right? Except maybe that was a little too
powerful so we'll spend the next 3 seasons hamstringing it and
trying to backpedal. 

There's just so much stupid shit I can keep going forever. In
tonight's episode, for instance, the captain decided that after
Michael Burnham's 53rd disobeying of orders he should probably not
make her his first officer anymore. So who should replace her? Oh,
what about the plucky comic relief ensign? She's literally the
lowest ranked person on the entire fucking ship. Let's make her #2
in charge, mmmkay? But she's obviously not cut out for it and is
gonna sweat over the decision. I know, we'll have everyone chime
in and tell her to say yes to the dress and it'll be this epic
moment of solidarity. *VOMIT*

And that brings me to my last point. Last not because it's the
last thing wrong with the show but because I'm too bored of
talking about this waste of time to continue. "The Epic Moment"

That's what this show tries to be. The Epic Moment, again and
again and again. Why? Cause that's what fanfic does. Jump from
amazing thing to amazing thing, let your Mary Sue save the day and
have Epic Moments. Monologue, YES. Threaten and then do some
badass fighty shit and win. Don't worry that your ship is
literally 1000 years old and a little kid's toy bike could take
out your star ship now, you've got moxie. And the Epic Moments
won't just be action and adventure, but heartfelt too. How do we
know? Well, everyone will whisper and tear up! Yes, even the
Mirror Universe queen of evil shit will have a soft spot for
Michael Burnham's ass because Mary Sue!

In all of this, in every single moment, nothing is earned. Michael
will get 1 episode to journey into the future and adventure
wondering where the Discovery is. The very start of episode 2 she
finds the ship and has a tearful reunion about how she's been
searching for them for a whole year. You can tell cause her hair
got longer. We saw none of it, felt none of it, and so the payoff
is flat. It's the same when we say a tearful goodbye to bridge
crew member #7 who I never learned the name of, but had a funny
mouth guard. It's all meaningless drivel without actual emotional
depth because they never invested in anyone or anything. We were
too busy jumping through mushrooms to the next moment of awesome.

Nate Cull on Mastodon had this to add:

  I really feel that kids today (by which I mean most movie and TV
  sci-fi writers) just have zero experience of working in
  a competent functioning team and so they can't write stories in
  a setting that requires there be a competent functioning team.
  It's all gotta be "BUT MY PROBLEMS COME FIRST" and having loud
  temper tantrums while trying to, eg, run an actual ship which
  will explode if anyone pushes the wrong button at any moment on
  their shift.

  I wonder if this is partly because having a career in movies or
  TV writing is something that only spoiled rich kids can afford
  to do nowadays, and so they literally can't comprehend what it's
  like to not always be the most important person in the room. Or
  is it just a deliberate dumbing down of writing to try to
  capture a young mass audience who have mostly never experienced
  working in even, say, a factory, let alone a military?

  But I mean if you even ran a McDonalds like the Federation runs
  the Starship Discovery, yikes.

I couldn't agree more.

This show is just terrible writing. It's an embarrassment to the
Star Trek franchise. It undermines what it stands for and weakens
canon with nonsense. The best I can hope for is that the last act
of the dying crew will be to erase themselves from history so we
can all ignore this shit and get back to our lives.

----- 

* I acknowledge that Picard is not an ensemble story, but it is
not pretending to be one. It's literally named for the one guy.
I am okay with this. They could have made the entire show about
him growing grapes on his vineyard and I'd have sat through it to
see Patrick Stewart act.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Talkd Fixes In Ubuntu 20 04</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201011-talkd-fixes-in-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
talkd fixes in ubuntu 20.04
October 11th, 2020
----------------------------------------

When cosmic voyage updated to ubuntu 20.04 subtle things broke
that I didn't notice right away. One of these was talk(1). We were
using ytalk(1) as the program of choice back in 18.10, but that
seems to no longer be in apt. I reinstalled it from source and was
hopeful that it would do the trick. Not so much.

I fought this for an hour tonight with a very patient voyager
helping me out. I tried closing out of mosh and tmux to narrow
down the issue. Eventually I got a clue from the error message in
syslog.

talkd[411722]: 127.0.0.1 (127.0.0.1): unintelligible packet

I had a lot of these messages and they eventually got me to
a redhat bug report that suggested removing the inetd entry for
talkd would fix it. I commented that out and left the ntalkd line
in place.

I also fixed a thing that bugged me from back in the day. The
nobody user had been configured to be a part of the tty group and
I was using it in that inetd line. That felt dirty since nobody
shouldn't have access to anything.

  sudo useradd -c 'in.talkd User' \
  -d /nonexistent \ -s /usr/sbin/nologin \
  -r -g tty talk

So I added a 'talk' user, gave it the proper access, and swapped
inetd to use that instead. Then I gave it a kick (restart the
process) and things are working again. Whew!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
