<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Christmas Break</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181223-christmas-break/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Christmas break
December 23rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was leaning against the counter in my kitchen while typing in
IRC and then started a coughingn fit. Why am I coughing,
I wondered as I rubbed at the bruise forming on my solar plexus.
Derp.

I'm now sitting comfortably in the stool that was right beside me.
I am very smart. :/

Anywho, I'm on break for Christmas this week and I hope to get
a few fun side-things accomplished. For one, I'd like to write at
least one substantial update for each of my ships in cosmic [0].
My original ship, Melchizedek, is in trouble with their botany
systems, while Starbloom may be going to war. My two newest ships
are Oleander, which is the story of a suicide mission sending
their final messages before activation, and Melvin P Feltersnatch,
a silly story with bad physics and quite a bit of nonsense.

[0] Cosmic Voyage
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/

I also dusted off a project idea I had called Ways. It's intended
to be an open-source text-adventure engine and expandable world.
Right now it's very much in "dream up the stuff" phase. I'm not
bothering to even choose a programming language yet. I want to get
all the concepts down in a README so I can go at it later for
execution. This week should give me a decent start on that.

In other news, Christmas is nearly upon us! I've been teaching my
son about the Icelandic Yule Lads and Yule Cat and he's loving it.
We've been leaving his shoe in the window each night and reading
up on each of the lads. It's so cute.

OMG, I haven't written since we sold the house! Um, yeah. We sold
our house on the 10th of December. I'm renting a 2br apartment
about a mile away from the house until the end of June when we
intend to make the move to Iceland. I've given myself a break from
any planning on that front until the new year, too. Self care?

We had a 5 bedroom house with a massive basement and detached
garage. Needless to say, we downsized quite a bit and are
continuing to do so. My wife found an awesome charity that takes
home goods and furniture for kids aging out of the foster system
and moving out on their own. Most of the house goods went to them.
My son gave up 2/3rds of his toys to Goodwill. I downsized my
computers to a single laptop (which I'm replacing next Friday with
a new one from System 76). We have a storage unit that is 10x20
and needs to get reduced down to 5x10 before June. The stuff
remaining will go into long-term storage in Charlotte near my
wife's family. The stuff in the apartment will get packed up and
shipped to Iceland. Somehow we'll make it all work.

---

There's been so many awesome discussions kicking around in
gopherspace that I haven't been engaging with. Ugh, now I want to
go back and write you all individual responses here. Instead, just
know that I'm reading everything in great detail, from the stuff
on the growing Zaibatsu adventure to the music generation scripts
to the OTHER burrow to home-grown RPGs. You are all amazing people
who keep me entertained and inspired. Especially you, Melton. Your
life is incredible. Never stop writing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Tfurrows Bible Translations</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181208-re-tfurrows-bible-translations/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: tfurrows - bible translations
December 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

tfurrows wrote [0] about picking up a copy of the English Standard
Version (ESV) Bible, a modern language translation by Crossway. It
just so happens that the ESV is my personal favorite translation
for casual bible reading. I like it so much, in fact, that
I sought out permission from Crossway to post the full contents of
the ESV on gopher.black. You can find it over here [1]!

[0] tfurrows - bible translations
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~tfurrows/phlog/2018-12-05_bibleTranslations.txt
[1] ESV Bible
    gopher://gopher.black/1/bible

I love the New American Standard Version (NASV) as well, as it's
the one used in the Catholic mass in the US and it's a very good
literal translation. For study I bounce around between versions,
especially since my Greek and Hebrew aren't particularly strong
language skills. I need to review alternate translations to find
new ways at the text.

Anyway, tfurrows, I hope you enjoy the ESV. There's a fantastic
set of commentaries that goes with it which you can find online
for free. Or, if you're just reading through for fun, you are
welcome to use gopher!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Jynx So Much Cool Stuff Going On</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181128-re-jynx-so-much-cool-stuff-going-on/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: jynx - so much cool stuff going on
November 28th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Jynx recently wrote [0] about gopher decentralization (and gave me
a cool shoutout). He also drew attention to federation tools
between the tildeverse and other micro-communities like
circumlunar. I love it and agree whole-heartedly. 

Cosmic Voyage is hosting an ircd that is part of the
irc.tilde.chat round-robin. I would love to figure out a way to
make my local mail on that box play nicely with tilde's, but not
open up wide to the universe. bbj style message boards that can
federate would be great too, like FidoNet. Bring on the cool
stuff, people.

Oh, and jynx, please do set up something in the cosmic.voyage
vein, even if it's via git. We need more!!! One of the folks that
sits in tilde IRC mentioned to me this morning that he plans on
making a D&D/Fantasy style version of cosmic. I would LOVE to see
that, and likely join. I'm imagining it as stories being told
"back at the inn". How cool.

So yes, gopherspace is growing and exploding with badassery.
Circumlunar phlogs are so popular. Maybe we can get tilde.team and
tilde.town communities thinking a little more gophery and get
their vast numbers phlogging too. Let's all keep on with
solderpunk's call to arms [1]: Hey you! Host something!

jynx - so much cool stuff going on
    gopher://1436.ninja/0/Phlog/20181128.post
solderpunk - hey you host something
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/hey-you-host-something.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Easy Dated Files For Sorting</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181127-easy-dated-files-for-sorting/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Easy dated files for sorting
November 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

For those of you out there using gophernicus and forcing
yourselves to write your posts with cumbersome file-name prefixes
for proper sorting, let me help you out.

Gophernicus allows you to execute in-line scripts in your
gophermaps. That means you can do something like this:

=ls -1r | grep -v 'gophermap' | awk '{printf "0%s\t%s\n", $1, $1}'

It will grab all the files in your directory, flip the order, and
print them out into a pretty gophermap for you. Tada! Just drop
files in place and name them with the date, YYYY-MM-DD. You'll
sort just fine.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cosmic Voyage</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181124-cosmic-voyage/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cosmic.voyage
November 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Cosmic Voyage is live!

Cosmic Voyage on Gopher
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/
Cosmic Voyage on the Web
    http://cosmic.voyage
Cosmic Voyage RSS Feed
    http://cosmic.voyage/rss.xml

If you don't know what I'm talking about, look here:
Space Gopher, Revisited
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181119-space-gopher-revisited

If you'd like to join, send an email to:

        tomasino [at] lavabit [dot] com

Be sure to include the following:

        1. Your desired username - we don't use it in the story
           itself, but there may be some uses on the system for
           local mail and logging in.

        2. Your first ship/colony/outpost name - This is what
           you'll be using to write the story content. You can
           have as many ships as you'd like. Just send me a note
           to request more.

        3. A public SSH key - We use key-based logins to ssh, not
           passwords. Shoot me the contents of the key or a link
           to it.

Once you sign up you'll receive an email detailing some basic
operations on the server. For instance, to author a message in the
story you'll need to be able to do two things:

        1. Create & edit text files
        2. Run the 'log' command and follow the prompts

No gopher expertise is needed!

If you have more questions, I'm pretty easy to find. For
cosmic.voyage in particular I sit in the #cosmic channel on
irc.tilde.chat. Information on how to connect to that server here:
tilde.chat
    http://tilde.chat/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The At Command</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181121-the-at-command/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
the at command
November 21st, 2018
----------------------------------------

I am going to be unavailable during my anonradio show tomorrow
night, and I wanted to queue up my show stream in my absence.
I knew that I could set up all the files I needed on a server
somewhere (in this case, tilde.team) and cron job the stream, but
it bothered me that I'd be setting up a reoccurring task for
something that should be a one-shot. *nix is old enough that this
couldn't be a new problem, so I searched around for a proper
solution. 

Enter 'at'. It's exactly what I needed. Run a script AT a certain
time. Just once. Tada!

$ man at

This reveals a lot of info, but it's pretty poorly documented, at
least by my new openbsd documentation standards. It took some
trial and error and searching through examples before I settled on
something that appears like it should work. We'll see tomorrow
night, I suppose!

One final note: at runs its script as you from your current
directory using your current environment. Basically, whatever your
shell looked like at the moment you defined the 'at' command,
that's how it'll execute. This is a huge convenience for these
one-shots. 

If everything goes off well tomorrow night, I expect I'll be using
this more often, maybe even to do simple things like cue up my
outro-music for my show!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Space Gopher Revisited</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181119-space-gopher-revisited/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Space Gopher, Revisited
November 19th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A while back I mused [0] about how some quantum mechanics mixed
with interstellar travel could create a scenario for text-based
communications to thrive, at least in fiction. Tonight the idea
came back to me again. 

I've been hanging out with the tilde [1] crowd a lot lately, and
it's so inspiring. I want to give back and make more of these
micro-instance outposts that offer one thing really well. So many
people have been phlogging about it recently, especially
solderpunk [2]. How can I legitimately contribute, though? I don't
think I have the time or energy for a full tilde admin role. Plus,
there's already a bunch of these general purpose communities. What
would be unique about mine?

So, then I began thinking about what motivates me and what I love.
Storytelling is #1, especially role-playing games. Merge all that
together and it gives me such a great idea:

  Humanity has expanded to the stars, but it wasn't in a single
  great migration as many thought. Small communities and
  individual families have drifted impossible distances away,
  connected only through the thin tethers of a Quantum Entaglement
  Communicator (QEC) which bridges their tiny bandwidth back to
  this ancient relay hub. These are pen-pal letters, reports,
  updates, cries for help, and calls into the darkness. What is
  delivered to the system is unfiltered. Some of it is
  intelligible. For some, common language has drifted too far for
  clear translation. 

  The year is unimportant and irrelevant due to relativistic
  travel. The only agreed upon date is the "now" of the QEC. 

  Launching sometime soon: A gopher-focused tilde community that
  exists 100% in-game, sharing stories across the universe on the
  only remaining free, interconnected network that unites the
  dispersed peoples of the stars.

Would you participate?

[0] Space Gopher 2000
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180705-space-gopher-2000
[1] tildeverse
    http://tildeverse.org/
[2] Circumlunar Updates
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/circumlunar-updates.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Yourtilde Com</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181118-yourtilde-com/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
yourtilde.com
November 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm adding another mirror of gopher.black to yourtilde.com,
a fantastic new addition to the tildeverse run by deepend.

gopher://yourtilde.com/1/~tomasino

Just in case, ya'll!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Perfection</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181113-perfection/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Perfection
November 13th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Very soon I'll be giving up my role as a manager and moving back
into the world of sole contributer. For the past five or six years
I've been a VP level director of a team or teams of developers. At
one point in time I had 24 direct reports across three offices.
These days I just have 3 direct reports at one office. Regardless,
my role has been primarily focused on facilitation, management,
coaching and strategy, with a heavy dollop of analytics work. It's
not that I don't get my hands dirty; I code all the time. It's
just that I'm typically jumping in to solve a single problem, or
create a framework, or rescue something gone astray. I rarely find
myself in the position of building things from scratch.

There's freelance, of course. I just completed a landing page for
a pharma company that will be launching shortly. It was an excuse
for me to learn the newest CSS features out there, CSS-Grid, and
to make sure I'm still sharp. Everything went exceptionally well,
and I should have a nice little side-money from it soon.

With the move out of the country I wanted to refocus on what
I enjoy doing and what keeps the stress level low. My dad was
a work-a-holic, and I could easily see myself falling into the
trap. I'm staring at a career crossroads: do I continue on my
present trajectory and take on C-suite positions and eventually
start my own company, or do I take a step back and focus on family
and friends at the cost of salary. It's not an easy decision.

I'm hoping Iceland can be a disconnect from a life of things.
I don't want all this stuff I've gathered. I have too many
hobbies, too many computers, too many projects. I want to take
a walk with the family and spend more time seeing my son smile.
While I don't want the stress of bills piling up, we're well past
the level of comfortable living. I don't need more if we're just
going to spend it.

So with the move to Iceland I'm giving up my VP title and my
managerial duties. I'm taking a step back into a senior developer
or lead architect role (whatever we decide to call it). I'll be
building things again and taking a pay cut to align. This feels
good and right, at least for now.

And it gives me the opportunity to think about what I enjoy about
coding. I'm a perfectionist in the work I do professionally. When
given a task I dig deep and try to solve it in ways that
anticipate things the designers never dreamed of. I anticipate the
ways testers will try to break things. I focus intensely on
pixel-perfect design execution without any compromise of speed or
accessibility. I want every piece of throw-away advertising trash
I build to be a perfect specimen.

Today I built a digital sales aid for pharmaceutical reps
detailing a drug that treats ALS. It's a tool that shows off payer
data and coverage information relevant to the doctor being
detailed. The original plan was for a national-level print piece,
but we managed to get the company to send us a feed of their raw
data. I worked on some analysis in R and generated specific
breakdowns for their list and found an elegant way to side-load
it into their presentations. The reps have extremely personalized
digital pieces now, which will give the home office interesting
analytics on the use of the tools and allow us to further segment
their targets by degree of concern about access and coverage, if
the client bothers to look at the data we collect anyway.

While the content I'm building isn't particularly interesting
I found ways to challenge myself, level it up, and focused on
perfection. That gives me a great deal of satisfaction. When I can
build something (even something dumb) perfectly in the first try,
that's a great feeling. I'm looking forward to more of that soon.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Notice</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181112-notice/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
NOTICE
November 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This gophermaster uses cookies (and milk). By reading this content
you acknowledge and accept our use of cookies for eating purposes.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
