<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/users/username/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>backups are good</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180414-backups-are-good/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Backups are good
April 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Alex Schroeder wrote recently [0] about backup formats. It was an
important reminder that since I'd moved everything (web, gopher,
... is that everything?) to a raspberry pi and configured it all
to a working state, I hadn't backed up the system. Granted, all
the content I have is in git, but the system configuration itself
is worth quite a bit of work.

Evidence of this can be found easily. Tonight after I did a backup
(more on that in a second) I rebooted the machine and discovered
that bitlbee didn't start up correctly. I'm using kensanata's
fabulous bitlbee-mastodon plugin [1] to do all my social media
junk via IRC. It's awesome, but it was a headache to get working.
For some reason I couldn't get it to play nice with the apt
version of Bitlbee, so I had to compile everything from source.
Tonight when bitlbee stopped responding I ended up trying the
whole process over again, eventually giving up on apt again, and
reinstalling from source. (This time I properly set up systemd.)

Mastodon in Weechat is a minor thing, but it's evidence enough
that I don't want to have to rebuild the box. So, I unplugged the
pi for a few minutes, removed the SD card, plugged it into another
machine and 'dd' copied everything to an ISO. I don't think I need
to worry about doing that too often, thankfully, as it means
downtime for the box. If I ever needed to restore, I can flash
a new SD card, plug it in, then run update on all the git repos.
It will pick up pretty much everything that way, unless I do some
serious system additions.

I think I'll do the full SD backup semi-annually, maybe when
I change the batteries in my smoke detectors. It has a similar
sort of safety-maintenance feel.

[0] Alex Schroeder - Backup Format
    gopher://alexschroeder.ch/02018-04-13_Backup_Format
[1] Kensanata - Bitlbee-Mastodon
    http://github.com/kensanata/bitlbee-mastodon
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>burrow v1 5 0 portable</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180411-burrow-v1-5-0-portable/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
burrow v1.5.0 - portable
April 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

burrow v1.5.0 is released [0]. I've removed the bash 4+
requirement and moved the script to /bin/sh. There are a number of
other small improvements and bug fixes as well.

[0] burrow v1.5.0
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/burrow/releases/tag/v1.5.0

You can always find a link to the latest release in the root of
this gopher hole. Grab your copy and test it out. Find a bug? Log
it on Github, please [1].

[1] burrow issues
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/burrow/issues
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>size</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180409-size/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Size
April 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

tfurrows recently wrote [0] about about the American need for more
space, more square footage, and generally bigger and better
things. You might harken it back to the "go West" mentality and an
assumption born from multi-generational standard-of-living growth,
but I have no real clue where it comes from. And tfurrows is
absolutely right when he says you get looked at funny for defying
that pattern.

[0] tfurrows - square feet
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~tfurrows/phlog/akr_squareFeet.txt

My dad certainly doesn't understand my desire to simplify,
downsize (right-size?), and work less. It's really frustrating
with him in particular because he worked so hard to achieve more
and earn more his whole life so that he could enjoy it later, but
he was diagnosed with a death sentence nearly the day after he
retired. How can that not wake you up to the here and now and say,
"use it while you've got it"?

I want a smaller house. Much smaller. This is my first home and
I got it for a ridiculous price because the housing market had
tanked two years before and the owner had been dropping his
selling price ever since. It's now worth double what I paid and
I can't wait to sell it. It's fantastic to have a bunch of space,
but we just fill it with things we don't have time to use. More BS
filling it up is no help to anyone. It's also a huge burden on us
maintaining it and paying utilities. I don't need to work harder
and longer to pay for things I'm not using.

Once we go to Iceland I plan on renting again (if their rental
situation gets cleared up, that is) and eventually working up to
a small home. I don't want any more space than I need. If that
means I have to go outside more, even better! Lowering my
cost-of-living means I can enjoy the same options or more and
still lower my workload. I'm not going to be able to match my
current salary in Iceland anyway, so it all aligns. Work less,
live smaller, enjoy things today instead of putting them off for
later.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>burrow release v1 4 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180409-burrow-release-v1-4-1/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
burrow release v1.4.1
April 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A new minor release of burrow is ready (v1.4.1) with mostly
compatability updates.

  - Removed longopts completely
  - Removed gnu getopt requirement
  - All echos -> printf
  - Shellcheck debugging settings for stylistic newlines
  - Better error handling
  - Fixed gnu specific switches on coreutils find

Want to help me test it out? Grab the latest release [0]

[0] burrow v1.4.1
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/burrow/releases/tag/v1.4.://github.com/jamestomasino/burrow/releases/tag/v1.4.1
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>re sysdharma gophercon</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180408-re-sysdharma-gophercon/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: sysdharma - Gophercon
April 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was so excited about the possibility of a gophercon when I saw
the first mention of Brazil. I was just as heartbroken when it
turned out (once again) to be about Go-lang. It drives me crazy
that they keep using "gopher" for everything. Fakes me out every
time. Boo.

Bitreich has something they do in Germany for gopher, but I'm not
sure what sort of attendance it gets or if it's more for their
private community. I'd love a real gopher (1436) conference, but
we regular users are far too spread out around the globe. I can't
imagine many people traveling across continents to attend. Maybe
a virtual thing? Do those work?

If we were to have a conference I think it should either be called
simply "1436con" or "Port 70". No confusion there. What sort of
things would happen at a conference for gopher? Ideas:

  - A talk or two on TLS and Gopher over Tor 
  - Panel discussion on the pros & cons of adding new ItemTypes
  - "To gophermap or not to gophermap, that is the question"
  - Social networking on legacy, minimal systems
  - Other sociological stuff about community
  - "Content is King"

What else?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>interactive fiction</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180408-interactive-fiction/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Interactive Fiction
April 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I've been thinking about writing some interactive fiction, or at
least a choose-your-own-adventure story. I want to do it on gopher
using gophermaps, keeping it as simple as links at the end of each
section. Any suggestions for a subject, theme, genre? I don't want
to tackle anything too long since I'll have to write all the
different variations.

Have any of you done one of these before? I was going to plot it
out on notecards first and write the scenes from there. Is there
a better way?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>cyberspace</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180408-cyberspace/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Cyberspace
April 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A few minutes ago in the #gopher irc room on sdf.org, zcrayfish
just mentioned remembering connecting to sdf over old modem
programs (xyzmodem). It brought back a flood of memories. I last
remember using zmodem to connect to my friend Kris's new machine.
We connected via blank term sometimes and just typed messages back
and forth in the same buffer. When we switched to zmodem I can
remember the thrill the first time we successfully resumed a file
transfer, not having to start it all over. Brilliant.

Mostly what stood out to me in memory is that the setting of these
memories was virtual. I did not remember sitting at my computer
using zmodem, but as if my place in the world was within zmodem.
I embodied it to the fullest extent of existential awareness.
I had no body, only idea form.

That makes me think more broadly on that concept. I did not have
it before that time when connecting to Prodigy and spending time
on the Xanth Chatroom I would eventually moderate. Those memories
involve seeing my hands typing, and the texture of the monitor.
I wasn't "in" the computer then. Ahh, but later, connecting to
Snakes Lair BBS in South Jersey, I am there in the door games, in
the discussion boards, in all of it.

BBSes are the start of virtual existance for me. That feels pretty
cool.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>fat</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180407-fat/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fat
April 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I keep track of my weight and a bunch of other measurements with
a little shell function that logs to a csv file on dropbox. A year
ago I made some fantastic progress but then it all fell apart.
With the new year I started getting back into my good habits and
once again was making progress. Last month I got really sick: flu,
pneumonia, blah blah. I fell off the wagon (a food wagon) and have
been eating like crap once again.

Tomorrow it's back on diet again (keto) and I know I'll feel so
much better soon. To help prep me mentally I decided to plot my
weight progress.

│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⡠⢢⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢠⢆⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢀⠔⠉⠀⠀⢣⠀⠀⠀⡠⠃⠘⡄⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⡜⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠱⡀⡰⠁⠀⠀⢱⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢠⠃⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠑⠁⠀⠀⠀⠀⡇⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⡸⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠸⡀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢀⠇⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢣
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢸⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠈
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⡇⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠉⠒⠤⣀⡀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢰⠁⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠈⠉⠑⠒⠤⠤⣀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⣀⣀⣀⣀⣀⣀⣀⡎⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠉⠒⠤⣀⣀⣀⣀⡀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢰⠁⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠈⠉⠑⠒⠤⣀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⢀⠇⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠉⠢⡀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⡜⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠈⠢⡀⠀⠀⠀⢠⠃⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠈⠢⢄⠀⡎⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠙⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
│⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀⠀
└────────────────────────────────────────────────────────────

I've stripped off the axis info here cause you don't need to see
all that, but you can see from the shape of the data that it's
been a wild ride. I hope things go more smoothly this time. I'm
sick of being fat.

  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -

Side note: I generated that chart with an awesome command-line
plotter called jp [0]. My tracker (which needs a lot of coded
cleanup) can be found here [1].

[0] jp
    http://github.com/sgreben/jp
[1] track
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/dotfiles/blob/master/bash/.functions/track

The final command to generate that chart:

  # my csv is formatted (year,month,day,weight)
  awk -F "," '{print $1 "-" $2 "-" $3 "," $4}' weight.csv | \
    jp \
      -input csv \
      -xy '[*][0,1]' \
      -canvas braille \
      -height 25 \
      -width 67
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>gopher alert bob alberti is here</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180406-gopher-alert-bob-alberti-is-here/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gopher Alert: Bob Alberti is here
April 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Bob Alberti [0] is now on SDF and has started a Phlog [1]. You
might remember him from a little thing called The Internet Gopher
Protocol RFC [2]. This is absolutely thrilling! Bob, if you see
this, welcome back to the land YOU built. I hope you enjoy the new
life that's being breathed back into it in our little corner.

[0] About Bob
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/alberti/aboutme
[1] Bob Alberti's Phlog
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/alberti/phlog
[2] The Internet Gopher Protocol (RFC 1436)
    gopher://gopher.black/0/archive/rfc/1436.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>the bible</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/users/username/phlog/./20180405-the-bible/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Bible
April 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Yesterday I added a new section to my gopher hole [0]. It's the
English Standard Version of the Bible, used with permission. I've
written a script to fetch books/chapters/verses on demand and used
it to prepopulate a full view of the Bible, chapter by chapter.
I'm pretty sure everything came in properly, but I'll be double
checking over the coming weeks.

My next step is to add some safeguards to the script and make it
work on demand as a cgi. There are limitations on how much can be
queried at once and such attached to the API, so I'll need to plan
accordingly. Stay tuned!

In the meantime, pop on over and give it a read. It's my favorite
translation: a literal one with modern grammar. I've opted to
suppress chapter & verse markings as well as footnotes and just
let the text live on its own. I think it makes things much more
reabable.

[0] The Bible (ESV)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/bible
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
