<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>A Warning To New Friends</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180401-a-warning-to-new-friends/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A warning to new friends
April 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

Take a moment to compose yourself and disconnect from the moment
happening around you.

Think about your place in the world and let your mind slowly zoom
out. Watch that place become a spec and then nothing at all as
your inward eye moves toward the infinite.

Now, with that distance and sense of impartiality consider for
a moment your own actions to the people around you. Think about
what you consider good and what leaves a bitter taste in your
mouth. Don't linger too long on any one thing, but try not to skip
over the shameful parts completely.

Everyone you meet today will face that person you just examined.
That person: keep the idea separate from yourself for now.

If a friend were to encounter that person today, what would you
warn them about before the encounter? How would you guide them to
a better relationship?
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>To Gophermap Or No</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180331-to-gophermap-or-no/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
To gophermap or no
March 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

Quick poll:

Do you think I should keep using gophermaps for my phlog, or
should I move back to type 0 and include non-followable links as
text, like so [0].

[0]: https://tomasino.org

Let me know on gopher, mastodon, or email, or whatever. My contact
info is in the About [1] page.

[1] About
    gopher://gopher.black/1/about
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>This Old House</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180331-this-old-house/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
This old house
March 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm standing in an empty room facing a large bow window stretching
from the rough wooden floor to a rounded arching top. There is
some dust and dirt in the corners and fallen between the floor
boards gapping slightly with age. To my right is a door to the
hallway and eventually roof access. Behind me a closet holds shoe
boxes of memories.

I know the layout of this place intimitely, though I've never
really been there. It doesn't really exist. In a sense it is my
memory palace [0]. In another sense, it is like the Hi'ngwikan of
the Lenape people and I am its a-la-pa-cte [1]. It is a private
place of prayer and solitude where I can organize my thoughts and
intentions.

[0] Method of loci
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Method of loci
[1] Lenape "Big House" Ceremony
    http://bit.ly/2GmQwgt

I don't remember the first time I went there, but I do remember
that it started with that window. I can still count the panes of
glass, see the smudges of fingerprints I've left, note the
imperfections in the glass as it distorts my view. These details
give it permanence that I find vital. Knowing the texture of the
wood gives me a comfort that I need to let myself be free. It is
through that freedom that I find peace.

                           - - - - -

Earlier today vilmibm posted [2] about what home means to him, and
how he is able to find it digitally by just finding a quite space
and connecting to his familiar tools, music, and communities.
I love that sentiment. I have anxiety over the question of "where
is home" or "where are you from". I could probably blame the Roma
heritage but that feels like cheating. In reality, I just don't
associate a physical place with home at all. Though I might wish
an online community or my digital environment to become home like
vilmibm has found, I don't think that fits me either.

[2] vilmibm's feels (2018-03-30)
    gopher://tilde.town/0/~vilmibm/feels/20180330.txt

No, my home is a dusty old house with a big bow window that always
has a different view when I look through it. I know where I keep
the memories of relationships past (in that closet on the bottom
shelf in a white shoebox), and I know that when I get really sad
I need to go out onto the rooftop garden and greenhouse and let
the light pour into me. 

                           - - - - -

Tonight I felt some of that sadness coming on. At first I thought
it might mean I was going to have a good evening writing (it's
much easier for me to write when depressed) but I felt it take
a sour turn in my mind. So, instead of wallowing I spent a little
time in meditation and prayer in my little old house.  No sooner
had I sat on that dusty floor and placed my hands lightly on the
wooden slats when a cloud broke and a fresh beam of sunlight
warmed my cheek. Like everything in that place, the symbols speak
a language I understand intuitively. 

That sunlight is what I needed tonight. That's how my prayer
works.
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rss Feed</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180331-rss-feed/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
RSS Feed
March 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

After the mini-poll on the last post I have decided to keep my
gophermap formatting on my phlog. As a sign of faith to the text
purists, I am now generating a happy little RSS feed for the most
recent 10 posts. You can find the feed here [0] and also see
a link to it on my main gophermap [1].

[0] gopher.black RSS feed
    gopher://gopher.black/0/rss.xml
[1] gopher.black
    gopher://gopher.black/1/

For those of you using newsbeuter, you can add this to your feed
list by dropping this line into the 'urls' file:

  "exec:curl -s gopher://gopher.black/0/rss.xml"

To accomplish this, rather than add a cgi script to my site,
I decided to add the RSS generation feature to burrow.

  $ burrow rss # generates the rss feed

There's also a config parameter to auto-generate RSS when writing
new phlogs. Check out the man page or README.md to see more.

NOTE: There's one little weakness of my RSS generator. It will
organize the most recent entries by date, but if you post multiple
entries in a single day, it just alphabetizes them. I'm sure you
guys can all deal with it.
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Quick Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180329-quick-updates/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Quick Updates
March 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Lynx has added support for the + item type. You can find it
working in 2.8.9dev.17. It displays with a prefix of (+++) to
distinguish it from other menu items. I beleive sacc plans similar
style of support.

kichimi's server made moku-pona sad and hang while it was down.
Luckily both he and Alex Schroeder are badass and a timeout was
quickly added to the program. While Alex was tinkering, he also
changed the display style of the generated gophermap to be more
condensed. I dig it. You can see the results over here [0].

[0] Phlogs I follow
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlogs

zcrayfish has finally joined the phlog parade [1]. He also made me
realize that .soy is a TLD! Make sure to add him to your lists.

[1] zcrayfish's phlog
    gopher://gopher.zcrayfish.soy/1/phlog
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>More Migrations</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180329-more-migrations/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
More migrations
March 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I stayed up a little bit late last night and transferred all my
domains off of AWS, then I nuked it. Every trace of me is gone
from that platform, and once this horrible bill is paid I'm
closing the account completely.

In the wake of the move I started thinking about where to put all
my stuff and I decided that this little Raspberry Pi is more than
sufficient for my needs. I have already gone through the headache
of converting all my web properties to static sites in order to
host on S3, so putting content into nginx seems like the easy and
obvious next step.

I've installed nginx and I'm reading up on how to manage multiple
sites with it (seems almost identical to Apache). I'll clone down
the websites when I get home tonight, port forward 80 and reset my
DNS A records. I've already put together a script for gopher.black
that handles my dynamic dns changes and updates Namesilo, so I can
easily package in the rest of my domains there. Finally, I'll want
HTTPS, so I guess it's finally time for me to read the man page on
certbot and start using LetsEncrypt. Whee!

None of this sounds particularly difficult. Hopefully I won't run
into any unexpected walls.

- - - - -

Moving away from the technical stuff, dropping AWS also represents
a shedding of a gross skin I've been wearing. I don't like the
monolithic, data-consuming giants. It hurts my heart when
I continue to use them, as I've mentioned before. I acknowledge
that I'll make choices that compromise my principles due to
convenience, and that's something I would like to lessen.

Do you think simply pulling websites off AWS can help facilitate
that sort of change? Am I ready to shut down my Google account? Is
that even viable as an Android user with Project Fi? I doubt it.
What are my realistic alternatives for phone service, anyway? Next
year I'll have a super-basic eInk phone I can set up on t-mobile,
but are they any better? Is any phone service any better?

I suspect I have a tiny bit of inertia I can use here but I just
don't see a clear action I can take. A lot of you have done
similar transitions in the past. Do you have any advice?
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Leaving Aws</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180329-leaving-aws/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Leaving AWS
March 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Earlier this week I got a notification from the AWS console that
my billing alarm level had been reached. I'm glad I set it because
there's no other way I would have know that I was running up an
incredibly expensive bill.

Over the weekend I was experimenting with Nextcloud and linked an
AWS S3 volume as an extra share. Something went wrong and the
syncs were failing, but constantly retrying to download data. At
least, this is what I now believe is the root cause. At the time
I figured it was one of my public sites getting abused.

I went digging around in AWS to see if I could figure out who the
culprit was, but that was in vain. AWS is a labyrinth of excessive
overengineering, techno-babble, and the worlds worst
documentation. I can find no information about where the charges
are coming from beyond "bandwidth".

It's 2 days later and my bill is over $300. I logged a support
ticket asking Amazon what the hell is happening, but screw it. I'm
done. I don't need AWS shit, it was just the idea of fast
performance that brought me there. My sites are all static.

I unlocked my domains and I'm transferring them to Namesilo. I'll
save down some of the crap sitting in cold storage, re-clone my
static sites on the gopher.black pi, add in nginx and tell my
router to forward port 80.

The cloud can suck it.
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Acme Sh Shenanigans</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180329-acme-sh-shenanigans/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
acme.sh shenanigans
March 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

These are notes to myself on how I finally got acme.sh and nginx
to play nice.


Step 1: Generate a cert

I'm using the namesilo api method here, so this part is simple.

acme.sh --issue --dns dns_namesilo --dnssleep 900 -d tomasino.org
-d www.tomasino.org -w /var/www

Step 2: Create a place to put those certs

This part was a struggle. Since acme.sh doesn't need root to run,
so I wasn't sure where to go. Eventually I settled on creating
a directory at /etc/nginx/acme.sh/domain/ and changed ownership to
www-data:www-data. I'm a member of that group and nginx works with
that too, so it should be good.

Step 3: Install the certs

This is poorly documented pretty much everywhere. It will pull the
files from the .acme.sh directory in your home folder and put them
wherever you define here. The reload command will run as root, so
you don't need to specify sudo. 

acme.sh --install-cert -d tomasino.org --key-file
/etc/nginx/acme.sh/tomasino.org/key.pem --cert-file
/etc/nginx/acme.sh/tomasino.org/cert.pem --fullchain-file
/etc/nginx/acme.sh/tomasino.org/fullchain.pem --reloadcmd
"service nginx force-reload"

Step 4: Set up the nginx configuration

First, a server directive on port 80 that just redirects to the
ssl version.

Second, listen on 443, add a bunch of headers, set up ssl
protocols, ciphers, link to the cert, key, and trusted cert
(fullchain). Etc, etc...

Step 5: Restart/Start nginx

Hopefully it doesn't crap out on you like it did for me 5,000
times.
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher On Gopher</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180328-gopher-on-gopher/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gopher on Gopher
March 28th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I've become self-conscious of my own phlogging on gopher on the
subject of gopher, or gopher related things. I do a lot of writing
about the protocol, the community, my scripts for my phlog, other
people's phlogging, gopher project, you get the idea. I started to
worry that I was neglecting original content for its own right
that wasn't all oriented to the weird little place we hang out. As
a result, I'm going to try to post more non-gophery things. There
will be no hard and fast rules about numbers or anything, but I'll
try.
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Distributism</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20180327-distributism/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Distributism
March 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I've been thinking about politics too much lately, so I thought
I'd liven things up by jumping into economics! I'll keep this one
short, I promise.

I'm no fan of capitalism, especially "free" market economics. It
is tantamount to slavery both in its literal abuse of the third
world or the consolidation of wealth into the corporate leading to
wage-slavery in the first world. The appeal of endless growth is
clear, but it's so obviously unsustainable that I can't keep up
the lie to myself. Eventually you will run out of peoples to
exploit and the workers will have no money to spend. It will
consume itself or transform from economic oligarchy into political
oligarchy.

No, the modern fascination with democracy is mirrored by the lust
for wealth that capitalism promises. In reality, the regulation
that free-market champions condemn are the very things that have
kept us from the brink thus far. The world economy teeters on the
edge of absolute ruin and it will be the greedy, get-rich-quick,
that take us all there.

There are alternatives, and they don't all involve us devolving
into an agrestic commune. Distributism [0] is my economic
structure of choice. Here's the extremely brief key points:

  - personal property is a right of the individual
  - don't assign to higher association what lesser and subordinate
    organizations can do
  - small production and local culture is favored over central
    systems and mass production

  AKA, keep it small and owned by the workers.

The best examples I can give in today's culture are credit unions
and farming co-ops.

Of course there's a lot more to it, and no system in place today
functions in its pure form. We have some elements of distributism
in the United States in the form of anti-trust laws. Still, I'd
prefer more.

Capitalism has no soul, no morality. Distributism shares the
morality of the community its attached to. I like that.

[0] Distributism on Gopherpedia
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Distributism
  </pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
