<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Nanowrimo 2019</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191031-nanowrimo-2019/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
NaNoWriMo 2019
October 31st, 2019
----------------------------------------

This year I'm going to participate in my own way in NaNoWriMo [0].
I will not be attempting a whole novel or even their on-pace daily
word count. It's not for me, though I wish I were that prolific.
No, instead I will be working on finishing some things. 

[0] NaNoWriMo
    https://www.nanowrimo.org/

First up: Emergence [1]

This is a speculative fiction about the birth of an AI that
I began a while back. I enjoyed some good progress on it and have
been satisfied reading back and what came out (rare). Sadly, it
fell off my priority list and has been sitting there begging for
some love.

Since this is only a short story, it's not the same level of
investment required as a whole novel. I've already got some good
development in place and notes on where I want it to go. Time to
finish it!

[1] Emergence
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/emergence

Next: Trobairitz [2]

Over on Cosmic Voyage [3] I have a new "ship" in planning. This
one is actually an interstellar group of women storytellers who
are hired to share the stories from various cultures. The format
for it will be very different than we've seen so far on Cosmic in
that each post is a complete, self-contained story.

The first story that will be published is related to the Oleander
[4] storyline, and shows a bit of the aftermath of that mission.
I hope to have that first post done in November as well.

[2] Trobairitz
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/ships/Trobairitz
[3] Cosmic Voyage
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/
[4] Oleander
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/ships/Oleander

Finally: Melchizedek [5]

If you're following along in my main Cosmic Voyage storyline
you'll know that something pretty weird just went down. As excited
as I am to explore that, there's a bit of a time delay involved.
So instead I need to switch my focus back to the other crew
sitting on the planets around Beta Hydri. It's always a joy to
write Stephanie Janssen, so she'll probably get another log next,
but there's also an ignored plotline I need to chip away at on
planet 4 with Hildar Simms. The poor guy has spent 90 days in
quarantine! Now that he's out, fun gets to begin.

[5] Melchizedek
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/ships/Melchizedek

I don't know that I'll get the to all this before the month ends,
though. We have our first visitors coming around the 20th. They'll
be staying with us until December, so I only get about 2/3rds of
the month to write. I hope it's enough to finish Emergence at the
very least. That's the minimum bar I want to set for myself.

- - - - -

So what about you? Are any of you planning on doing anything
special for NaNoWriMo? Anyone actively following Melchizedek? Have
anything you're dying to read more about?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Living As An Rpg Textbooks</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190928-living-as-an-rpg-textbooks/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Living as an RPG - Textbooks
September 28th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I think about my own life in terms of roleplaying games. I'm not
alone in this. I bet some of you reading do the same thing. When
I learn a new skill, I am totally thinking about it being added to
my character sheet as I draw a 1 in a little column. The skills
I choose to collect are probably a little skewed toward things
that are more useful in a fantasy adventure than in real life, but
that's not so bad. I once helped a friend get back into their
house when they locked themselves out, so who says lockpicking
isn't practical!

It's not just skills, though. I travel and move through life ready
to pounce on the newest quest that comes along. "Quests aren't
real," you say? Screw that jazz. You're just not looking hard
enough. When a ridiculous opportunity arises and you say yes,
BAM!, you're on a quest. Max out that XP and level up, my dudes.

For those of you who aren't quite ready to up-and-move to another
country, or join the military on a lark, or enter religious life,
or go live on a boat in the middle of a lake, or whatever, you can
still power-level by using some of the sweet loot available to you
at your local library. That's right, I'm talking about textbooks.

Simply read these magic tomes from the start to the end to add
a skill rank in whatever subject you desire. That's it! And it's
free! Maybe the library doesn't carry the subject you want and the
latest volume is like $7,000 at the campus bookstore... so get an
old version online for pennies. You think the information in Intro
to Physics has changed that much in 10 years?

When you're not in school anymore it might not occur to you that
you are still allowed access to textbooks. Just because it wasn't
assigned in a class doesn't mean you can't just pick it up on your
own. It doesn't have to be related to work, or a hobby, or
anything at all. Maybe you always sucked at math in school. Maybe
you can't remember the first thing about Algebra. If you want to
fix that, just get a textbook. Seriously. You're older, wiser, and
know how to apply your brain meats to stuff. Pick it up and start
at the beginning. The book will teach you. That's what it's for.
You won't have a teacher, so instead you'll have to,
I dunno...Google it. Hit up Khan Academy, or wikipedia, or bug
someone on a Tilde server. It's not hard. 

That's the secret of the whole fucking universe, by the way. It's
not that hard. Nothing is. It just takes some time to learn. Start
at the beginning and build up the knowledge.

You want to know how to build rockets? Do it. Like, for real. The
knowledge to do so is free. What else are you working on that's so
important that you can't crack a book in the bathroom for a few
minutes while you do your business?

Learn new skills, level up, take on new quests, be heroes.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Banshee</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190923-banshee/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Banshee
September 23rd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I have an idea for a thing. 

Now, I get a lot of ideas for things and some of them are just too
big for me to do in a reasonable timeframe. Sometimes they're so
big my eyes glaze over at the very thought, so I just tell
everyone else in a blog or phlog and hope someone else does it.
Sometimes the idea is so dumb that I know I'm the only hope and
have to do it myself. Sometimes the timinging is such that it
needs to be done right away or it's not relevant. Sometimes time
doesn't matter and I can just ignore it until I'm bored one night.
In my head this all adds up to a sort of Eisenhower decision
matrix:

                        URGENT               NOT URGENT
               +---------------------------------------------+
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
  Important    |     Do it First     |     Schedule it       |
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
               +---------------------+-----------------------+
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
     Not       |                     |                       |
  Important    |     Delegate it     |     Don't do it       |
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
               |                     |                       |
               +---------------------------------------------+

Except in my case it's more of a "don't do it and feel bad vs
don't do it and don't care".

Well, now I've got an idea for  +-----------------------------+
a project that is too big for   | One of the reasons (not the |
me to do in a weekend, but it   | #1, but up there) that      |
might actually matter to        | I wanted to move to Iceland |
people. Do I just go for it and | was to get away from coding |
drop all the other things I've  | for evil (pharma, mostly)   |
got going? Ugh, probably not,   | and get around to doing     |
but I need to come up with a    | something for the betterment|
real plan if I have any hope of | of people. I haven't found  |
accomplishing the goal.         | a lot of opportunity for    |
                                | that just yet, but I'm      |
But I never said what this is   | getting there.              |
all about, did I?               +-----------------------------+

So what is it?

I want to make an easily deployable system that creates a platform
for publishing text which does so on web, gopher, gemini, and any
other logical systems, is made available on tor, IPFS, zero-web,
and so on (RSS, fediverse?, moar). Basically, I want you to be
able to click "go" and spin up a server that will push your
text-based content out into the wild on all possible channels at
maximum volume. (Hence why this phost is called Banshee)

Why?

Some people have a hard time getting their voice out from behind
firewalls, oppressive regimes, and so on. I want to make it easy
for them to toss something on a raspberry pi, or spin up a virtual
machine, or SOMETHING, and have a way to be heard.

How?

I really don't know. I assume I could look into containers as
a start. There's a heavy devops part of this that's not my
wheel-house. Frankly, I think I'll need help.

I'm going to start up a tildegit org for this, stub out a repo
with a readme and get some conversations going. I think this could
really help people with real problems today. Hopefully it won't
fall off my radar and into the "someday" category.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Av 98 Gopher Proxy On Gopher Black</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190921-av-98-gopher-proxy-on-gopher-black/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
AV-98 gopher proxy on gopher.black
September 21st, 2019
----------------------------------------

Solderpunk had a great response to my VF-1 & AV-98 musings that
you can read here [0].

[0] solderpunk - vf1 av98 and agena
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/vf1-av98-and-agena.txt

In it he shares the secret of an awesome little project, agena,
that is a gopher to gemini proxy. AV-98 is already capable of
using it out of the box, you just need a proxy to point to.

Well, gopher.black is happy to be your Huckleberry. If you use
AV-98 you can try it out now.

    AV-98> set gopher_proxy gopher.black:1965

That's it. I think you can set that in a config file too, if I'm
not mistaken. Then, if you browse past the limits of gemspace and
hit gopher your adventures will just keep going.

I may add this to tilde.black on a different port (since 1965 is
already in use for that server's gemini pages). If you are extra,
ridiculously paranoid you could then torify your AV-98 session and
hit the tilde.black proxy over tor. You're welcome, Mr. Snowden.

Solderpunk has lots of improvements planned for it, so I expect
agena to grow up real fast.

EDIT:

I'm now running agena on tilde.black on port 1966 as well.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Compassion Is Important</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190918-compassion-is-important/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
compassion is important
September 18th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I started this phost intending to say something about RMS [0] and
the various responses I see coming out on the web and in
gopherspace.

[0] Richard Stallman and the Fall of the Clueless Nerd
    https://www.wired.com/story/richard-stallman-and-the-fall-of-the-clueless-nerd/

The thing is, nobody really cares about "yet another opinion".
It's just another example of how comments are useless [1].

[1] "Comments" on Labs blog
    https://labs.tomasino.org/comments/

Instead I think I'll say something about compassion.

Right now people are suffering. Richard Stallman is watching in
shock, outrage, and yes, in pain, as the world he built around
himself falls apart. He is suffering.

Also, the dozens of individuals he has interacted with over the
years who have been the targets of his well-meaning pedantry, of
his priviliged musings, and of his "hot takes", are feeling the
painful effects of those encounters. They feel demeaned,
less-than, or ignored. They feel injured, helpless, outraged, and
yes, in pain. They are suffering.

Epstein's victims have suffered horrendously and suffer still as
the government closes their options for compensation in the wake
of his suicide.

In short, there's a whole lot of pain going around and we'd all be
a little bit better people if we took a moment to consider it
before we launch into our next diatribe. That's not to say you
should shut up. Just try not to forget there's humans on the other
side of your outrage.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Av 98 And Vf 1 Daydream</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190918-av-98-and-vf-1-daydream/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
av-98 and vf-1 daydream
September 18th, 2019
----------------------------------------

This is mostly directed at solderpunk.

I was thinking on AV-98 and VF-1 and how they're so wonderfully
similar. It would be so neat to have a single client that could
browse gopher & gemini protocols seemlessly, and they're kinda the
perfect place to start that thought.

But then I was thinking, "Oh, it would be terrible to start your
journey thinking you're on Gemini and safely using TLS only to
move into Gopher without realizing it and be unprotected." But if
there was a way to differentiate between the modes, sort of like
"battle mode" that visually indicated you were TLS protected, then
things would be better.

I thought about the way I've got my vim status bar configured to
change color when I'm in insert vs normal modes and thought about
that in VF1. One color for "secure" one color for "unsecure".
That'd be neat, right? And what about onion addresses? VF-1 works
quite well over tor, and onion addresses provide end-to-end
encryption. So they could be safely grouped in the "secure" block,
or maybe get a third color.

And that's great for knowing where you are, but not where you're
going. Colorizing links with matching colors would help indicate
your options.

But then again, not everybody like colors, so maybe a prefix on
links or the bar like an "@" or a "!" or something? Or maybe
that's a configuration option.

Anyway, it's a whole bunch of thoughts about somebody elses code
and clients and not my place at all to direct, but I thought I'd
share my thinking in case it inspires anything in you.

Cheers!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Apocrypha Of Cat The Desert</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190906-the-apocrypha-of-cat-the-desert/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
the apocrypha of cat - the desert
September 06th, 2019
----------------------------------------

It is said that before the desert, there was no cat.

It is also said that before cat, there was no desert.

What is known is that when cat left the desert he left a piece of
himself behind and took something different in its place. For
before the desert was a time when cat wore colors, when he sang
karaoke, and most importantly, when he had hair.

The sages speak of a time before myth and before legend when the
world held its breath waiting for a story to begin and set all in
motion. In some traditions this began with a Word, or a song that
can be heard in the Vedas, but the true devotee knows the truth.
The story began with a baby doll crying.

Cat found the doll at the edge of the great expanse stretching
endlessly beyond horizon covered in scrub brush and dust devils.
Low in the sky, the sun was quickly fleeing the heat of the day.
The baby cried once, twice, and a third time as a true harbinger.
In that aged voice-box a clarion rang from the heavens and opened
cat's eyes to Truth, such as needs capitalization and archaic
meter.

He lifted the baby in his arms with tender care and when he looked
down again his shoes had become Doc Martens. He knew these boots
were meant for walking, and that's just what he did as they
carried him deeper into the void. A voice then spoke, and cat knew
it to be his own though it carried no identifiable accent. It had
the cadence of an American and the diction of an Aussie but
scrambled deep in the bowels of bargain-bin Anime and food trucks.
The words themselves sounded like carnies trying their best to
hide their shame on a home visit for Christmas. It was glorious
and held the true power that can only be found in softness.

When cat asked the wind, "Why do I sound like this?" The wind
responded with a susurrus more brutal and jagged than cat's own
voice. In that moment the wind relented knowing that cat had
become as wind himself. And so he drifted forward further into the
desert.

In the desert he found many things. Boredom was chief amongst his
discoveries, though. His ennui bore a hole into the Earth,
hallowing it out and filling it with monsters and myth. It
expanded to the heavens and cast aliens from the sky raining down
across time. It filled our oceans and created Seaquest DSV, which
it is said nobody watched, ever. Finally his boredom brought him
back to the baby with it's soft coos and stuttered cries. In that
beatific countenance he saw the purity of purpose of the crafted
doll and it spoke a second Truth. Forever would he seek such
perfection in all things that crossed his gaze.

But his quest for beauty was at odds with the desert, for the only
beauty of the desert is in its solitude. While cat remained it
could never be itself. To love a thing and to crave for it such
beauty as he did, cat knew he had to leave.

And so, with the pure will of his element, he breathed outward
across the landscape and painted it with all his colors. The pinks
and fuchsias washed across the sky and land. The deep blues of his
eyes filled the sky. But green, which he always had avoided in his
youth, would not come from him. And so the desert would hold its
purity and its beauty for all time while cat was left with only
darkness to shroud himself.

In Doc Martens he walked forth and it is whispered that he left
three secrets behind in the vastness. The first was a fax number
of unknown purpose. The second was a horde of unused raspberry
pis. And the third was the greatest mix tape of all time.

These days cat wanders the Earth in search of beauty and truth
while battling those forces diametrically opposed. Chiefly among
these is Salesforce, which cat has made his personal dragon to
slay.

One day cat may return to the desert and teach it the secrets he
has learned. It is said you can find hints of these secrets buried
underground in the depths of his latest baby, if you know where to
look.

Remember what cat does for us each and every day and give thanks.

cat
    gopher://baud.baby/1/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Busses</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190902-busses/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
busses
September 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I never spent much time on busses growing up. We were a car family
in the suburbs. I either rode my bike places or we drove a car.
Nothing was accessible by foot, and busses didnt run close by.

Upon moving to Reykjavík we decided to go without a car for the
first year to save money and get to know the area more intimately.
It forces me to walk place to place, which is exercise I need, and
it slows the pace of life.

Today I wanted to buy new 3D filament. I've only found one store
that sells it so far, and it took me almost two hours to get there
and make the purchase with all the transfers. A single errand is
a day's outing. 

Even now as I'm on the bus home I feel a strange reaction from
completing a simple task. It reminds me of the pleasures of the
Slow Internet.

My wife went grocery shopping this morning. She walked the 2 km
into town (down a big hill and up another) then shopped and rode
the bus home. She accomplished something more significant than it
would have been by car.

This is all of mind due to the convergence of solderpunk's
ROOPHLOCH and kensanata's thread on creating, or rather the notion
of being productive. It seems to me that the method contributes so
much to the worth that I'm not sure end products are of much use in
determining quality of time spent.

Another case in point, sewing. I routinely did the sewing in our
last home by machine. It gave satisfaction for creation, but since
moving all my needle work has been by hand. It took me an hour to
make finger puppets for my son, but the satisfaction scaled more
rapidly than the increased effort. Some of that may be novelty, but
the same could be said for the machine.

Working manually by choice gives strange fruit.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hammer Time Extended</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190901-hammer-time-extended/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Hammer Time! (extended)
September 01st, 2019
----------------------------------------

We got a few submissions in for the first zine by midnight last
night, but a few people expressed disappointment that they'd
forgotten. So... Let's do a small extension. I'm not going to
start assembly on whatever weird format this thing will take until
next weekend. That means that any stragglers out there have until
Saturday morning GMT to toss your hammer in.

Thanks to everyone who submitted or will. I think this will be
a fun little thing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Lambdalab Email Thoughts</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190827-re-lambdalab-email-thoughts/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: lambdalab - email thoughts
August 27th, 2019
----------------------------------------

The lambda lab wrote [0] about setting up email and asked for some
thoughts on relaying that mail to others around gopherspace. I do
something like that on cosmic.voyage. Namely, I have installed and
enabled postfix to allow for outbound emails only to specific
hosts. [1,2] Since I'm targeting other tildes and not big email
providers I don't need to worry about ending up on spam lists
because of unauthenticated emails to Biggy-G. It also means I can
be lazy about it.

If you're using the host yourself and not sharing it with others
then you don't even need to go that far. Just be selective about
who you email, I guess.

But honestly, setting up DKIM, SPF, etc, isn't too bad these days.
The hard part is dealing with the Notorious-G and others
blacklisting you because they don't care, forcing you to manually
intercede and get clearance. The last time I dealt with that with
them I had to do a bunch of extra crap to figure out how to see
the error message that had some obscure URL they wanted me to
visit. Yuck.

[0] thelambdalab - email thoughts
    gopher://70/0/phlog/2019-08-27-Email-woes.txtthelambdalab.xyz
[1] postfix transport
    ttps://tildegit.org/cosmic/cosmic/src/branch/master/postfix/transport
[2] postfix transport install
    https://tildegit.org/cosmic/cosmic/src/branch/master/Makefile#L55-L62
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
