<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Strike A Pose</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190605-strike-a-pose/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
strike a pose
June 05th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I was reading a twitter thread about the history of linked-list
questions in interviews [0] and a commenter asked how the poster
added a strikethrough to a tweet. He linked to a neat little site
that lets you type a message and generate a unicode strikethrough
version. You can then copy the g̶o̶o̶f̶y̶ ̶s̶h̶e̶n̶a̶n̶i̶g̶a̶n̶s̶ well-formatted
unicode and it should show up for you.

I obviously had to p̶r̶o̶v̶e̶ ̶m̶y̶ ̶n̶e̶r̶d̶i̶n̶e̶s̶s̶ test it out!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Everything Is Evil</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190601-everything-is-evil/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
everything is evil
June 01st, 2019
----------------------------------------

There's a link on tilde.news [0] to a blog post by Nolan Lawson on
"Tech Veganism" [1]. It is, in his summary:

 - a preference for open-source software over proprietary software
 - a suspicion of big tech companies 
 - a high bar for privacy and security

[0] tilde.news
    https://tilde.news
[1] Tech Veganism
    https://nolanlawson.com/2019/05/31/tech-veganism/

My initial reaction was a visceral gagging at the name. I readied
my angriest typing fingers and opened up the lobste.rs style
comments ready to dive in as soon as I consumed this article.
I opened it up, clicked on my Stutter [2] icon and binged it in
a minute.

[2] Stutter
    https://github.com/jamestomasino/stutter

What came out deflated me. He argues some good points early on in
the ways that the behavior of open source purists, security
experts, and digital conspiracy theorists comes across to others
in the same ways as veganism (or crossfit). And, while the article
loses some focus toward the end, it did a decent job of what it
set out to do.

It got me thinking about the whole situation from a different
perspective. For a moment I was running in place like Fred
Flinstone [3] trying to snap an argument into place so I could
fill in that comment box, but eventually I gave up.

[3] Flinstones Running
    https://www.hooktube.com/watch?v=TudMykewh_I

Instead, I imagined the mid-century world with its post-war
optimism and renewed sense of manifest destiny in the United
States. In place of a territorial expansion it was an expansion of
the confidence of indifatigable America and its moral democracy
and powerful innovation. You can feel it in the pride of the
newsreels. The awe capped off with a man standing on the moon.
Progress is perfect. Capitalism and the democratic republic,
combined with the "cowboy" ideal and puritan ethics is the
ultimate way forward. Every child will have a better life than
their parent and the world will grow in all things exponentially.

And so with the invincible self-confidence of a teenage boy on
a half-pipe, America jumped head first. Its power on the world
stage was unequaled militarily and in terms of media. Regulation
and timidity took a back seat and we all went barrelling down the
ramp.

But the mid-century sci-fi authors taught us something else. It
lingered in their messages, only to hit main stream pop culture
years later. We saw the danger of machines, of a runaway state, of
unchecked power, of the masses deciding for all. Literature,
comics, art, they put a spotlight on all aspects of life, not just
the "big dream" of a nation. They help us see the cracks. Even
post-war, things were not perfect by any means, as those who
suffered outrageous oppression (and still do) can attest. They
were not part of that narrative. Unchecked capitalism devours
everything it touches, and so it did to the American economy in
the 70s. The counter-culture of disco, an attempt at glamour in
the squalid realities of life, is art screaming for help.

Here we are three quarters of a century on from that ridiculous
vision of a country who can do no wrong. We see those ideals
spread far, far beyond the US boundaries. The ideas themselves are
an identity for many, disconnected from their birthplace. Even now
we hear the same tripe of trickle-down economics cross the lips of
idiots. Even now we have those who believe in their hearts that
technology will save us from ourselves, as if innovation could
ever outpace hubris.

That was the daydream of thoughts that overtook me from this
little article on tech veganism. And with that lense I look again
and see something different. I don't see angry white men sitting
at their computers bitching about Google spying on them. I see
people who are walking with the rest of the world across
a landscape of ease and luxury, but have stumbled and looked down
and realized what we're crushing under our feet with each step.

Progress isn't perfect.

Everything we do has the infinite consequences that come from
being a part of this insane system of reality, a piece of humanity
as a whole, and a spec of unique life in the midst of a biosphere
hugging an oblique spheriod tumbling through the vacuum of space
like mildew around a shower handle. Everything about us is messy,
gross, and complex. It's hard enough to change something
intentionally for the good without unintended consequences
crushing your idea of progress. And it is so much easier to do
immesurable damage to our world and ourselves with the reckless
abandon of innovation for its own sake (or worse, for money).

I think back to the optimism of the space age and the pulp view of
"good" that it represents. It is not an objective reality, but it
had a presence and an effect at the time. In that way it was
"real". Today our tech advancements promise us pleasure and ease
and luxury at the cost of data, access, information, exposure, and
all the other little things that seem intangible and "no big deal"
in marketing-speak. Many, many people will take that deal. Why
not? Why pay for TV when you can sit through ads and let the
company know what you like. You'll just get better targeted ads.
Where's the harm? Right?

Where the dewey-eyed comic view of the 40s and 50s had eyes on
shiny rockets and travels to the moon, these days we know the
ineffible terror of an all-powerful algorithm, a machine
intelligence, churning numbers about each of us and uncovering
secrets we didn't know we had. We know governments use these for
their own aims, often against the individual. We know hackers can
exploit this. We know that advertisers care about money, not what
we want to see. We know that consumerism will push us toward
a place where we spend every dollar and borrow more to spend
ourselves into debt. We know that the world will enslave us in
a thousand ways to keep power with those in power.

We know, in effect, that the whole world is driven by evil
intentions. Evil in selfishness and in dehumanization and in the
lack of concern for future generations, environment, and the world
in general. 

Everything is evil.

It might not be objective reality, but it has a presence and
effect on everything. In that way it is our "reality". It's almost
enough to make me accept the vegan label without cringing. Almost.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Board Games</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190529-board-games/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
board games
May 29th, 2019
----------------------------------------

cat just dropped a nice phlog [0] about board and card games that
he loves. He wrapped up by asking others what they enjoy.

[0] cat - top 3 board & card games
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20190528.txt

I'll try to keep this to just 3 games as well (with an honorable
mention or two). Unlike cat, who favors the solo or two player
games, I'm a fan of the epic.

1. The Republic of Rome (Avalon Hill)

Avalon Hill is famous for making complex war simulation board
games that take hours to set up, let alone play. It is a company
at the forefront of destroying friendships. Diplomacy is probably
the game responsible for the most gamer-feuds in history, which
makes Republic of Rome remarkable in that it was created
specifically for gamers who thought it too tame. Avalon Hill had
a rating system for complexity in their games and at the time of
its release, RoR was the first game to max it out. These days we
can enjoy a few that have since jumped the shark in terms of
complexity [1].

[1] The Campaign for North Africa
    https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/4815/campaign-north-africa

For all its ridiculous complexity and legal-code rulebook, it's
a brilliantly fun game to tackle with a group of friends. The
players control factions of senators in either the early, middle,
or late republic time periods of Roman history. They struggle
against one another for money, influence, popularity, and military
might until one comes out dominant enough to meet one of several
victory conditions. But they must be careful! If the factions
don't cooperate, Rome itself can fall and everyone loses.

This has been responsible for so many amazing nights of board game
fun I can't sing its praises enough. As I'm gearing up to leave
the country, my friends here planned one last get together to say
farewell and what better way could they have done so than with
a game of RoR.


2. Carcassonne (Hans im Glück)

This tile-laying game is fast (20-30 min), easy-to-learn, and
endlessly amusing. It's a great lunch-time game if you work with
another board game geek. You are building a sprawling city and
trying to occupy the buildings you create to score points when
they are completed. You farm the lands servicing these buildings
and set up monestaries. Oh, and don't forget to build roads! All
of this is done with puzzle-like square tiles that connect and
extend the existing city into a new crazy puzzle of awesome. Score
keeping is a little tricky at first, but it becomes second nature.


3. Once Upon a Time: The Storytelling Card Game (AMIGO)

I adore storytelling and this game really scratches that itch.
It's a card-game with fantastic creatures and items all fantasy
themed. You will find character types like the witch, or princess,
and items like magic swords. You'll also find story elements like
a broken promise. With these building blocks you and your friends
will create an epic tale. Together. Entirely improv style.

The way it works is really cool. Someone starts telling the story.
As they tell their story they will begin to play cards in their
hand that match the story they're telling. If they introduce
a swarthy princess who runs an illegal footwear consortium, then
they may lay down the princess card. If that princess discovers
a way to hide switch blades in the magical Air Jordans she's
creating, then the player may play the magical sword card. But
it's not as simple as just making up gibberish and laying down
your cards!

If the story fails to make sense, contradicts itself, or if the
player pauses too long (as determined by the other players) then
the story moves to the next clockwise player and the previous
storyteller must draw a new card to their hand for having "lost"
the story. There's also a tricky way to steal a story from
a storyteller. If the storyteller mentions a story element that
matches a card in your hand, you can play that card and take over
the story. But you better be ready to start right away or you may
pause too long and lose it.

All of this storytelling and card playing/drawing is leading
toward and ending that's unique to each player. You draw secret
ending cards at the start of the game. Your ending is different
from the other players and you need to steer the narative in the
right direction to get there. If your story ends with "The twins
were cooked in the pie." and the story doesn't even have twins
introduced, you have some catching up to do.

This game requires outgoing friends and benefits from some
moderate drinking. It also has a special place in my game
collection because of our house rule on "who goes first." 

No matter what game we're playing, the choice of who goes first
comes down to the Once Upon a Time deck. Everyone cuts the deck
and takes out one card. Whichever card is "Closest to Unicorn"
goes first. We love the ambiguity and determining whether the
Princess or the Magic Sword is closer to unicorn (magic sword,
obviously). It starts every game out with a smile.


Honorable Mentions:

A. Chess

A classic, and I'm totally addicted, but it didn't feel right to
include in this list.

B. Tabletop RPGs

Pathfinder, D&D, Fate, The Riddle of Steel, Alternity, Fiasco, and
all the rest are the very best games in the world. As much as
I love a board game, a D&D campaign has no equal. I guess I'll
probably have to write more about that soon.


Okay, people... what's your top 3?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Robots Txt</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190524-robots-txt/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
robots.txt
May 24th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I've run a little disallow robots.txt file on this gopher hole for
a while. Now there's been more discussion about its inclusion on
gopher for gopher search engines. This leads me to a little
problem.

My robots.txt file is not meant for gopher crawlers. I created it
because I do not want my site crawled by web crawlers trawling
through proxies to gopher. There's some question as to whether
a robots.txt file is effective in that way (technically the proxy
should have one, not the site itself), but I thought it better
than nothing.

Now I have a dilemma. I would very much like my site to be crawled
by Veronica-2 and other gopher-centric search engines, but I don't
want Google plopping my burrowy-thoughts on the web. What's
a gopher to do?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Not Going Anywhere</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190524-not-going-anywhere/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Not going anywhere
May 24th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Remember like five minutes ago when I said gopher.black was going
offline for a bit? [0] Yeah, I'm full of crap. I spent a couple
hours tonight and migrated everything on that lovely little
raspberry pi that's been in my bedroom up to a sexy little VM on
vultr. Gopher.black is out among the clouds now, and it's not
going anywhere while I move. So, keep your dial tuned to that
gophery station if you dig what you see. More shenanigans are on
their way.

[0] offline for a bit
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190523-offline-for-a-bit
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Offline For A Bit</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190523-offline-for-a-bit/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
offline for a bit
May 23rd, 2019
----------------------------------------

gopher.black will be going offline for a couple months sometime in
early June. We're packing everything up to put on the container to
ship to Iceland. That includes my lovely little pi here. Once we
have a long-term place to live with internet access and a router
that I can set up port forwarding on we'll be back in business.
Until then, my lovely Moku Pona feed will disappear for a bit.

The good news is my high quality phlogging action can still be
found at the 3 mirroring locations I have:

sdf mirror
    gopher://sdf.org/1/user/tomasino
tilde.town mirror
    gopher://tilde.town/1/~tomasino
yourtilde.com mirror
    gopher://yourtilde.com/1/~tomasino

I'm not sure when this site will be back. I'm guessing sometime in
August. You can find me on IRC still during the break. 

þetta reddast!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tea And Shakuhachi</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190510-tea-and-shakuhachi/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
tea and shakuhachi
May 10th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I'm having an accidental Japanese moment. I'm prepping for
a Traveller RPG game that will be starting in 30 minutes and I put
on some Shakuhachi music [0] to test my headset. I also have
a lovely cup of tea next to me. It's peaceful and I thought I'd
share.

[0] Rodrigo Rodriguez - A Winter Night
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wscHJc4NRfo
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Asmr</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190502-asmr/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
ASMR
May 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

                      *scritch scritch*

                        *breathing*

                       *tappy-taps*

can you...


                                                      ...hear me?


                     *gentle mic rubs*

                      *more breathing*


welcome to my
underground...


              A


                                                        S



     M




                                           R


                                                      pure gopher
                                                       experience


i'm your
hhhhhhhhhhhhhost



                          tomasino



                      *crinkling paper*

                  *eating a hard shell taco*

                    *popping bubble wrap*

                    *even more breathing*

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Poppy</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190429-poppy/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Poppy
April 29th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I just learned about youtube personality and musician, Poppy.
Thanks, brendantcc! Her music isn't bad, and the humor she
obviously has with it makes it a pretty fun listen. The track "X"
is my favorite so far with it's genre defying silliness. The rest
of this (apparently 2nd) album seems a bit more like generic club
stuff, but still catchy.

Unfortunately for Poppy, I just grabbed the latest (and last)
Cranberries album "In The End". It fills that Cranberries shaped
hole in my heart perfectly. If you're a fan or still reeling from
the loss of Dolores O'Riordan then have no fear in picking it up.
Solid stuff. I'll be listening to this on repeat for a while.
Maybe Poppy will still be a thing when I dig back out.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Net News On Tilde Black</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190426-net-news-on-tilde-black/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
net news on tilde.black
April 26th, 2019
----------------------------------------

What a great day for net news! Not only is cosmic.voyage,
tilde.team, and news.tildeverse.org (yourtilde.com) peering, but
now tilde.black has been added as well. Tilde Black is my tilde
dedicated to discussions, research and expirementation on the
topics of privacy, anonymity and and security. It's an openbsd
machine, which brought with it a new set of challenges. 

Here's a quick note on special sauce needed for openbsd:

- clone from source as there's no package
- make sure to install a bunch of perl dependencies listed in the
  INSTALL file. It makes heavy use of these during make
- use gmake not make if you can
- configure --without-openssl is a must. The specific requirements
  for TLS don't play nice with libssl
- once you make install the paths will not be /etc/news and
  /var/lib/news but rather /usr/local/news/etc and
  /usr/local/news/db respectively.
- innd won't start automatically. You'll need to change to the
  "news" user and run /usr/local/news/bin/rc.news start.
  I installed sudo to do it since my news user is non-login.
- /usr/local/news/bin is also the path to ctlinnd, which you need
  to install groups and restart the innd process.

Otherwise the setup was pretty much the same as in my previous
post. Very cool.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
