<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Ssh Keys</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190414-ssh-keys/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
ssh keys
April 14th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I'm listening to Go Go Penguin's tiny desk concert [0] right now
while I type this little phlog. You should join me if you can.
They're incredible. 

[0] Go Go Penguin Tiny Desk Concert
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=47XlUL6sRow

Yesterday I got snookered into starting up a new tilde [1] server
called tilde.black. My reasoning was pretty simple: gopher.black
is literally the only .black TLD site I know. I can't have someone
else starting tilde.black! It must be me.

[1] The Tildeverse
    gopher://tildeverse.org/1/;tildeverse.org

So I was going to spin up a general purpose thing in Ubuntu 18.04
cause that's what I know best, but again I let myself get talked
into doing more. So, the machine is running OpenBSD 6.4. It's
going to be focused on privacy, anonymity, and security once
I open her up to new members. And I was close today! I had web
& gopher set up, lets encrypt all configured, tor worked on web,
gopher and even SSH. All was glorious. But then something wonky
happened with rcctl and a forum post I read recommended tossing
some config line in place and restarting the box. Big. Mistake.

So it didn't come back up and now I'm starting over. This time
around though I wanted to give some time and consideration to my
ssh keys and how I'm managing all that gibberish. One thing led to
another and Michael W. Lucas's SSH Mastery book kept slapping me
in the face. The way I had my keys set up was criminally simple
and insecure. I needed to do something before I launch a project
with security in the goals.

So, I bit the bullet and dove in to posts on ssh-agent and using
gpg-agent to interface with ssh and a host of other things. I can
now say with the confidence of a person who skimmed web pages for
an hour that all that shit needs some work. In fact, I hope it's
something the community on tilde.black will do eventually. There
should be simple guides for new people on these topics. There
should be examples, recommendations, watch-outs, and more. Instead
there's aging stack-exchange posts with scripts that throw errors
in modern ssh-agent, hordes of contradictory blog posts, and
worse. This is fundamental stuff for terminal work, guys! We can
do better. The knowledge is in our circle, lets share it, okay?

In the meantime I did what I always do. I said "eff it, I'll roll
my own solution with a shell script". And I did! You can see it
over here [2] if you want. Here's the gist:

  1) Every service gets its own ssh key. Period. 
  2) Every ssh key gets a password. 
  3) These passwords are not all the same thing. 
  4) Simple script to enable/disable the keys when I need them
     without having to memorize all the passwords.

[2] lssh
    https://github.com/jamestomasino/dotfiles/blob/master/bin/lssh

What I wrote is a wrapper around Lastpass, the password manager
I use. Lastpass has a cli tool called lpass which is great.
I added entries in Lastpass for each of my ssh keys' passwords,
placed them into a sync folder using Spideroak (my preferred
secure sync solution) and made an easy shell wrapper to activate
whichever one I need. The activated key goes into ssh-agent. I can
easily clear ssh-agent with ssh-add -D, so that didn't need any
special wrapping (though I may add a quick switch to my script
anyway for that purpose). It's all very basic stuff, again, but it
works well and brings me closer to "safe" for my threat level.

I'd like to clean the script up more and put some bells & whistles
on it, but that will come with time.

Next week it's back to the grindstone at work, but after Friday
I have a week off. My mother-in-law is in town and there's some
things I really need to focus on for the move, though, so this
break probably won't mean great investments of time into tildes or
even writing on Cosmic Voyage. There's a couple more months of
this ahead, and then craziness once we arrive in Iceland.
Hopefully I'll be slowing down a notch or two mid-August. :)
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Phlog Listing Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190411-phlog-listing-updates/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
phlog listing updates
April 11th, 2019
----------------------------------------

It looks like tilde.town recently updated gophernicus, which is
awesome. Many of the servers out there running gophernicus leave
the bottom footer active for their users, which shows the current
gophernicus version that's running.

In my /etc/default/gophernicus I like to disable headers, footers
and the status page hidden at /server-status with the -nt -nh -nf
flags, like so:

OPTIONS="-o UTF-8 -nt -nh -nf -T 7070"

Part of my reasoning is aesthetic. I don't need to show extra crud
on gopher. Part of my reason is security. Not knowing which server
I'm running may make attacks on it more difficult. Not seeing IP
addresses of users engaged with my system helps them stay
anonymous (server-status related). And part of my reasoning is so
I don't accidentally trip up aggregators.

When you upgrade gophernicus and that version in the footer
changes, every aggregator out there suddenly thinks you made an
update to your phlog. This happens routinely on SDF and suddenly
every SDF member tracked on my moku-pona [0] sorts to the top of
the list. Today that happened for our tilde.town users.

Is it a big deal? Oh definitely not. Am I recommending others
running gophernicus use those switches? It's totally up to them
and I won't harp on the issue. I just want people to be aware that
it's a thing. I suspect many would choose to add the flags if they
knew about the situation, but I won't hold it against you if you
disagree, or simply don't care. Gopher is whatever the hell you
want to make it.

Phlog Roll
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlogs

- - - - - - - - - 

Speaking of gopher being whatever the hell you want to make it,
I was surprised to see Ze Libertine Gamer post recently that he
may be deleting his phlog [1]. That's a real shock, to be honest.
He's got some great content that goes back years. I wonder what
sort of things might lead someone to deleting a phlog but not the
entire gopher hole and I'm at a loss. I won't speculate here, but
I will say to ZLG, I really hope you keep it around, even if you
don't update very often. You've got some useful information you've
shared and have been a big part of the community. I'd certainly
miss your contributions.

ZLG - 2019-04-10
    gopher://zlg.space/0/phlog/2019-04-10_1813.txt

- - - - - - - - - 

To zcrayfish:

I agree. WebP does indeed suck. [2] Stop trying to make "fetch"
a thing, Google. Their sleasy method of inserting "switch to
modern image formats" into website performance checkers is dirty
and unwelcome. I don't like blackhat UI and I don't appreciate
their "disruptions".

zcrayfish - WebP Sucks
    gopher://gopher.zcrayfish.soy/1/phlog/20190410-webp-sucks

- - - - - - - - - 

Thanks to all of you who answered my silly three questions. I got
a lot of great movies to add to the playlist and I've been jamming
to your songs all week.

Keep gopherin' everyone!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Opening Gopher Links From Firefox In Lynx</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190411-opening-gopher-links-from-firefox-in-lynx/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
opening gopher links from firefox in lynx
April 11th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I was working on a goal of adding a new protocol handler to
Firefox that would open gopher:// links in lynx. I think it's
doable based on my research, but I'm not quite able to get it
working. First of all, you can expose a protocol to request a new
handler when invoked by adding a config item to Firefox via the
about:config screen.

network.protocol-handler.expose.gopher

Add that entry as a boolean, and set it to false. Now the next
time you click on a gopher link it will prompt you for the app to
use. If you have a standalone gopher app with gui support, point
at that and you're done! YAY!

If you're like me and want it to launch a terminal window, start
lynx, and browse to that gopher hole, well... I don't quite have
the solve just yet. I found three potential ways to do it so far,
but none is actually working.

1. Point to a shell script that launches a terminal window running
   lynx, and forward along the parameter. I created a bash script
   that launched gnome-terminal and passed along the startup
   script as lynx. Sounded good in theory, and if I invoke it from
   the terminal myself it does indeed launch a new term running
   lynx. That's cool, but Firefox seems to do nothing when it acts
   as a handler. Damn.

2. Define a new shell app like described in this webpage [0]
[0] Firefox enable starting of scripts
    https://www.bitkistl.com/2015/04/firefox-enable-starting-of-scripts-and.html

3. Try to make a lynx.desktop file that will launch the lynx
   browser. Here's mine:

   [Desktop Entry]
   Name=Lynx
   Comment=Terminal Browser
   Terminal=true
   Type=Application
   Exec=lynx %U
   Categories=Application;Network;

   That totally works once you trust it if you click on the app.
   But it does jack shit when you try to use it as a Firefox
   protocol handler. Ugh.

Guys, I feel like I'm so damn close. Who wants to be my hero and
swoop in and save the day. Gopher handlers will make my life 3%
better overnight. Don't you want to be a part of that?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fun Questions</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190330-fun-questions/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fun Questions
March 30th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I'm in a fun mood, so let's do something fun!

christyotwisty had a post on circumlunar not too long ago asking
users a bunch of reading questions. I'd link to it, but I can't
seem to find the phlog entry. Regardless, it was really fun and
got a lot of gopherspace engagement. I miss gopherspace
engagement! I want more. So, this is my blatant attempt to fish
interaction out of you all.

Who among you likes movies? How about music? Any readers? Good!
I was thinking of a nice, difficult challenge to throw your way.

1. Name one film that everyone should see at least once.
2. Name one book everyone should read at least TWICE.
3. Name one song everyone should listen to at least once a year.

Why those rules? Cause clickbait, baby!

Here's mine with no context:

1. Mary Poppins
2. Dune
3. Harry Chapin - Cat's in the Cradle
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Spam Files Central Intellegence Agency</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190317-the-spam-files-central-intellegence-agency/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Spam Files - Central Intellegence Agency
March 17th, 2019
----------------------------------------

This is a really interesting new spam/blackmail attempt that I
haven't seen before. I'm not sure exactly how it expects to be
effective being that it requires the individual to sort-of admit
to distribution and storage of child pornography. Hmmm...

Well, here it is, with only the email targeted redacted.

- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -

Case #47823596

Distribution and storage of pornographic electronic materials
involving underage children.

My name is Sharika Snell and I am a technical collection officer
working for Central Intelligence Agency.

It has come to my attention that your personal details including
your email address (<REDACTED>) are listed in case #47823596.

The following details are listed in the document's attachment:

    Your personal details,
    Home address,
    Work address,
    List of relatives and their contact information.

Case #47823596 is part of a large international operation set to
arrest more than 2000 individuals suspected of paedophilia in 27
countries.

The data which could be used to acquire your personal information:

    Your ISP web browsing history,
    DNS queries history and connection logs,
    Deep web .onion browsing and/or connection sharing,
    Online chat-room logs,
    Social media activity log.

The first arrests are scheduled for April 8, 2019.

Why am I contacting you ?

I read the documentation and I know you are a wealthy person who
may be concerned about reputation.

I am one of several people who have access to those documents and
I have enough security clearance to amend and remove your details
from this case. Here is my proposition.

Transfer exactly $10,000 USD (ten thousand dollars - about 2.5
BTC) through Bitcoin network to this special bitcoin address:

3CwcSdb9siP13NYpJ2Eck3dAfTAy3JCW1k

You can transfer funds with online bitcoin exchanges such as
Coinbase, Bitstamp or Coinmama. The deadline is March 27, 2019 (I
need few days to access and edit the files).

Upon confirming your transfer I will take care of all the files
linked to you and you can rest assured no one will bother you.

Please do not contact me. I will contact you and confirm only when
I see the valid transfer.

Regards,

Sharika Snell

Technical Collection Officer

Directorate of Science and Technology

Central Intelligence Agency
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tilde Tel</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190302-tilde-tel/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
tilde.tel
March 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

cat (cat is excitement)
ooh, cat (cat is adventure)
oooh (glamour and glitter, babies and phones)

cat has created something truly outrageous
truly, truly, truly outrageous. 
Whoa, cat! tilde.tel's contagious (outrageous)
cat is his name, no one else is the same
cat is his name

      But we're the pubnix
      Our tilde's better
      We are the pubnix, the PUBNIX
      And we're gonna get 'em

CAT (CAT!), tilde.tel's contagious (outrageous)
cat is his name, no one else is the same
CAT IS HIS NAME!!!!

                                    ,---,  
                                 ,`--.' |  
                          ___    |   :  :  
                        ,--.'|_  '   '  ;  
                        |  | :,' |   |  |  
                        :  : ' : '   :  ;  
   ,---.     ,--.--.  .;__,'  /  |   |  '  
  /     \   /       \ |  |   |   '   :  |  
 /    / '  .--.  .-. |:__,'| :   ;   |  ;  
.    ' /    \__\/: . .  '  : |__ `---'. |  
'   ; :__   ," .--.; |  |  | '.'| `--..`;  
'   | '.'| /  /  ,.  |  ;  :    ;.--,_     
|   :    :;  :   .'   \ |  ,   / |    |`.  
 \   \  / |  ,     .-./  ---`-'  `-- -`, ; 
  `----'   `--`---'                '---`"

cat's tilde.tel
    gopher://tilde.tel/1/
sing-a-long
    http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DiXN5_KO-Ks
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ada</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190302-ada/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
ada
March 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I must be 30% magpie or something because I can't steer clear of
shiny new things no matter how hard I try. In this case, the shiny
"new" thing isn't so new at all, but is a programming language
from 1980 (when I was born). Ada [0] is a brilliant language. It's
incredibly simple, syntactically, but also extremely powerful. It
makes conscious decisions to forgo speed and brevity in exchange
for safety and clarity. It is cautious where other languages are
bold.

Here's a "hello, world" example:

with Ada.Text_IO;
procedure Hello is
  use Ada.Text_IO;
begin
  Put_Line("Hello, World!");
end Hello;

Everything is spelled out. Every instruction ends with
a semicolon, everything is case insensitive, variables must be
declared between the "is" and "begin" of a procedure. Every
beginning has an explicit end, which is labeled. It's so
ridiculously cautious!

I told ~ben the other day that it's the Tigran Petrosian [1] of
programming languages. The whole mentality is so neat to me.

There's a lot of languages out there and I don't need to learn
this one. While it's true that I haven't kept up with any
systems-programming languages it's not really a gap in my
knowledge. It's just that I have no need of them since I don't do
that type of work. So why learn something that's best suited to
massive government builds? Cause FUCK YOU, I wanna!

Look forward to seeing a bunch of shell work done in Ada in the
near future. I was going to make Cosmic Voyage's web generation
script in python instead of continuing to grow the massive /bin/sh
script, but maybe I'll tackle it in Ada instead.

Has anyone out there ever used it for web programming before? That
tickles me pink!

Anywho, any of you know and use Ada? I learned the basics in
college but have never done anything worth a damn in it. I found
a bunch of resources online including a standards site with the
most Orwellian name ever: Ada Conformity Assessment Authority [2].
Hah! So badass. They're serious about following conventions with
it, which really makes sense for the applications it serves. PEP8
is similar for python. If you feel like diving in with me, here's
a link to a crash-course in the form of a ~40pg PDF [3]. I'm going
to store my practice programs and notes in a git repo [4].

Now, lets see if I can do this without cutting into my Icelandic
practice, or my writing on this phlog, or on Cosmic Voyage, or my
preparations for the upcoming move, or planning my wife's 50th
birthday party (SEEEECRET) or any of the other things that are
actually important which I should be focusing on instead.

- xoxo, magpie

[0] Ada (programming language)
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Ada (programming language)
[1] Tigran Petrosian
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Tigran Petrosian
[2] Ada 2012 Language Reference Manual
    http://www.ada-auth.org/standards/ada12.html
[3] Ada Crash Course
    http://www.pchapin.org/VTC/TutorialAda/AdaCrash.pdf
[4] tomasino's ada practice repo
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/ada-practice
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Cdmnky Crazy Bugs</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190219-re-cdmnky-crazy-bugs/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: cdmnky - crazy bugs
February 19th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Here's a couple techniques I've learned over the years to punch
those sassy bugs that just won't go away square in the face-hole.

1. Explain that part of the program bit by bit to someone
   unfamiliar with it. It can be someone else in your class, or on
   your team, or just someone you know. They don't need to be
   coders. Just explain to them the logic of what you're doing and
   walk them through that part out loud.

   Often this will reveal your mistake sideways. You'll probably
   catch yourself just before you say the next part out loud as
   you unconsciously see the disconnect between what you expected
   to see and what's there. It's frustrating that it works, but it
   does. 

   Don't let a full hour go by debugging a single issue without
   trying this.

2. Delete it and rewrite it.

   No, shut-up. Just do it. I don't care that it SHOULD work.
   I don't care that you're just going to type it again exactly
   like the first time. Do it. Right, effing, now.

   Does it work? Oh hells yes. Will it make you angry when it
   does? Fuck yes.

   Don't let half a day go by debugging a single issue without
   trying this.

3. Try to solve something else.

   Take a break and work on a different thing if you can. Put it
   out of your brain. Give a day to another project or subject or
   call in sick with the butt-flu. Get some distance.

   It's not as reliable a fix as the first two, but it can do the
   trick. This is great if your issues is on a side-project or
   hobby that's not under a pressing deadline. Go wind surfing, or
   try to research different types of furry sub-culture, or
   binge-watch the old MTV cartoon "Clone High" so I can make
   jokes that people will get.

Those are my big 3. Maybe some others out there have
recommendations for you as well?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On The Separation Of Artists From Their Art</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190218-on-the-separation-of-artists-from-their-art/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
On the separation of artists from their art
February 18th, 2019
----------------------------------------

A stray boost on Mastodon got me thinking about the value of works
by horrible people. Do we damn the works, the art, the music, the
films once we discover something damning about the creator which?
Do you separate the art from the artist and think of each as
distinct?

I generally try for separation and I'll explain why. For me it
comes down to four things:

 - Ownership of ideas
 - Compassion
 - Outrage
 - Pragmatism

The most complex idea floating around in my head has to do with
the idea of ownership of artistic works. Does an artist own their
creation? While one might quickly argue in the affirmative, that
is owing to a legal point of view. Ownership has a cognitive
influence on our relationship to ideas which goes beyond the
courts and governments and fits more squarely into cultural mores
and moral frameworks. How you react to someone else's pen might
vary wildly depending on your cultural upbringing, for instance.
Where are lines drawn? How firm are they? Is there a gray area?

Lets take a specific example of a disgraced artist and his body of
work: Bill Cosby and the Cosby Show. Given the vague nature of
ownership, it's easy to attribute something of that sort here.
Bill Cosby was the star of the Cosby Show, certainly, and while he
might now own the rights to it, he was fundamental in its
creation. Great!

But there's more to it. Hundreds and thousands of other people
contributed to the show as well. Just considering actors alone,
can we really dismiss the contributions of the other co-stars?
Some of the children literally spent their own childhoods
dedicated to that art. They have equal legal ownership of the
product, and clearly as much personal investment upon creation.

There's also the ancient idea that art is created for the people.
Even our copyright law and patent protections in the US are
designed to recoup the losses of research and development of the
idea, not to form some perpetual ownership of intellectual
property. That would be ridiculous! Ideas belong to the people!

So where is the line here? Is it gray? Do we grant the ultimate
position to Cosby because his name is on it? Certainly, if we
can't attribute it to him then we can't in good conscience dismiss
the art with the artist. If it's not his, then he has no impact on
it. If we find out that Bill Cosby went to a certain high school,
should we shun it? Should we shut it down? It's irrelevant, right?

It would also be a disservice to those others who were involved.
Do we punish them? It was their art as well.

But now we're approaching my second point: compassion. Let's
assume compassion for possible other artists (who may have
suffered from the disgraced artist!) is a given. Besides that
point is the subject of the artist. This part may not be popular
with everyone, but I think it's important to keep out hope for the
forgiveness of the asshole. This is a Christian ideal and one
I can't always live up to, but I think it's important to aim for.
If an artist is disgraced along with all their works then the
message to them and to everyone is that a horrible thing can
completely define you. Any other good you might have done is wiped
away as a result. What hope is there for redemption in that? What
lesson to bother trying? I try to have compassion for the artist
here by not throwing out their good works with the bad. Let their
reputation be damned. Let them suffer prison time if appropriate,
but don't throw away the good with the bad!

And that brings me to my third idea: outrage! Why the actual fuck
would I give up something I enjoy because the creator was a dick?
Why am I punishing myself for something that asshat did? Fuck
that! The Cosby Show is fucking brilliant and funny as hell. It's
still relevant and touching and a genuine joy. That selfish fucker
can go fuck-off to prison now and suffer for what he did, but he's
not taking Rudy from me.

Oh, and then there's pragmatism. I've been talking about the Cosby
Show up until now, but how about the douche-nozzle that invented
the transistor? Don't know about his brand of awful? [0] I'm not
about to give up using electronics because of some guy whose name
I don't really care to know. His ideas belong to the people. I'm
going to use stuff, watch stuff, listen to stuff, and while I may
on occasion also throw up a finger toward the heavens while doing
so, IMMA be me.

[0] William Shockley
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/William Shockley
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Heavy Breathing</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190130-heavy-breathing/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Heavy Breathing
January 30th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I just played an impromptu mix on tilderadio.org. The theme was
"songs that breath"

Here's the playlist:

Garbage - #1 Crush
Enigma - Sadeness (Part II)
Ciara - Body Party
Julia Michaels - "Pink"
Twista ft Mariah- Carey So Lonely
Britney Spears - Breathe On Me
Lana Del Rey - Burning Desire
Britt Nicole - How We Roll (this one kinda sucked)
Charli XCX - Secret (Shh)
Björk - It's Oh So Quiet
Aaliyah - It's Whatever
Marina and the Diamonds - How to Be a Heartbreaker
Shakira - La Loba
Tinashe - All Hands on Deck
Destiny's Child - Lose My Breath
Taylor Swift - Wildest Dreams
Jessie J - Burnin' Up ft. 2 Chainz
Selena Gomez - Hands To Myself
Beyoncé - Blow
No Doubt - Hella Good
The Cure - Close to me
P!nk feat. Peaches - Oh My God
Michael Jackson - Pretty Young Thing
Enigma - Sadeness: Part i
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
