<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Game Ideas/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180725-game-ideas/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Game ideas
July 25th, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's a new Kickstarter fund going called Your Best Game Ever,
by Monte Cook [0]. He's done a ton of RPG writing in the past,
including the D&D 3rd Edition DM's Guide and about a thousand
others. His most recent work was on Numenera, which is pretty cool
if you haven't checked it out before. This new fund is to create
a book which will help you run a game and a gaming group and get
the most out of the experience. It's not about the rules, but
rather about all the other stuff that's not in the books. Sounds
pretty cool, right?

[0] Kickstarter - Your Best Game Ever
    http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/montecookgames/your-best-game-ever

As I was backing that crowdfunding campaign I started thinking
about my own games that I've run in the past, want to run in the
future and the infinite abyss of lameness that is my time NOT
playing an RPG with friends. Ugh, it's awful!

I want to run a game, but I think I need a new format. My local
crew can't manage to do an in-person game reliably, and it's
really not the same working online. It's too easy for the quiet
folks to stay quiet and the active players dominate. It's too easy
to get lost browsing new skills and spells instead of getting into
the session. It's too easy to do anything other than play.

That's the heart of the experience for me, too. The play. The role
play, in game, in character voices and in their heads; making
decisions that your character would make, not that you would.
I miss that part terribly, even in the games I'm playing now.

So I was thinking about running something different. Screw the
system. Screw all the rules. Screw everything that isn't the
role-playing around a table. When I first started RPGs seriously
it was in a setting like that, with my next door neighbor. We
never bothered to crack a book or worry about skill points or
levels. We let the character explore and become someone new, and
told the story together. I would describe my actions and he would
describe the outcome. Battles weren't about hitpoints. They were
about good tactics and planning.

I also don't want to worry about telling an infinitely open-ended
story. This game is not going to be a richly created world that's
free to explore. It will have a setting that hooks the players
from the start and pulls them along the adventure. They will
change the outcomes, they will change the world, but not by
galavanting off to the next town on a whim. I'm thinking the
setting won't even have another town! I'm thinking of something
otherworldly with a mist of unknown descending upon a remote
hamlet. Adventure is survival in the face of mystery. 

And what fun it will be to create a real mystery, or series of
mysteries, for the characters to figure out and explore. If my
plotting works it will take planning, notes, and active work on
the their part to figure things out in time. "In time for what?"
you ask? Well, that's part of the stakes! In this case, time will
be a major factor in survival, and a major limitation in the
choice of action.

Yes yes... lots of plans coming to me. I'll need to start writing
it all out, mapping out all the ideas, and then find the right
group to explore it with me. Hopefully I can run this one soon.
I really miss role playing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Italian Citizenship/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180721-italian-citizenship/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Italian Citizenship
July 21st, 2018
----------------------------------------

Today I am officially an Italian citizen. I went though an
extremely long process to claim my citizenship via a process
called jure sanguinis. I proved, in essence, that I have always
been an Italian citizen by way of birth since my ancestor who
immegrated had children before becoming naturalized. Thus, his
kids were born as Italians on foreign soil.

My son also has Italian citizenship as a result, and we're going
to file for my wife to get hers via marriage. I'll be getting
a second passport soon, and when the dust settles, we'll be
leaving the United States.

If you read this phlog, you probably already know that our
destination is Iceland, which will allow me residency now since it
is part of the Schengen Agreement, just like Italy. Moving to
Iceland as an American is a giant pain in the butt, but as an
Italian it should be quite simple.

This made my whole day, obviously, but it also helps me out in
some bigger stress areas. I've been stressing about what to do
next in my career. I have an opportunity to potentially move into
a CTO role with a startup, which fascinates me and would challenge
me quite a bit. It would also be an increased investment on my
time, and I already work a lot. The job I'm at now is wearing on
me more and more, and I don't see it as sustainable for very much
longer. The move to Iceland represents a refocusing of priorities
off of work and onto life. I'm planning on taking a significant
pay cut, living more simply, and focusing on the family and
hobbies. Since that timeline is finally "for real", it means that
my current work troubles have an end in sight. That is powerful.

While I finish getting all the papers in order for the family,
we'll also be selling our house and moving into a much smaller
apartment. We'll get rid of most of our things, place most of the
leftovers into storage, and live on what we intend to ship. Once
all that's in place, I'll be quitting my job, heading to Iceland
on my own ahead of the family, and we'll live off the house sale
money until I can find a new job, get us a new apartment, and
arrange to move them over and meet me.

I'm utterly thrilled!

Oh, if any of you reading this are Icelandic, live or know someone
in Iceland, or in any way could help me find something
code-related to do in Iceland to get us settled I'd be extremely
grateful. I run a technology team of web developers, front & back
end. I also act as the digital strategy lead (pharmaceutical
marketing) and head of analytics & reporting. I can code in JS
extremely well, and prefer using vue, but can learn whatever. My
php & python skills are a little rusty, but I can jump back into
that in a heartbeat. Ruby? I guess I could do that too. I'm not
much of a windows development guy, though.

Need a programmer? Need someone to run a dev team? Need an
analyst? I'm also good at balancing stuff on my chin!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hard Things/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180720-hard-things/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Hard things
July 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is just a reminder:

Do the hard thing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Ftp Find/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180720-gopher-ftp-find/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gopher ftp find
July 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

@sparcipx@mastodon.sdf.org found a really nice treasure trove of
gopher goodies on an ftp server [0]. I'm out of the house, so I'm
writing this to remind myself to do some archiving of the content
when I get home.

[0] ftp archive
    ftp://ftp.sunet.se/mirror/archive/ftp.sunet.se/pub/gopher/Unix/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Left/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180717-the-left/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Left
July 17th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I just received the following email on an account I have which
monitors conservative political action. I have similar feelers
into a few different areas so I can keep tabs on things. This one
stood out, especially in light of Trump's recent meeting with
Putin.


----------------------------------------
|   Authorized By Trump Headquarters   |
----------------------------------------

James,

Have you seen the Democrats lately?

They're completely unhinged.

They’re all over this country vowing to go further and further to
the Left. For weeks, they’ve been calling for harassment,
intimidation, even the abolishment of ICE! Now, they’re promising
to block President Trump’s Supreme Court nominee from ever
reaching the bench.

They want to ignore our laws, abuse our people, and obstruct our
agenda by subjecting Judge Kavanaugh to a long, drawn out
confirmation process.

They think their new tactics will chase all “deplorables” into
hiding… but the silent majority is not backing down. We’re getting
together and we’re standing up. We’re knocking on doors and
reaching voters for our National Week of Action to protect our
President and make sure we win big in November.

And we need YOU to join us by going door to door to spread our
message
 
REGISTER TO VOLUNTEER

James, the way I see it, if liberals want to come for our borders,
for our jobs, and OUR Supreme Court, and they’re willing to stop
at nothing to make that happen.

We CAN win for the Silent Majority -- not by stooping down to the
left’s level -- but by volunteering in your neighborhood to turn
out voters and spread our positive message of putting America
FIRST.

Please, join us for the National Week of Action.

Thank you,

Chris Carr
Donald J. Trump for President, Political Director

------------------------------------------------------------------

What struck me most was the blatant use of the Left as an entity
of otherness. Notice that it's the Left coming for OUR borders,
Supreme Court, laws, and jobs. The Left wants to abuse OUR people.
This is an interesting and dangerous shift in rhetoric. It is
essentially calling liberals anti-American and digging deeper the
divide.

In a similar email last month the language used was based on
fighting, shooting, and violence in general. "Strike back!" they
cheer.

This is the stuff that later generations will point to with
disgust and say, "how did they not see it coming?"
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cwondr/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180716-cwondr/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CWONDR
July 16th, 2018
----------------------------------------

yargo writes [0] about a cool Morse/CW project he's working on.
A low-power, pocket-sized CW transceiver for the 430 Mhz band: for
Morse code. I love it! I don't have much interest in getting into
HAM stuff (mainly because I know it would end up being a huge time
sink for me) but I love Morse and I think I could dig something
little and portable like this. If you make it, I'll use one!

[0] yargo - CWONDR, another Morse/CW project
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/yargo/glog/t18414-cwondr.txt

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flashcards/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180714-flashcards/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Flashcards
July 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

User jakob phlogged recently [0] about getting back into flash
cards & spaced repetition. He found a fantastic solution using
emacs as he seems to be slowly adopting the "all things are emacs"
principle. I'm not quite to that extreme with vim, but I do love
me some command line solutions.

[0] jakob - replacing anki with org-drill
    gopher://jakob.space/0/phlog/replacing_anki_with_org_drill/text

Plain text is just simpler. I don't need fancy guis for 99% of my
stuff. Flash cards are definitely in that list. So, what's a man
to do? Obviously the only solution is to roll my own!

I started by searching a bit on the different styles of spaced
repetition (there are many) and quickly settled on the Leitner
System. It's usable by hand, so I should clearly be able to
replicate it with a program, right? It turns out that there's not
really any agreement on the specifics of the system. I watched
several videos on youtube who would almost get there and then say
something that didn't make any sense. The wikipedia page is such
a hot mess I'm not even going to link you there. If you want to
read some train wreck stuff, you'll need to go there on your own.

In the end I settled on the following as my interpretation of
Leitner:

- Flash cards get a front and a back
- Flash cards are sorted into levels based on your proficiency
  with the card
- All cards start at level 1
- Cards move up one level when you successfully identify the back
- Cards return all the way to level 1 if you fail to successfully
  identify the back in time
- Time is important. Sitting there staring at a card and working
  it out is not the same as "getting it right". That is a failure.
- The number of proficiency levels you use isn't important
- The frequency of cards being shown is determined by the level:
  - Cards at level 1 are shown every day
  - Cards at level 2 are shown every other day
  - Cards at level 3 are shown every 3rd day
  - Cards at level 4 are shown every 4th day
  - and so on
- Cards are reviewed only once per session with the exception of
  cards at level 1. They can be reviewed multiple times until they
  move to level 2.

I started putting together these notes yesterday into a README
file intending to build a bourne shell app like I did with burrow.
I was reminded by a coworker that I said I'd build something in
node soon, so I caved and used javascript instead. Yes, I felt
incredibly dirty the whole time. Even worse, it was really, really
fun and easy. Puke.

If you have node installed you can try out my app by running:

  yarn global add flashleit
  or
  npm i -g flashleit

That's right.... Flashleit! Get it? Leitner... Flash Cards...
Huzzah!

When you run the app you can start by adding cards. There's a menu
option for it. Cards creation will launch your $EDITOR. Card
fronts & backs can be multi-line. Ascii art welcome!

You can also mess with some of the settings in the app. Change
some colors, change the maximum proficiency level, or the delay
before the card flip happens. There's more color settings in the
configuration file if you want to go digging. It's usually at:

  ~/.config/config/configstore/flashleit.json

but it may vary on your system. All the data is stored in that one
file, including your cards. If you want to import a list or
generate one, just look at the pattern in there and mess with the
JSON itself. You're big kids.

Source is over on github [1]. If you try it out and have any
recommendations or spot any bugs, leave me an issue there. 

[1] flashleit on github
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/flashleit
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Jynx On Life Segmentation And Happiness/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180711-re-jynx-on-life-segmentation-and-happiness/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: jynx on life segmentation and happiness
July 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

jynx wrote [0] a note about separation of life and employment and
the freedom it's given him. It's been an extremely helpful read
for me and helped me put things back in perspective. I keep
re-reading it.

[0] jynx - On life segmentation and happiness
    gopher://gopher.club/0/users/jynx/phlog/typezero/20180709.post
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Freelance/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180709-freelance/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Freelance
July 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm not sure why I bother with freelance. I mean, I like having
some extra income, but I'm so burnt out from work already, do
I really want more?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shut It Down/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180708-shut-it-down/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
shut it down
July 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Sometimes the little frustrations add up and spill over. I tend to
get very quiet when I'm at my breaking point. I shut down. I walk
away. When I was young I'd walk away in grandiose ways: from
relationships, jobs, responsibility. I've learned how to siphon
off the steam before reaching that point. I meditate, I walk,
I pray. I can roll with it a lot more than when I was a kid.
Still, sometimes it feels like it would be easier to shut it all
down and walk away from my life. It's not a rational thought. My
life is pretty damn good. The frustrations are minor things,
meaningless really. You can't compare lives that way, though. It's
not rational, as I said, and it's not logical.

I'm going to drink a nice glass of gin, read a bit, and go for an
evening walk. Tomorrow will start a busy work-week and I'll be
walking into it already stressed. It's not a good recipe.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
