<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Little Free Library Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190109-little-free-library-part-2/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Little Free Library, part 2
January 09th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I originally wrote part 1 of this build back in October [0] and
I have a few little things to add.

First, I want to call out a major hurdle I'm facing: Captive
Portal browsers don't allow users to download files. It's
a security thing. That's annoying for a library that's designed to
give you ebooks, but it might not be a barrier for your uses.
Someone on Mastodon mentioned making a video based thing, and that
should work just fine entirely in captive portal.

Second, captive portal browsers are way behind the times with
regard to css support. No CSS-Grid here, folks. Sadly I had to
fall back on some older methods to make my page pretty.

Speaking of pages, here's a link to the repository that houses my
web interface to the library [1].

If you're reading this as of the moment of posting then you'll see
that I haven't addressed problem #1 yet. If you're finding this
later in time, hopefully it's all fixed for you. Here's my current
plan of attack:

- Create a very simple captive portal page that advertises the
  little free library and instructs users to open a regular
  browser and navigate to http://littlefreelibrary.local
- The generated library page will be hosted at the root url, not
  the captive-portal location, and will allow full downloads.

This is going to take some testing to get right, but once it's all
squared away I'll update that repo to contain both pages and
deployment scripts.

Finally, I've purchased a solar battery that I'm going to try out.
It's a very basic solar charging battery pack of Amazon that I'm
not going to bother linking. It's likely not the real solution
here since they're notoriously bad at actually charging from the
sun, and when they do they overheat and destroy the battery. But
it will finish my proof of concept, and that's what's important.

Once that arrives, I'll hopefully have time this weekend to give
the project one last push and get it working in the woods.

[0] Little Free Library, Part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-little-free-library-part-1
[1] Little Free Library Web Source
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/littlefreelibrary
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Talkd On Ubuntu</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190102-talkd-on-ubuntu/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
talkd on ubuntu
January 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I need to save these notes somewhere. I just got talkd working on
ubuntu 18.10 and it was quite convoluted. Here's what I did:

- install openbsd-inetd (not inetutils-inetd, it's shit)
- install talkd (not inetutils-talkd, also shit)
- install ytalk (better than talk by a mile)

edit /etc/inetd.conf and add the following:

#:BSD: Shell, login, exec and talk are BSD protocols.
talk   dgram udp wait nobody.tty /usr/sbin/tcpd in.talkd
ntalk  dgram udp wait nobody.tty /usr/sbin/tcpd in.ntalkd 

note the /usr/sbin/tcpd. If talkd added content here for you,
those are probably quite different. Trust tcpd to handle the
connection for you and hand it off to in.talkd and in.ntalkd
afterwards. 

'nobody' will probably need to be added to the tty group. In truth
you should make another dummy user without a login shell named
'talkd' and add THAT user to tty, but this works.

$ sudo usermod -a -G tty nobody

Restart inetd:

$ sudo service openbsd-inetd restart

Now you should be able to use 'talk' on your server, locally at
least.

Ports 517 and 518 are for talkd, so you can open them up in your
firewall and that should be enough to talk to other servers, but
I don't have that piece of the puzzle just yet.

Good luck!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading Questions And Answers</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181230-reading-questions-and-answers/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reading Questions and Answers
December 30th, 2018
----------------------------------------

These questions come from christyotwisty [0]. I'll do my best to
answer them as other's have [1].

What is the first book you remember loving?

  This is a little embarrassing now, since I've grown to discover
  what a horrific little man the author is, but the first book and
  series I grew to love was Vale of the Vole [2], book 10 in the
  Xanth series by Piers Anthony. My dad brought it home one day
  and I gave it a shot. It hooked me quick and sent me back to the
  beginning of the series. I read a bunch of them before
  graduating on to better fantasy books. It put a life-long love
  of the genre into my blood.

What book/series would you like to see adapted to film?

  The Wheel of Time has long been my answer to this. It's epic on
  a scale that many series strive for and can't quite achieve.
  It's part of the central canon of fantasy literature, love it or
  hate it, and it's never been given a fair shot at the screen.
  I would love to see it done well, but fear it as well.
  
  Adaptations no longer belong to the author. They need to
  maximize their medium and be the best they can be in that form.
  This is why Dune is so hard to put on screen. The book is
  philosophy and philosophy makes for terrible films. It causes
  directors to over-use voice-over for internal thoughts. The
  Wheel of Time would make for excellent on-screen action without
  getting too lost in translation. Even so, will a film match the
  story I love or will I be disgusted by the inevitable changes
  that need to be made?

Who are your favourite protagonists?

  I get deep satisfaction from characters that take a beating but
  keep up the snark only to eventually do something epic. Harry
  Dresden pops to mind as an example, as does Nona Grey from the
  Book of the Ancestor series. Even Helen Harper's guilty pleasure
  urban fantasy series "The Lazy Girl's Guide to Magic" has such
  a heroine in Ivy Wilde. Joe Bishop of the Expeditionary Force
  takes his knocks and then starts inter-stellar civil wars. Nancy
  A. Collins' Sonja Blue does it too.

  While they may not share the snark, characters who endure
  endless hardship with positivity, ingenuity, and resolve also
  dig into my heart for all time. The hero of Hatchet and Julie of
  the Wolves did that to me in middle school. And it's why my
  favorite character from any book is still Jane Eyre. I mean...
  the quotes!

     "Do you think I am an automaton? — a machine without feelings?
     and can bear to have my morsel of bread snatched from my
     lips, and my drop of living water dashed from my cup? Do you
     think, because I am poor, obscure, plain, and little, I am
     soulless and heartless? You think wrong! — I have as much
     soul as you — and full as much heart! And if God had gifted
     me with some beauty and much wealth, I should have made it as
     hard for you to leave me, as it is now for me to leave you. I
     am not talking to you now through the medium of custom,
     conventionalities, nor even of mortal flesh: it is my spirit
     that addresses your spirit; just as if both had passed
     through the grave, and we stood at God's feet, equal — as we
     are!"

     "I care for myself. The more solitary, the more friendless,
     the more unsustained I am, the more I will respect myself."

  Damn, son!

Who are your favourite antagonists?

  The Baron Harkonnen in all his forms and genetic memory takes
  it. He is brilliant and disgusting. Hannibal Lecter is delicious
  too. Going old-school, Lady MacBeth was the first villain to
  make me throw a book across a room (honorable mention to Iago).
  Oh, and freakin' Mars itself in the Martian. It threw everything
  it could at our hero, but took a swift sciencey kick to the
  face.

What, so far, is the best book you've read this year?

  The Collapsing Empire (The Interdependency #1) by John Scalzi.
  It's a lovely new sci-fi series that just release book #2. If
  you're into Scalzi's stuff it doesn't disappoint. There's some
  epic stuff, some really nice mysteries, and colorful characters
  gallore. I hope it goes on and on.

Can you list three to five of your favourite authors? 

  Genre greats like Brandon Sanderson, Frank Herbert, Robert
  Jordan, George R.R. Martin, Mary Stewart, and John Scalzi.
  
  Classic literature is dominated by my girl Charlotte Bronte.
  
  Poets like Mary Oliver, Christina Rosetti, and Elizabeth Barrett
  Browning.

Why are they your favourite?

  They create worlds where I can lose myself. They create
  characters who I internalize and who become a part of me. And
  they speak truth to my soul.

What are your least favourite genres to read?

  Romance is a no-go to me. Same with whatever fluffy nonsense you
  call Elin Hilderbrand's stuff. Horror is also not often on the
  list. I don't find it scary, so it's mostly just gross or
  depressing. 

What was the last book you recommended to a friend?

  Sebastien De Castell's "Traitor's Blade", book one of the
  Greatcoats Series. When did I recommend it? Why, right now of
  course. You should pick it up!  

What is your favourite film adaptation of a book?

  The Firm. It stands out as a fantastic example of the film being
  better than the book. It doesn't happen often!

What books have you read the most times?

  Dune, far and away. After that, Jane Eyre.

What fictional world or novel's setting would you like to live in?

  That's such a tricky question. So many of the fantasy worlds
  I read are amazing places, but horribly dangerous. Or they would
  be awesome to live in if I had one of the magic powers. The same
  goes for sci-fi series. If I weren't running out of air on
  a runaway space station, it might be cool!

  I've read a bunch of Star Trek novels, though, so I'm gonna take
  the easy way out and say I'd like to live in the Federation.
  Give me a future of peace where humanity struggles to improve
  itself. (Side note, The Economics of Star Trek is also an
  amazing book. Read that too.)

What are your favourite classic books?

  Oh, I should have looked ahead at this list. Jane Eyre for
  fiction, but I love a lot of others too. The classical reads of
  stoicism, like Epictetus and Aurelius's stuff is special to me.
  So is Summa Theologica, though I admit skimming large portions.
  There's Martin Chuzzlewit and the Iliad, or Introduction to the
  Devout Life. So many great reads.

What is the most recent book you didn't expect to like, yet did?

  The Trumpet of Terror! It's a Choose Your Own Adventure book and
  I picked it to read on my show because the cover looked awful,
  but it turned out to be really well written.

If you could meet one author, living or dead, whom would it be?

  Hmm, probably Frank Herbert. It's not a particular desire of
  mine in general, but I'd like to know from his own mouth where
  he wanted the series to go before his son butchered it.

What authors do you think more people should read?

  Don't be afraid of classics. Most of them have stuck around for
  a reason. :)

[0] Christina's Reading Questions
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~christina/ReadingQuestions.txt
[1] Sloum's Answers
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~sloum/phlog/20181230-12.txt
[2] Vale of the Vole
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Vale of the Vole
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moku Pona Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181226-moku-pona-updates/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Moku Pona updates
December 26th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Thanks to a great deal of help from kensanata, my moku-pona page
now supports phlog feeds. Ulcer is the first one benefiting from
it. Have a look.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolutions</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
resolutions
December 25th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A friend came up with a brilliant way to handle New Year
resolutions when we were in college. He decided that he would
resolve to do something or accomplish something that is definitely
attainable by SOMEONE, just not YOU. It makes for a fun resolution
that's also kinda hard to come up with. Here's a few we've had
over the years:

- This year I will break the sound barrier.
- This year I'll be given the KEY to the CITY!
- This year I'm going to kiss the Queen of England.

With that in mind, I'd like to let you all know that 2019 is going
to be an epic year for me. How epic, you ask? Well...

This year, I'm going to be impeached.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Christmas Break</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181223-christmas-break/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Christmas break
December 23rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was leaning against the counter in my kitchen while typing in
IRC and then started a coughingn fit. Why am I coughing,
I wondered as I rubbed at the bruise forming on my solar plexus.
Derp.

I'm now sitting comfortably in the stool that was right beside me.
I am very smart. :/

Anywho, I'm on break for Christmas this week and I hope to get
a few fun side-things accomplished. For one, I'd like to write at
least one substantial update for each of my ships in cosmic [0].
My original ship, Melchizedek, is in trouble with their botany
systems, while Starbloom may be going to war. My two newest ships
are Oleander, which is the story of a suicide mission sending
their final messages before activation, and Melvin P Feltersnatch,
a silly story with bad physics and quite a bit of nonsense.

[0] Cosmic Voyage
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/

I also dusted off a project idea I had called Ways. It's intended
to be an open-source text-adventure engine and expandable world.
Right now it's very much in "dream up the stuff" phase. I'm not
bothering to even choose a programming language yet. I want to get
all the concepts down in a README so I can go at it later for
execution. This week should give me a decent start on that.

In other news, Christmas is nearly upon us! I've been teaching my
son about the Icelandic Yule Lads and Yule Cat and he's loving it.
We've been leaving his shoe in the window each night and reading
up on each of the lads. It's so cute.

OMG, I haven't written since we sold the house! Um, yeah. We sold
our house on the 10th of December. I'm renting a 2br apartment
about a mile away from the house until the end of June when we
intend to make the move to Iceland. I've given myself a break from
any planning on that front until the new year, too. Self care?

We had a 5 bedroom house with a massive basement and detached
garage. Needless to say, we downsized quite a bit and are
continuing to do so. My wife found an awesome charity that takes
home goods and furniture for kids aging out of the foster system
and moving out on their own. Most of the house goods went to them.
My son gave up 2/3rds of his toys to Goodwill. I downsized my
computers to a single laptop (which I'm replacing next Friday with
a new one from System 76). We have a storage unit that is 10x20
and needs to get reduced down to 5x10 before June. The stuff
remaining will go into long-term storage in Charlotte near my
wife's family. The stuff in the apartment will get packed up and
shipped to Iceland. Somehow we'll make it all work.

---

There's been so many awesome discussions kicking around in
gopherspace that I haven't been engaging with. Ugh, now I want to
go back and write you all individual responses here. Instead, just
know that I'm reading everything in great detail, from the stuff
on the growing Zaibatsu adventure to the music generation scripts
to the OTHER burrow to home-grown RPGs. You are all amazing people
who keep me entertained and inspired. Especially you, Melton. Your
life is incredible. Never stop writing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Tfurrows Bible Translations</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181208-re-tfurrows-bible-translations/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: tfurrows - bible translations
December 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

tfurrows wrote [0] about picking up a copy of the English Standard
Version (ESV) Bible, a modern language translation by Crossway. It
just so happens that the ESV is my personal favorite translation
for casual bible reading. I like it so much, in fact, that
I sought out permission from Crossway to post the full contents of
the ESV on gopher.black. You can find it over here [1]!

[0] tfurrows - bible translations
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~tfurrows/phlog/2018-12-05_bibleTranslations.txt
[1] ESV Bible
    gopher://gopher.black/1/bible

I love the New American Standard Version (NASV) as well, as it's
the one used in the Catholic mass in the US and it's a very good
literal translation. For study I bounce around between versions,
especially since my Greek and Hebrew aren't particularly strong
language skills. I need to review alternate translations to find
new ways at the text.

Anyway, tfurrows, I hope you enjoy the ESV. There's a fantastic
set of commentaries that goes with it which you can find online
for free. Or, if you're just reading through for fun, you are
welcome to use gopher!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Jynx So Much Cool Stuff Going On</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181128-re-jynx-so-much-cool-stuff-going-on/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: jynx - so much cool stuff going on
November 28th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Jynx recently wrote [0] about gopher decentralization (and gave me
a cool shoutout). He also drew attention to federation tools
between the tildeverse and other micro-communities like
circumlunar. I love it and agree whole-heartedly. 

Cosmic Voyage is hosting an ircd that is part of the
irc.tilde.chat round-robin. I would love to figure out a way to
make my local mail on that box play nicely with tilde's, but not
open up wide to the universe. bbj style message boards that can
federate would be great too, like FidoNet. Bring on the cool
stuff, people.

Oh, and jynx, please do set up something in the cosmic.voyage
vein, even if it's via git. We need more!!! One of the folks that
sits in tilde IRC mentioned to me this morning that he plans on
making a D&D/Fantasy style version of cosmic. I would LOVE to see
that, and likely join. I'm imagining it as stories being told
"back at the inn". How cool.

So yes, gopherspace is growing and exploding with badassery.
Circumlunar phlogs are so popular. Maybe we can get tilde.team and
tilde.town communities thinking a little more gophery and get
their vast numbers phlogging too. Let's all keep on with
solderpunk's call to arms [1]: Hey you! Host something!

jynx - so much cool stuff going on
    gopher://1436.ninja/0/Phlog/20181128.post
solderpunk - hey you host something
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/hey-you-host-something.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Easy Dated Files For Sorting</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181127-easy-dated-files-for-sorting/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Easy dated files for sorting
November 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

For those of you out there using gophernicus and forcing
yourselves to write your posts with cumbersome file-name prefixes
for proper sorting, let me help you out.

Gophernicus allows you to execute in-line scripts in your
gophermaps. That means you can do something like this:

=ls -1r | grep -v 'gophermap' | awk '{printf "0%s\t%s\n", $1, $1}'

It will grab all the files in your directory, flip the order, and
print them out into a pretty gophermap for you. Tada! Just drop
files in place and name them with the date, YYYY-MM-DD. You'll
sort just fine.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cosmic Voyage</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181124-cosmic-voyage/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cosmic.voyage
November 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Cosmic Voyage is live!

Cosmic Voyage on Gopher
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/
Cosmic Voyage on the Web
    http://cosmic.voyage
Cosmic Voyage RSS Feed
    http://cosmic.voyage/rss.xml

If you don't know what I'm talking about, look here:
Space Gopher, Revisited
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181119-space-gopher-revisited

If you'd like to join, send an email to:

        tomasino [at] lavabit [dot] com

Be sure to include the following:

        1. Your desired username - we don't use it in the story
           itself, but there may be some uses on the system for
           local mail and logging in.

        2. Your first ship/colony/outpost name - This is what
           you'll be using to write the story content. You can
           have as many ships as you'd like. Just send me a note
           to request more.

        3. A public SSH key - We use key-based logins to ssh, not
           passwords. Shoot me the contents of the key or a link
           to it.

Once you sign up you'll receive an email detailing some basic
operations on the server. For instance, to author a message in the
story you'll need to be able to do two things:

        1. Create & edit text files
        2. Run the 'log' command and follow the prompts

No gopher expertise is needed!

If you have more questions, I'm pretty easy to find. For
cosmic.voyage in particular I sit in the #cosmic channel on
irc.tilde.chat. Information on how to connect to that server here:
tilde.chat
    http://tilde.chat/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
