<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>The Games We Play</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180501-the-games-we-play/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The games we play
May 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's been a lot of people talking recently about games they're
playing, whether on the computer, board game, or pencil-based
RPGs. It's been really inspiring.

I love RPGs so much, and I'm happy that I've got a monthly game
going with a local crew. We're playing online with Discord and
Roll20.net and it's... fair. I prefer no electronics involved in
my table-top, and everyone around the same table. Still, I'll take
what I can get.

At work I spent a little bit of my team-building budget to buy
a couple board games. Charterstone, a fancy new legacy game, and
a casual game called Lattice are the first purchases. I'll report
back on how they work soon.

I've also been thinking about other games I play or have played
with my friends over the years. Some are easily categorized, like
the D&D campaigns I've run or played in. Others are hard to pin
down, like the De Profundis writing-game I've got here on
gopher.black [0].

[0] De Profundis
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/deprofundis

This is a game of sorts, but it's also collaborative writing. It
started with the first letter when I wrote it in an email to my
friend Dan. I didn't give much explanation other than, "you get to
write from the other side and move the story along." We don't
communicate about our plans for each letter and we can introduce
characters as we see fit. We meticulously research historical
locations and events to prepare each one, and try to keep to the
style of the time as best as we're able. Dan's got the next letter
coming my way soon and I'm thrilled.

My game experience isn't all table-top or computer based, of
course. When I was a teen in Boy Scouts we did a lot of
night-gaming. Usually it was something akin to capture the flag,
or a moderately violent hide-and-seek variant we called Man Hunt.
My favorite thing was what I called "Flee-running". If you're
familiar with Free Running or Parkour, it's more in line with the
latter. It wasn't about flourishes, but rather about getting from
point A to point B as efficiently as possible. The only difference
was, you were being chased. It's a combination of tag & parkour
usually played deep in the woods, often in the dark. It's skill
based only so much as it takes a lot of skill not to stop running
when you take a branch to the face in the middle of the night. It
was so thrilling, though. I've lept from cabin roofs, tarzan'd
across creeks, and jumped through windows. So dangerous, and so
fun.

We also had really stupid high school games. There's one that
I picked up on in college that started from a friend's high school
time. It's really simple, if someone says the word "bogwan" you
have to freeze exactly where you are in the position you're in for
thirty seconds. If it's dangerous or whatever, then you don't...
but once you're clear of danger you have to freeze. It was mostly
used to emphasize some stupid expression you were making at the
time. Make some embarrasing face and you're bound to be bogwan'd.
It's still active and on rare occasion I'll get a bogwan text from
that crew.

There's so many other stupid games from that time. A lot of them
involve getting punched in the balls, for some reason. High school
again, I guess.

Board games are coming back into my life again which is great.
I've got one RPG going and will likely run a Numenera game
sometime in the next year. I'm doing a retro-gaming playthrough of
the complete Zelda franchise and occasionally twitch stream it.
I'm 8bitino on Twitch, but I rarely go on. I'm about halfway
through Zelda II: The Adventure of Link. It's hard! Next up will
be the Game Boy games, and I'm really excited.

I also am in a slow retro-playthrough of the Quest for Glory
series. I rocked QFG1 in style on Twitch not too long ago. I have
my saved character for QFG2, but I'm going to restart it now that
I found a VGA version. The most exciting thing about this
playthrough is that I've never played QFG5. I stopped at #4 and
loved it so much, but 5 came out after I'd moved on to other
things. EEEk, so much fun!

In a future post I'd like to cover off on some of the RPG
campaigns I've run in the past. The Assassini is probably my best
one, so I think I'll start there. 

Assassini

Setting: 1716 Paris 

Mission: Two agents of the Catholic Church, armed with Papal
dispensation, have been dispatched to undermine the political
power in the region, uncover a religious mystery, and combat
agents of the British Crown who seek to disrupt their plans.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stuck</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180501-stuck/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Stuck
May 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

I've been sitting at my desk for 20 minutes tabbing back and forth
between virtual desktops, tmux sessions/windows/panes, weechat
channels, etc. I feel like I had something I wanted to do, or
maybe say, but I can't remember what it is. It's paralyzing me.

I have 30,000 things I could be doing right now but my inability
to remember this one specific thing has me stuck. Stupid brain.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Proper Mirroring</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180429-proper-mirroring/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Proper mirroring
April 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A few folks were kind enough to let me know that my recent
experiments with tor [0][1] broke my gopher hole mirrored on SDF
and tilde.town. In reality, those mirrors weren't all that useful
in the first place. All the links in my gophermaps to internal
resources were using full, complete hostnames & ports. Thus, if
you went to SDF, after link #1 you were really over on
gopher.black anyway.

[0] gopher.black on tor, part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-gopher-black-on-tor-part-1
[1] gopher.black on tor, part 2
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180428-gopher-black-on-tor-part-2

This wasn't ideal, but it was low priority. It worked well enough,
right? When I removed the explicit hostname & port info from
gophermaps to allow my dual server goodness for tor, suddenly SDF
and tilde.town thought that my links were legitimately local.
There was just one problem... my content paths are different on
all three systems.

On gopher.black, / is mine. Everything starts there.
On SDF, /users/tomasino is mine.
On tilde.town, /~tomasino is mine

The fix didn't take a ton of work since I already had a pretty
solid foundation for mirroring the content. I have a local copy of
my gopher git repo on those boxes and a cron-job that pulls it
four times a day. Simple! Well, now I have a little extra goodness
in there.

The update process looks like so:

  - Fetch the remote
  - Check the SHA of the latest commit in HEAD vs origin/master
  - If different:
    - force reset the local head
    - pull origin/master
    - find all gophermaps and use sed to replace root paths
    - touch the local folder (for SDF's phlog list)

Here's the code [2]:
[2] sdf-update-gopher
    http://gist.github.com/jamestomasino/8241f9e3daf2a0fa49e5a9d35679a427

It's not the cleanest. I could remove the pushd/popd stuff. It's
legacy from a much more complex process time. The sed command is
cumbersome as well. I could have matched \t/[^\t]*$ instead, but
it works. So, like most of my stuff... good enough.

A final note:

Moku Pona & my reading lists are local cron tasks on gopher.black
that update quite often. To avoid a bajillion commits to my gopher
repo I don't include them at all. That means my moku-pona list and
reading lists are not available on SDF or tilde.town. All the rest
of the goods are there, though.

Enjoy & stuff!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gdpr</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180429-gdpr/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
GDPR
April 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

******************************************************************
******************************************************************
******************************************************************
***                                                            ***
***                       N O T I C E                          ***
***                           O F                              ***
***                         G D P R                            ***
***                 C O M P L I A N C E (1)                    ***
***                                                            ***
******************************************************************
******************************************************************
******************************************************************

1. Because Gopher
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Black On Tor Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180428-gopher-black-on-tor-part-2/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gopher.black on tor, part 2
April 28th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This gopher site is finally available as a tor hidden service with
the production onion address: blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion [0]

[0] gopher.black (tor)
    gopher://blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion/1/

In my last post [1] I mentioned three problems I had left:
[1] gopher.black on tor, part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-gopher-black-on-tor-part-1

1) Ugly onion addresses
2) Internal links kick you out of tor
3) Port 71

Here's how that got resolved.

I used Eschalot to generate my onion address. I let the app run
a full day trying to get something that started with gopherblack,
but the pattern was too long to find a match. I figure "black" is
good enough for folks to remember. I had about
15 different ones starting with black, but this had the best
looking pattern.

I ended up installing Gophernicus as a second gopher server next
to motsognir and configured it to serve up my same content. This
install was a tiny bit tricky since I already have a service
listenining on port 70. I also wanted Gophernicus to use my tor
address, not my actual hostname. Finally, I wanted it to run on
port 71, but act like links were still port 70. Doing all this
involved changing 3 files in the repo before I ran make install:

  gophernicus.env

  Uncomment options and give it the onion host and whatever else
  is necessary to your liking: 
  
    OPTIONS="-h blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion -nf -nt"


  gophernicus.socket

  Change port to listen on to 71 or 1138 or whatever you'll be
  using with the tor proxy.


  gophernicus@.service

  There's a line in there that looks like this:

    ExecStart=/usr/sbin/in.gophernicus -h %H $OPTIONS

  Remove the -h %H bit. We set that in options.

Now you can 'sudo make install' and it should "Just Work".
Remember to update your torrc to use port 70 and proxy to 71. This
will give you your content back on port 70 over tor and all will
be good in the world.

The last hurdle to fix were the internal links. My sexy burrow
helper wants to be a good partner, so it generates gophermaps with
full \tHOST\tPORT\r\n line endings. That's overkill for motsognir
and gophernicus, and doesn't allow them the flexibility to add
those bits itself. 

On Motsognir I can exclude the full line ending as long as
I prefix the line with type "i" and it will work.

On Gophernicus I can get rid of any type at the start of the line
and it will work.

To make both happy I need to include the type "i" at the start of
the line and add a single tab character at the end. Not two tabs
or three, just exactly one with nothing after it. This makes both
servers happy and lets them fill in the gaps.

I'll need to add a switch to burrow to generate this style in the
future, but in the meantime I can manually clean it up as I add
posts.

find . -name "gophermap" -exec sed -i 's/\tgopher.black.*//g' {} \;
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Poison Sumac</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180427-poison-sumac/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Poison Sumac
April 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

We had a storm here a few weeks back that did a bunch of damage to
the trees in my yard. One of these trees in the backyard split
into three pieces straight down the middle!

On Saturday I took my hatchet and a chain saw (literally saw-teeth
on a chain that you drag back and forth by hand) and I set to work
clearing things. In the process of chopping and sawing I failed to
notice that the sad tri-split tree was also surrounded by an
overgrown bush of poison sumac. (If you're not familiar with this
particular breed of awfulness, it's just like poison ivy or poison
oak, but harder to identify.)

I was mostly prepared for the work, wearing long pants and sturdy
gloves. I didn't have on a long sleeve shirt, though (it was
hot!). So, now I'm super itchy and covered in a blistery rash.
Calamine lotion helps a bit, but I'm ready for this ordeal to be
over.

I've gotten hit by sumac twice before, and thankfully this time is
much less severe. My first exposure was on a canoeing trip where
I failed to notice that the creek I was in was surrounded on both
sides by sumac. I was covered in a rash from the waist up after
that trip.

The second time was the worst. I was in Boy Scouts on a camping
trip and one of the new scouts tossed in a bunch of green branches
into the fire. It started smoking and flew into my face before
I noticed what was going on. I was just about to explain why we
don't burn green wood when I saw what it was. Too late. I was
hospitalized that time, as I got the sumac in my eyes and lungs.
No good at all.

I hope this clears up soon. I'm so damned itchy!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Black On Tor Part 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180427-gopher-black-on-tor-part-1/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gopher.black on tor, part 1
April 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm working on adding a tor hidden service to gopher.black so you
can enjoy all my steamy content anonymously, you sneaky vixen.
Honestly, the idea seemed a bit daunting but it's turned out to be
pretty straight forward. While I'm not at 100% yet, I thought
I learned enough to share while it's fresh in my mind.

Here's the main steps going from a normal gopher server to
a torified one:

  - Install tor
  - Configure tor to point to your server
  - Start tor
  - Find your hostname


Step 1: Install tor

Check out the install instructions on the tor website. In most
cases it's as simple as:

  sudo apt install tor


Step 2: Configure tor to point to your server

Everything you need to configure in tor is located at
/etc/tor/torrc. Open that bad-boy up and jump down a bit until you
find the section on Hidden Services. Mine is around line 72.
Uncomment them and make it look like so:

  HiddenServiceDir /var/lib/tor/hidden_service/
  HiddenServicePort 71 127.0.0.1:70

The first line is where your hidden service will store all its
secret shenanigans, like the private key it's going to
auto-generate for you. We'll look there in a minute to find the
hostname.

The second line describes Tor's mapping of fake port to real port.
Since we have our gopher hole running on port 70 that's what we
reference on the right. For now, we're going to tell Tor to
pretend port 71 is what we want to use publicly.


Step 3: Start tor

  sudo service tor start # or whatever your machine uses


Step 4: Find your hostname

If you have your hidden service directory like mine above, then
you just need to cat out the hostname hidden in that folder. It'll
be set up to use root permissions, so sudo like so:

  sudo cat /var/lib/tor/hidden_service/hostname

It'll spit out your ugly hostname. Mine is: fhsujakrrdvwq2gk.onion
I'll be changing it soon (see below).


Okay, now you're all set and ready to fire it up. To test you'll
need a gopher client running on tor. I installed Overbite on my
Tor Browser on my PC for easy testing, but you can also use torify
on lynx and a bunch of other things. Once you found a way to run
a tor browser that can see gopher, navigate to your gopher hole
using the onion address and port 71.

  For instance:
  gopher://fhsujakrrdvwq2gk.onion:71

It should work and you'll be moderately pleased. But now we have
problems. 99 of them (not quite).

1) Your onion address sux
2) All the links in your gopher hole on tor probably kick you back
   to your unencrypted, plaintext gopher hole
3) Port 71? What is this, NETRJS?

How can we deal with all these horrors? Let's take a look.


Problem 1: Onion addresses

It's possible to generate sexy onion addresses. You might be
familiar with protonmail's relatively readable one:

  protonirockerxow.onion

That's almost words!

So how can you get that level of not-quite-suck? Why, brute force,
of course! Check out Eschalot [0].

[0] Eschalot
    http://github.com/ReclaimYourPrivacy/eschalot

You can use this and wait... and wait... and wait... and
eventually you'll have a cool onion address. There's some issues
with it, as you can read on the README, but it's probably good
enough for gopher work.


Problem 2: Links

I don't know what gopher server you're running. I'm on motsognir,
which I love and cherish with a little too much gusto. Chances are
that your server is smart enough that if you have no gophermaps or
if you leave off the server & port info in your gophermaps they
are autogenerated based on your host name. That's awesome.
Motsognir does that too. Why aren't you using it again?

Regardless, that will break your shit on tor cause we have
a totally different host name we want to use there.

What's the solution? Well, unless someone has a better idea,
I think the best thing to do is install a second gopher server,
use a different configuration with your tor address as the host
name, and change the port to something other than 70 (more on this
next). If you are on geomyidae, it's already set up so you can run
multiple instances of the server at the same time and override the
host name and port via command line switches. I haven't figured
out how to do that with motsognir yet. I'll probably just install
gophernicus next to motsognir and serve tor over that instead.
They're fairly compatible in gophermap structures.


Problem 3: Port 71!@#$!@#$!$

If you install a second server and run it on another port, oh
let's say... 1138, then you can update your torrc file and point
tor at that new port. In fact, you can point tor at the new point
and let tor pretend it is serving it from 70. Like so:

  HiddenServicePort 70 127.0.0.1:1138

Sexy.

Restart tor and you should be good to go!


I'm still working through these 3 problems with my own solution,
but once it's all done I'll be sure to share part 2 of my journey
and give you all the new tor address.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Grex Hiccups</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180420-grex-hiccups/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
grex hiccups
April 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm not sure what went down over on grex [0] recently, but it
looks to have been sorted out. I'm glad to see everyone phlogging
again. Interestingly, it looks like the hiccup resulted in
moku-pona [1] kicking all the grex folk back up on top of the
lists.

Any of you grex'rs have more to the story?

[0] grex.org
    gopher://grex.org/1/
[1] moku-pona
    http://github.com/kensanata/moku-pona
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Hobbit</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180418-the-hobbit/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Hobbit
April 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I just hit one of the coolest dad milestones. I'm reading The
Hobbit to my son. He's five, nearly six, and I've been talking it
up for the last couple days to get him excited. Tonight, he agreed
to listen to one page.

"If you like it," I said, "I can read a little more. If not, we
can read this other book tonight and try again later."

He agreed. He lifted a stuffed dragon to his chest and nestled
into a spot at my hip against his pillow. I looked down and he
looked back up.

A deep breath.

"In a hole in the ground there lived a hobbit."

He didn't want to stop at one.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sheet Music</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180417-sheet-music/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Sheet music
April 17th, 2018
----------------------------------------

ckeen writes [0] about ABC notation [1] on his phlog, a way to
write music in ascii that's convertable to other formats including
sheet music. I love the idea and have added a collection of
bookmarks to read. Maybe I'll get around to writing my own
converter to Shakuhachi utf-8 notation [2].

[0] ckeen - Setting music sheets
    gopher://vernunftzentrum.de/0/ckeen/phlog/2018-04-17-Setting-music-sheets.md
[1] ABC notation
    http://abcnotation.com
[2] Shakuhachi
    gopher://gopher.black/1/explorations/shakuhachi
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
