<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Talkd Fixes In Ubuntu 20 04</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201011-talkd-fixes-in-ubuntu-20-04/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
talkd fixes in ubuntu 20.04
October 11th, 2020
----------------------------------------

When cosmic voyage updated to ubuntu 20.04 subtle things broke
that I didn't notice right away. One of these was talk(1). We were
using ytalk(1) as the program of choice back in 18.10, but that
seems to no longer be in apt. I reinstalled it from source and was
hopeful that it would do the trick. Not so much.

I fought this for an hour tonight with a very patient voyager
helping me out. I tried closing out of mosh and tmux to narrow
down the issue. Eventually I got a clue from the error message in
syslog.

talkd[411722]: 127.0.0.1 (127.0.0.1): unintelligible packet

I had a lot of these messages and they eventually got me to
a redhat bug report that suggested removing the inetd entry for
talkd would fix it. I commented that out and left the ntalkd line
in place.

I also fixed a thing that bugged me from back in the day. The
nobody user had been configured to be a part of the tty group and
I was using it in that inetd line. That felt dirty since nobody
shouldn't have access to anything.

  sudo useradd -c 'in.talkd User' \
  -d /nonexistent \ -s /usr/sbin/nologin \
  -r -g tty talk

So I added a 'talk' user, gave it the proper access, and swapped
inetd to use that instead. Then I gave it a kick (restart the
process) and things are working again. Whew!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading The Roophlochs</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200928-reading-the-roophlochs/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
reading the roophlochs
September 28th, 2020
----------------------------------------

You are all so amazing. I just read logout, katolaz, and jynx's
roophloch posts and they're so inspiring. I don't have anything
exceptional planned to join you this year but that stuff is really
motivating me to do more. I've been quiet lately and I'm not sure
that's healthy for me. Gopher is a really special place and
I should keep sharing.

More to come from me on that front. Until then, well done!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Vps Upgrades</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200920-vps-upgrades/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
VPS upgrades
September 20th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Yesterday I upgraded gopher.black. Technically I did quite a bit
more than that, but that's probably the most relevant bits for you
gopherites. I have a personal Vultr VPS that hosts this gopher
hole as well as most of my personal websites, my weechat IRC
client, an SMS-to-email relay for my old US-based phone number
that's now a SIP line, my Calibre library, and a whole bunch of
other nonsense that nobody cares about but me. That was all
running on a 25GB instance and doing alright, but free space was
getting a little tight.

The upgrade was set in motion by my desire to start a new
TildeRadio show. It's called Sci-Fi Radio and will be airing on
Tuesdays and Thursdays at 22:00 UTC. It's a 30-minute program that
plays vintage science fiction radio dramas. Specifically the show
will start by re-airing all 125 episodes of X Minus One, and NBC
program from the 1950s. At the conclusion of those episodes we'll
follow up with Dimension X, and then some other programs. I do
hope you'll tune in!

Anyway, in order to set up this stream I wanted to queue up all
the content and then automate the playback via a cron job on my
VPS. That necessitated installing liquidsoap and having enough
space for all the files. Liquidsoap is a bit of a pain in the ass
to get installed properly on Ubuntu. It fails to install the
needed libraries or puts them in the wrong place. I figured out
a solve for it on my home machine running Ubuntu 20.04, but my VPS
was still having issues since it was on 18.04. Also, the mp3s for
the show exceeded my remaining disk space.

So, I decided to upgrade my VPS to a bigger plan! The next problem
was that I didn't have enough remaining disk space to auto-expand
the volume with a plan increase. Instead I needed to snapshot the
instance and spin up a brand new server on a new plan. Fine fine
fine... So I did that, but my static IP pointing to the old server
wouldn't release to let me point it at the new one. This may be
because I chose to put the new server in Amsterdam instead of
London (I still don't trust Brexit). Or maybe it's a Vultr thing
I couldn't figure out. I have no clue.

So here I am, restoring this new box with a new IP which means now
I need to update all my DNS records for the bajillions of domains
that point here. I logged into NameSilo, which is my preferred
registrar, and I started the process. I really don't like dealing
with DNS inside NameSilo, though. For work I typically just point
the DNS to DigitalOcean for droplets I make there. Why not do the
same thing for Vultr? So I did that! I updated the nameservers for
all those domains and painstakingly set up the DNS on Vultr
instead.

About this time the box came back up and I just had to wait on DNS
propagation. As that finished I was up to my next step, the
upgrade to 20.04. This VPS was my 5th such upgrade and it went
very smooth. I had to manually restart one service and then I was
just fighting a few odds and ends. The "python" binary was still
pointing to python2 which was breaking some things. I blew that
away and also removed python2 completely from the system because,
"screw that jazz". I manually relinked python to python3 and it
Just Works™. UFW didn't like the upgrade and reset all my firewall
rules, so I did a little netstat check and enabled the necessary
bits there. And then the last bit of work was going through my
nginx config and patching the few services that weren't showing
up, like Calibre-web and my URL shortner service at ino.is. While
I was tinkering I enabled IPv6 for https://tomasino.org because
I noticed it was missing. I should do the same for my other sites,
but I haven't bothered.

At this point the only things that aren't up and running are:

- The web interface to my syncthing server on the VPS. Syncthing
  itself is running fine and the data is transmitting fine. I can
  ssh-tunnel into the VPS and see the web interface, but my nginx
  reverse proxy won't work. Blerg.

- My minimal gemini server that was running on tomasino.org. That
  uses ncat, part of the nmap project. When I tried installing
  that on Ubuntu 20.04 it failed. Maybe I'll set up a proper
  gemini server instead, or maybe not. I haven't decided.

Oh, and once everything was updated I was able to install
liquidsoap and test out my stream for Sci-Fi Radio. It's
good-to-go for the stream on Tuesday! Woo!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Net News Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200917-net-news-updates/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
net news updates
September 17th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Last year I wrote a guide on how I set up net news (USENET) on
Cosmic Voyage [0]. It's designed not to peer with the big USENET,
but rather with other tilde servers to make a micro net news
network just for us. That post is still valid and if you run
a tilde or pubnix and want to peer with cosmic, reach out and let
me know.

[0] net news on cosmic voyage
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190426-net-news-on-cosmic-voyage

Since Tilde Club rejoined the fold and has become an active member
of the tildeverse, deepend has been good enough to set up a net
news node there as well. We ran into some challenges with the
peering setup early on due to IPV6, but that's been solved. Now
we're growing together and learning new tricks.

Tilde Club opened up its access for using net news remotely, not
just from the local system [1]. If you want to jump into the
conversation now and aren't on Cosmic or Club, you can follow the
instructions there to do so.

[1] usenet news via tilde.club
    https://tilde.club/wiki/usenet-news.html

User xwindows was chatting with me today about a mission to fix
the few problems we have remaining on the network. Perhaps the
most important is the expiration of old messages. As of this phlog
Club is set to expire net news messages after only 15 days.
Hopefully that will be rectified in the next few days, but also
we're working on a way to suck in all the old posts off cosmic to
refill the system. Cosmic's posts are set to expire after 1 year,
so it has much more post data to share with the rest of the
network. Today's immediate challenge was that cosmic didn't have
a method to view that data from outside cosmic itself. Unlike Club
I hadn't set up external access.

With a bit of investigation and some trial & error that has been
fixed. If you connect to cosmic.voyage from an external net news
client you can get a read-only view of everything on the system.

The only change required to make this happen was in
'readers.conf':

  # auth blocks match whichever group succeeds LAST
  # so having the local group below the wildcard
  # is important

  auth "default" {
      hosts: "*"
      default: "anonymous"
  }

  auth "localhost" {
      hosts: "localhost, 127.0.0.1, ::1, stdin"
      default: "<localhost>"
  }

  access regular {
      read: "*,!junk,!control,!control.*"
  }

  access full {
      users: "*,!anonymous"
      newsgroups: "*,!junk,!control,!control.*"
  }

  access "localhost" {
      users: "<localhost>"
      newsgroups: "*,!junk,!control,!control.*"
      access: RPA
  }

The first two blocks handle local access which is basically saying
if you're on cosmic you're good to go. Post away. Otherwise read.

The three blocks following set up a two-case scenario for everyone
else. If you connect and successfully auth your user will be set
to whatever your username is. If not, you get the default name
"anonymous". Then I have a blanket rule for everyone to be able to
read everything, and finally a special rule for everyone not named
anonymous allowing posting.

So far testing seems to be working alright!

Oh, and one last thing... If you want to make sure your expiration
settings are nice and long (say... several years) then you only 
need to change a few config lines:

  # expire.ctl
  *:A:365:1095:never

  # innreport.conf
  cycle 365;

  # inn.conf
  artcutoff: 365
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Goodbye Tilde Black</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200905-goodbye-tilde-black/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
goodbye tilde.black
September 05th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A few days ago I woke up to a string of emails about abuse from
a member of tilde.black upon EFNet, the IRC network. I was about
to start work and didn't have the energy or time to deal with the
problem, so I took the server offline. The next day I thought more
about the situation and realization came to me that I had
absolutely no desire to spend my time figuring out who the bad
apple was this time, removing them, and sealing the door against
them returning. It wasn't the first time I'd had to act upon
someone taking advantage of the system and it sure looked like
this wouldn't be the last time either.

When I created tilde.black it was on a whim. I had this silly idea
that I could pre-generate usernames from dictionary words and then
when people joined they would get a random name. What better way
to provide anonymity, right? Since it was going to be a system
about privacy, I felt a secure OS was warranted and I went with
openbsd despite knowing nothing about it. This was an opportunity
to learn, and learn I did. I learned to value and appreciate a lot
about that system. The sane defaults, the truly incredible
documentation, and the intuitive configuration were all pleasant
surprises. The web server, horribly named httpd (try web-searching
for help on that) was another matter. Shortly before this incident
I had finally broken down and just installed nginx.

The experiment was good. It lasted far longer than I expected and
gained far, far more users than I ever thought would find it
interesting. For one thing the very nature of this private tilde
went against the concepts of community building that really make
a tilde work. There was almost no peer engagement happening. But
people were attracted to the idea of the server. I think, in the
end, I was too. I really liked the concept of a private, anonymous
place where people could experiment. In reality it was pretty
boring, though.

From a user perspective the best thing that came out of it was
brool, a user who kept a file called "stoned.txt". It was in
essence a never-ending phlog/journal of random thoughts, ideas,
and art that came to them while they were high. It was fantastic.
I'm sad that's not around anymore. I hope whoever made it has
a copy somewhere and finds a way to ressurect it on another
server. It spawned a few copy-cat files, but it was a true
masterpiece and really deserves some recognition.

Beyond that there was some stock market analysis, a few irc bot
coding projects, the odd shell scripting thing here or there, and
a few minimal websites. Not a lot to miss.

I had put my initial gemini work up on the server. In fact, I made
it a point not to put gemini on gopher.black or on any of my
tomasino domains specifically as an excuse to log into tilde.black
and do something. That was all backed up in git, though, and has
since migrated over to tilde.team[0].

[0] Tomasino's Gemini site
    gemini://tilde.team/~tomasino/

Tilde.Black is shut down for good. I stopped seeing it as fun at
some point and it had become a burden. I hadn't been able to put
that into words until this EFNet incident. Were it not for this
trigger the site may have continued for months more, but it would
have inevitably fallen. It was a neat idea and that's good enough.

Now I have cosmic.voyage as my sole remaining tilde community and
I want to put my love back into it. With the growing popularity of
black I hadn't spent nearly enough time looking after cosmic. It's
been sort of on autopilot, you might say. There's still writers
writing. There's still chatters in the channel in IRC. I find
I still have a passion for it and an excitement for it to continue
and grow.

This November I'm going to put out a series of writing prompts as
a sort of mini-contest to see how much we can all write. I don't
know that there are any prizes, but hey, maybe? I just want to
really do something for it to give it the love. Do you know what
I mean?

It reminds me a bit of cat's sites: baud.baby, baud.vision, and
konpeito.media. There's a guy who has some incredible passion to
the stuff he puts out there and I am in awe of it each time he
does so. But like cat, I get bored of it sometimes. Bored isn't
even the right word. Other things come first and it sort of
doesn't matter. Or maybe it does matter, but the fact that it
matters annoys me so I ignore it. Or maybe my mind is just sick of
dealing with thoughts in the way required to engage with my
project. There's a hundred metaphors and none are quite correct.

Cosmic will be getting more love soon. Hopefully my gopher hole
will as well. Once I start writing in one place it's hard not to
write everywhere. Maybe this post will help kick it off! Either
way, saying goodbye to Tilde Black feels great.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Divination</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200717-divination/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
divination
July 17th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A few days ago I coded a shell-script version of the I Ching (Book
of Changes), and made it accessible on Gemini [0]. In the process
I added a note on the Gemini site quickly addressing some concerns
over the use of digital tools for divination. It all felt rushed
and incomplete and I think I have more to say on the subject,
perhaps a lot more. Gemini isn't the place for that, though. This
is definitely a gopher topic.

[0] I Ching Shell Script
    https://github.com/jamestomasino/iching

I practice a number of forms of divination including consulting
the I Ching, tarot cards, tasseography, cleromancy (whether with
dice, dominos, or runes), and so on. There's a number of forms
I don't practice for various reasons: horoscopy, gematria,
extispicy (ew), ouija, augury, and oh so many more. Someone has
figured out a way to use just about anything for divination.

Before we get too far into this, let me drop some dictionary magic
on you. Here's the definition from two online dictionaries: 

  Divination: 
  
  1. the practice of seeking knowledge of the future or the
     unknown by supernatural means

  2. the art or practice that seeks to foresee or foretell future
     events or discover hidden knowledge usually by the
     interpretation of omens or by the aid of supernatural powers

Seeking knowledge, usually hidden knowledge, by the aid of the
supernatural. Cool. Got it?

So there are a billion forms of divination out there, but why? Do
they all work? Do any of them work? How do they purport to work?
Lets focus on the last bit first. How does divination work? This
is the interesting bit for me at least.

In cleromancy the mechanism of action is some sort of randomness.
Cleromancy is about "tossing stuff" like dice and seeing what
comes up. Some practitioners suggest that the randomness allows
the supernatural to take direct action and influence the results
of the toss. Other practitioners would say that the toss and its
randomness is just that and not influenced by the supernatural,
but the querent (person seeking information) must use their
intuition to understand the results of the toss. That type of
practitioner moves the supernatural action internal to the
unconscious mind and changes its domain of action to the
interpretation alone. But there are still other types! Some see
the unconscious mind as affecting the toss itself in a sort of
blend of the first two. Others shy away from intuition and suggest
self-reflection and psychology allow the interpretation of any
symbol to be helpful as a means of thinking in a new way about the
issue.

Yeesh, that's a lot, and that's just cleromancy! But what about
chartomancy (books & cards)? Is the mechanism of action different?

On the one hand, there are far more established symbols present
in, say, a tarot card than in a rune. Consulting the I Ching or
the Bible likewise greatly increases the available symbols and
interpretations. The act itself is still governed by some sort of
randomness, or chaotic action as I like to call it. Shuffling
cards, separating yarrow stalks, even flipping pages promotes some
sort of uncertainty and allows for the possibility of and unknown.

Does this unknown mean that a supernatural power is guiding the
result? That's a matter of faith and, ultimately, irrelevant. What
about the interpretation? Is that guided by a supernatural power?
Again, a question of faith that has no ultimate bearing on the
value of divination. What‽

Yeah, you read me correctly. I'm saying that it doesn't matter if
there's no supernatural involved at all or if there is. The aim of
divination is to seek to foresee the future or discover hidden
knowledge and divination can succeed in  both cases regardless of
the origin of its power.

Lets side with the pragmatic doubter practitioner for a moment and
assume that there's no magic at work here at all. We're going to
go through some exercise that will result in symbols ready for
interpretation. The process we have just taken was designed to
orient our mind to the problem, focus upon it seriously, perhaps
spending a significant amount of time in so doing. We are now
asked to review and interpret these forms which have a variety of
possible meanings requiring we try to apply them systematically
and in various combinations to the problem or subject. That
thought process involves mental judo and an openness to new ideas.
It will inevitably bring insight and... wait for it... hidden
knowledge. It will also undoubtedly influence future actions and
have a major impact on the events to come. BAM! Divined.

Now, allow yourself to take the seat as an individual who has
faith in the machinations of the supernatural. Given even a hint
of influence from that "other", the results gain significance and
their origins may carry more weight, but the interpretation and
internalization of that information is unchanged. It really
doesn't matter.

I really enjoy the processes, especially the lengthy ones with
much ritual like the yarrow stalk I Ching method, or the ones that
are inherently delicious like tasseography (reading tea leaves).

If I have any advice to give on the subject it is to enter into
divination with healthy skepticism, not to undermine the results
but to fully engage with them. Don't take any reading at face
value or you've done yourself a disservice.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What Is Gemini</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200612-what-is-gemini/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
What is Gemini?
June 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Last night I recorded a video about the new Gemini protocol [0],
created by solderpunk [1] which has been _taking off_ remarkably
well. If you aren't familiar with Gemini by now, it is a new
protocol that is very similar to gopher but with some
enhancements. It is still far, far away from being anything like
the web, but it brings some modern thought and consideration to
hypertext browsing.

[0] gemini protocol
    gopher://gemini.circumlunar.space/1/
[1] solderpunk
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/1/~solderpunk

You can watch my video on peertube or on youtube! [2,3]

[2] peertube
    https://toobnix.org/videos/watch/8ee54700-971c-4da3-a8b4-7a78ed9ac42e
[3] youtube
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoEI6VzybDk
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fun Questions Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200605-fun-questions-part-2/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fun Questions - Part 2
June 05th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Last spring I asked gopherspace a few fun questions to get some
interactions rolling [0]. Lots of people participated and
I personally got a lot of joy from seeing both the feedback and
learning a bit more about all of you. Well, I'm in desperate need
of some joy right now so I figure it's a good time for part 2!

[0] fun questions
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190330-fun-questions

I'll keep with the theme and ask 3 questions again. If you want to
participate, you can answer any or all. Phlog the answer over on
your own gopher hole and we'll read up on them. Send me a note if
you do so and I'll add a link to the bottom of this post so
everyone can read your responses.

1. Think back and try to remember the most satisfying drink of
   water in your life. What's the story of that drink?

2. Have you ever personally witnessed an act off human compassion
   that brought you to tears?

3. When is the last time you fell off a bicycle?

Replies:
seedy
    gopher://seedy.xyz/0/phlog/2020/jun/20200605.txt
christyotwisty
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/christyotwisty/phlog/2020-06-05.txt
jebug29
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/jebug29/log/2020-06/09-0348
tfurrows
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~tfurrows/phlog/2020-06-24_reFunQuestions2.txt
plugd
    gopher://thelambdalab.xyz/0/phlog/2020-06-23-Eight-Answers-(Replies-to-Tomasino-and-Christina).txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>More Deaths Poetry</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200602-more-deaths-poetry/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
more deaths - poetry
June 02nd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Another high school friend died on Saturday. I met her in poetry
class in my junior year. She sat behind me and we had a lot of
fun. In fact, we had so much fun that we attracted the attention
of another person across the room, Kristin. She came to join us
after a few weeks in our little area and would eventually become
my best friend.

In honor of Erin, may she rest in peace, I'm reading back over my
poetry here on gopher and in old notebooks. So much of it makes me
cringe now (I obviously read too much Dickenson & Browning at the
time) but I can still feel the youthful passion. I wish I had some
of her poems around.

Old poems of dubious quality
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/poetry
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Car</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200526-new-car/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
new car
May 26th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A funny thing happened to me on Saturday. I went to a lovely BBQ
with some friends in Reyjkavík and had to head home around 2300 in
order to catch the last bus from the capital out to my little
suburb. The bus picked me up and deposited me there 20 minutes
later as planned. While I was on the bus, I took out my kindle to
do some reading.

When I got off that bus I needed to make one transfer onto the #7
bus which would take me into my neighborhood, saving me a 1km walk
from the town center. I've done this many times and knew the bus
would be along any moment, so I kept reading. As expected, the bus
came around the corner and up the hill toward me. I hopped on and
kept reading.

See, here's where things get a little silly. I may have been
pretty drunk at this point owing to said BBQ earlier in the
evening. I was most certainly not paying attention as I was
reading. I also forgot completely that the number 7 bus travels in
both directions from the same bus stop I was at. I usually would
check the exact timing of the bus because there's no way to tell
from the signage whether it's headed to my neighborhood or away
from it. In fact, during that last nightly route both busses
appear at that stop within two minutes of one another.

So yeah, I was a little surprised when I looked up to find myself
in another town and not in my neighborhood. I was screwed. Ugh.

There were no more busses and taxis don't just wander the streets.
You need to call them and arrange a pickup. So what's a drunk guy
to do in this situation? If you guessed "walk 10km home around
a mountain in the middle of the night in Iceland" then you win
a prize!

I took a shortcut across the middle of a golf course at one point,
and marveled once again at the well maintained and numerous trails
and paths available in my area. Almost everything was well lit and
clean. It was lovely! It took me over two hours to get home and
I got a few hot-spots on my heels since I was walking in flimsy
slip-on shoes and not my boots. Still, no harm no foul.

Anyway, today I bought a car. :D It's a 2017 SsangYong Tivoli. It
is white and in pretty good shape with only about 60,000km on it.
I'm not sure you'll believe me now, but this was actually in the
works before Saturday's adventure. My wife and I were talking
about how nice it is here to be able to take the bus everywhere
and how it was probably better for our health to do all the
walking. We also admitted that it's frustrating not to be able to
go out into the countryside. We live only 25 minutes from
þingvellir, after all, but we never go. We want to head up north
this summer and we were considering renting. But there's little
annoyances too. 

This summer there are a number of activities available to the kids
in the area. One is a little zoo and horseback riding place where
the kids can learn to take care of the animals. It would be
perfect for my boy. The farm is only 5 minutes away, but that's by
car. It's directly on the other side of the mountain behind my
apartment. To walk there would take an hour, each way. That's not
something we could sign him up for before. Now it's no problem.

People here also just assume you have a car or access to one. It
can be tricky when activites happen at odd spots. Even travelling
to IKEA from my place is a chore because it takes 4 transfers and
over 2hrs to get there. Now with a car it's an 18 minute drive.

We don't intend to use it for everything. Certainly we want to
have it to go out into the country and see the sights. We also
will use it for things like IKEA trips. But we want to keep using
the bus to go downtown and walk to go shopping for groceries.
I don't know how realistic that goal is, but we shall see.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
