<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Anonradio Show</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180907-anonradio-show/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
aNONradio show
September 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Yesterday cat posted on Mastodon that someone should jump on
openVOIP and monologue. That sounded like a great idea and
I wasn't busy, so I decided I'd go for it. My first thought was
that I'd read some Virgil or maybe Bronte. I walked into my dining
room which has the main collection of our books and looked over my
shelves for something good. Boy Scout Handbook... Nimzowitsch...
Harry Potter in Latin... ahh, here we are:

ZORK #4: Conquest at Quendor

Is there a more perfect book for the SDF crew than a choose your
own adventure ZORK? I snapped a quick picture of the cover and
posted it to mastodon, then walked upstairs to my office. A note
on IRC or two and I was dialing in to the openVOIP line. At first
there was some sort of text adventure being played out with
Daniel's robot voice narrating it. That wrapped up and I got
started.

It was awkward, silly, and entirely too much fun. Instead of
picking the choices in the book myself I tossed them out to the
crowd to chime in. The engagement from people in com, mastodon,
and IRC made the experience for me. I was riding a high afterwards
and talked myself into doing it again. This time, though, I'll do
it right.

The anonradio mailing list folks agreed that the show was worthy
of a time slot, so now on Thursday nights/Friday mornings at 0100
UTC, or 9PM EST, I'll be continuing our adventures. This first
"real" show I'll finish up the ZORK story so I don't leave
everyone hanging, and then we'll start a new adventure. I don't
know that I'll make a point of finishing the adventures or not. If
time runs out I may just start a new one the next week instead of
trying to pick up again. On the one hand, it's nice to have some
completion, but these are books designed to be tried again and
again. Also, the authors aren't getting paid for this beyond me
buying a book or two, so I like the idea of enticing people with
the show so that they might go out and pick up a copy if they
enjoy it. That makes the whole thing seem much more legit, right?

To support the new show I've added a new section to my gopher
hole. You can find it on the root gophermap and here: 
Choose Your Own Adventure (anonradio)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/cyoa

For those who want to check it out, details about the first real
episode can be found here:
Episode 001 (2018-09-14)
    gopher://gopher.black/0/cyoa/2018-09-14-episode-001.txt

Please join me next week for the first show!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Blogging</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180904-blogging/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Blogging
September 04th, 2018
----------------------------------------

So I just published a regular old boring blog post and now I feel
dirty. I mean, not really, but I do feel something. I think it's
frustration or annoyance. You see, I wanted to open the blog with
a screenplay style intro, but it turned out to be painfully
difficult. I'm using Hugo which in turn uses markdown for
formatting and generally that's just fine. But in this case
I wanted to do some very specific text formatting that would have
been obvious and immediate in gopher but which took me five or six
iterations to figure out over there.

But it has a picture! :/ Meh, I guess so. More-over, the content
fit the theme of another blog post I wrote about Clue (this one is
about Guess Who, btw). It made sense to put it on the web.

I guess it once again illustrates why I prefer gopher. I can just
write stuff here and I'm done. In the world of HTTP I need to
massage stuff, play with themes, etc. Moops to that.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>3d Printing</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180901-3d-printing/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
3D Printing
September 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

I bought a 3D printer. It's a FlashForge Finder, available on
Amazon for somewhere in the $300-350USD range at present. It
prints PLA but not ABS, has a decent sized print area, comes fully
assembled, and has fair community support. The service that
FlashForge offers is extremely responsive and helpful. Overall I'm
quite pleased with the purchase.

Since Tuesday I've been printing things almost non-stop. I've made
an external spool holder to support bigger filament spools than
the printer can handle normally. I've got a tool holder caddy on
the box as well. I've made an Arduino Uno bumper/baseplate, a few
toys for my son including squishy turtles and a fully articulated
snail with shell that opens. As I'm writing this a book holder
just finished.

I'll be making some desk accessories soon, and then I think I'll
take my first stab at designing my own piece by modifying the
hanging tool-holder to make a glue-stick holder of the same style.

3D printing is pretty fantastic. It's really easy, way faster than
I expected, and the quality of this personally affordable model is
suprisingly good. I can make real things!

Oh, I made a few rings for my wife. She's allergic to metal, so
this is perfect. I've sanded them down and I'm priming them now.
Later today I'll paint and seal them for her. Isn't that exciting?
I can design her jewelry, print it, post-process, and she can wear
it all in the same day. That's some agrestic shit right there [0].

[0] Agrestic
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180824-the-agrestic
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Letterboxing</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180831-letterboxing/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Letterboxing
August 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

Let me preface this by saying my snark here is entirely fictional
and I have the greatest of respect for other people's hobbies...

                *    *    *    *    *    *    
                
Geocaching is bullshit. Seriously? Let me poke in some numbers and
walk there and boom! a seeeeeecret thing. Tada! (play "Link gets
the triforce noise" in your head). Oh sure, there's clues to solve
but at the end of the day the whole physical aspect of going
somewhere could be removed and replaced with a checkbox that says,
"Yep, got it."

Now letterboxing... that's the shit right there. None of this
fancy schmancy technology. Instead, good old fashioned vague
pioneer directions like, "Go west-north-west for 45 paces until
you near the tree that looks like an old man taking a piss."
That's some real adventure! Not the old man taking a piss, the
dire--you know what I mean. I love letterboxing. I will stamp the
shit out of some letterboxes. I will leave hitchhikers along the
way and have grand adventures in state parks. Mmmm, saucy hobby.

The reason I bring this up is not to bash geocaching (though that
was fun) but because Christy (who loves her some GPS) reminded me
of an idea I had a while back for letterboxing which, I suppose,
could be channelled for the dark arts in her hobby as well. My
idea was to make a series of box challenges which led from one to
the other and eventually were all pieced together into an Uber
challenge. Not the car service kind, but like--you know what
I mean.

The theme was cryptography, which I felt was fitting. The simplest
box used a Da Vinci cipher. The box then gave a piece of the
puzzle to the next clue which was an Arnold cipher. Then on to
a straddling checkerboard. Then the big one was a VIC cipher. And
when you took the pieces from all the boxes together and
concatenated all the strings you found, it would be a PGP key you
could use to decode the final message to the final box.

I got as far as that and some basic clue planning, then I got hung
up on where I wanted to hide the boxes and never got around to
doing it. So, if you are out there and you letterbox, please go
ahead and steal my idea. I'd like to try and find your box
(snicker). If you're a dirty geocacher, I guess you can do with it
what you want... ugh.

;)
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Weechat Android</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180825-weechat-android/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
weechat-android
August 25th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I just installed weechat-android on my phone and boy are my arms
tired. Wait, no... I mean, boy was that easy! 

I set up a relay:

/secure set relaypass yourmom
/set relay.network.password "${sec.data.yourmom}"
/relay add weechat 9001

Then I opened up port 9001:

sudo ufw allow 9001

Then I went into my router and port forwarded 9001 to gopher.black
(which runs my weechat).

I downloaded the app from the play store like a heathen (it's on
f-droid too, or direct from github). Opened up the configuration
settings, clicked connect, and nothing worked!!!

Then I closed the app, reopened it, and boom! Everything was fine.

The interface is great. Very intuitive for swiping around. If
you're an IRC junky and use weechat, check it out.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Agrestic</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180824-the-agrestic/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Agrestic
August 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

== Introduction ==

I wrote an opinion piece in my college newspaper about the state
of our campus due to excessive construction during my two years
attending. There was no grass over the vast majority of the
campus, only churned earth or piled dirt next to broken cement
walkways. I don't remember much of the article except that I used
the word "agrestic" in a way that suggested rural beauty. The
editor of the paper had enormous issue with the word, claiming it
wasn't a real word at all (her three degrees in English literature
as proof). This outrage and logical fallacy cemented "agrestic" in
my mind forever. Funny how brains work [0].

[0] cat - Miscolored memory of Washington
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20180825.txt

This phost isn't about that article though. This phost is about
the future, post-modernism, the death of the internet, and the
rise of the agrarian renaissance. Hold on to your butts, we're
going for a ride.


== Time Travel == 

In 1985 Back to the Future was released. Apart from it being
a nearly flawless film giving us endless quotability and
establishing a benchmark for all future time travel films, it also
cemented into my budding consciousness the idea of temporal
relativity. By this I don't mean anything to do with Einstein's
terminology, but rather the sense of future and past being
relative to your own present. What seems obvious from your point
of view today gets very complex when you take into consideration
time travel.

Lets say you traveled back to 1955. When you say "in the future
I want to be a rock star" do you mean back in 1985 where you're
from, or in your personal future? Perhaps you'll return to your
original timeline, or perhaps like Doc Brown you'll cut ties to it
completely and move independently like a Time Lord. The further
you get away from linear existence the harder relative temporal
terms become. Or maybe they just become less useful since they
lack a common vantage point. If you were the Doctor traveling with
Rose Tyler, you could say, "let's get chips tomorrow" and it might
still make sense, even if tomorrow happened to be in Victorian
London.

Time travel complicates everything [1], even basic language. But
it doesn't take a T.A.R.D.I.S. to weaken a word into
meaninglessness. It just takes aging.

[1] tomasino - time travel
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20171130-time-travel

As a kid, the future represented sleek, pointy cars with sharp
angles and neon colors. Badass dudes with giant shoulder pads
would wear opaque shades while LA and NYC were either on fire or
underwater. These days the future is global economic collapse as
the balance of power shifts to China and a waffling United States
falls back on military action to try and maintain a control it
gave away through isolationism. The future, in essence, is nothing
at all. It is a fantasy in constant flux with no anchor in reality
or common experience. It is neither hope nor fear. It is
intangible and ineffable, and utterly useless.

In 1955, Marty McFly went back to the future. He returned to his
nineteen eighty-five where sexy mom and successful dad were ruling
the day. He had his truck, he had the girl, and everything was
going to be okay. That moment of psychological juxtaposition where
he physically entered into a new timeline that was not his own
projections of anticipation or a cultural meme of anxiety but
a physical reality that had been shaped by actions he would never
personally witness--that was like the moment of birth all over
again. He was in a new world, a "future" world, bearing no
similarity to the other meaningless definitions of the term. His
fictional actions made fictionally-real a concept which cannot
ever be real. Rather than a tautology, this is something inverted:
where the repetition of a meaningless idea becomes meaningful.

If you're following my logic I commend you or apologize or both.
Ultimately what I'm getting at is that the idea of a future is
meaningless, except in context of its own manipulation. That
manipulation is irrelevant without time travel or some other means
of temporal scrying. You cannot change the future if you don't
know what the future holds. The future is nothing becoming nothing
otherwise. Simple, right?

So, it with all of this in mind that I proclaim with all the
seriousness of IHOP rebranding as IHOb that "The Future" must
definitively refer to 1985 and nothing else or it will become
meaningless once again. 

Being that the definition of definition is (yes, tautology again),
"a statement of the meaning of a word or word group or a sign or
symbol," then only a statement that gives meaning to the word
"future" can rightly be called a definition. If only such
a situation as car-washer Biff can justify a true "future", there
you have it. Let all other uses be damned. Change thy lexicon!


== The Agrestic ==

While sitting at a Denny's in Greenwood, Indiana, staring down at
a paper place-mat featuring "Guess Who?", I had this conversation
with my friend Josh. There was much coffee involved, and probably
a burger in there somewhere, and we were more certainly awake far
too late in the night. My argument stated, I continued for him as
I will for you now.

The future is over. It's been done, you see. 1985! We're well
passed that, even if it was a fictional version of it. If this
time is no longer the future, or even "A" future, what is it? We
have generational terms, decade terms, and occasionally history
grants a time with an overall label in retrospect. These are all
scientific, calculated, or reactive. They don't attempt to
describe us while we are still in the act of being. They describe
the past, or they describe the calendar of the present.
Uncertainty clouds the present and the days ahead and puts us back
into nonsense-words again, right? 

What if we chose a nonsense word for the times we're in and the
times to come that wasn't bland or neutral, but instead one that
evoked in us a primal sense of experience. Imagine that a word
could convey in existential, individual, human terms a sense of
the entire days to come. It wouldn't need to be packed with
context from other sources but contain them within its full
understanding.

Agrestic.

That is the "future" I envision and put forth in my own mind and
in my interactions with the world. It can be summed up as the
logical conclusion to the phrase:

"Then they all decided the internet was a pretty bad idea."

What happens next. What do we find. Rustic. Beauty. The Earth.
Human animals in the dirt, in the trees, in the seas. Unpack as
much as you can from the word and from its idea and from all that
came before it and let it saturate you.

Is it silly, is it absurd, is it infinitely unlikely to happen?
Who cares? Flying cars are EXACTLY as absurd.

Here's the key to the whole thing: whatever you aim at you're not
going to hit, but you're going to end up close. If you aim at
flying cars and nuclear war... I don't want to go there with you.
If you aim at a world where we found peace with our planet and
didn't let our creations define us then everyone deserves some
god-damned high fives in my book.

Agrestic. Say it with me. It may not be a word (it really, really
is a word), but that doesn't matter. It's in your head and it's in
my head and it's more fucking real than a flux capacitor.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>X11forward</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180816-x11forward/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
X11Forward
August 16th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Today I tried in vain to accomplish something that should be
relatively simple: to share my clipboard with remote terminal
sessions.

Here's the scenario I'm in:
 - I'm using a MacBook Air (work machine)
 - I mosh to gopher.black (raspberry pi)
 - I use tmux

This shouldn't be so difficult, but it is. Here's a list of
problems I've run into (and fixes):
 - macOS needs X installed first (XQuartz installed)
 - mosh doesn't seem to do x11 forwarding (used ssh -X or ssh -Y)
 - remote ssh didn't allow x11 forwarding (edited sshd_config)
 - local ssh config didn't allow x11 forwarding (edit .ssh/config)

After all that, I now successfully can see a $DISPLAY on the
remote when I connect! Hooray!

But what's this? Copying something with xsel on the remote does
a whole load of nothing? Awesome.

Somedays I feel like I'm crushing this whole computer thing. Some
days I just want to walk out into the woods and build a cabin.
I think I'm gonna go read some Thoreau.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Rings</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180811-gopher-rings/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gopher rings
August 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

From ze libertine gamer [0] on Mastodon:
[0] ze libertine gamer
    gopher://zlg.space/1/

<zlg> Places like Bongusta and phlogroll remind me of web-rings
from the 1990s. Let's name'em gopher-rings, or perhaps gopher dens
if we want to be cute. They serve the same function: building
a network with volunteer participants (the curation process) and
technology that empowers the individual (self-hosting and
moku-pona). What do you think, #gopher?

tfurrows [1] also posted a semi-related phlog [2] today on
favorites and the tools that engineer our interactions.
[1] tfurrows - sdf
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/tfurrows
[2] tfurrows - favorites
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/tfurrows/phlog/2018/agp_favorites.txt

- - - - - - - -

I started thinking about a response on Mastodon, but my head
flooded with too many things to fit in 500 characters. A phlog is
a better medium, I think.

In the nascent web we had many ways of finding each other and
other content that seems archaic or obtuse in retrospect. In the
very earliest days I kept a paper notebook where I manually wrote
down email addresses and websites. Later web-rings became popular
ways to link like-content to one another, forming communities from
the ether. By the time search engines came online we had all sorts
of other ways to bridge the gaps.

I think back to my time using AltaVista, or Lycos, or Yahoo!,
finding them awkward and lacking, and returning to the advice of
a webring or forum to find real relevant sites. I would cast
a broader net using a meta-search engine like SavvySearch and
click through pages and pages of results. That method of exploring
the web didn't take over in prominance for me, personally, until
Google began their takeover.

Web-rings fell to the wayside quickly as "googling" entered the
lexicon, and I don't think I consciously realized the
"engineering" or "channeled usage", as tfurrows puts it, was so
broadly affecting my behavior until very recently. In my head,
search engines are tools and I use them. If I am careful to avoid
tracking behaviors, they don't use me, right?

Well, maybe not. Google's algorithms, or a browser's "favorites"
screen guides our hand and our habits in a major way. We engage
with what we see and what we find, and that is a power that
shouldn't be forgotten.

So, thinking on ze libertine gamer's idea, I think the gopher
aggregators, the gopher-rings, are very much a throwback to the
old days when communities were more manually linked to one
another. There is still a power inherent in the tools we use, no
different than Google wields, or Firefox, but because it's curated
by participants in the community (like me!), I feel better about
it. Our micro-aggregators aren't monolithic. Anyone can run one,
thanks to the awesome utilities shared around the community.

My phlog roll [3] began as a personal tool for me to track the
phlogs I read. It's become a very popular starting point for
others as well, and so I added some language to the top on how to
get new sites added. Inclusion on my aggregator is open to all, as
long as your phlog is in a format that moku-pona can handle.
I don't want to be a barrier to finding gopher content; I want to
be an easy entry-point. 

[3] gopher.black phlog roll
    gopher://gopher.black/1/moku-pona

Have a site that you want added? Drop me an email at one of the
addresses in my contact page on this gopher hole, or reach out on
Mastodon. I try to watch SDF, grex, and the tilde communities for
new holes that pop up so I can add them quickly. I generally wait
until a phlog has at least two posts before I add it to avoid the
"hello world" phenomenon that litters SDF. Just hit me up if you
see something missing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Data Security Ratings</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180810-data-security-ratings/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Data Security Ratings
August 10th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Christina has been posting about data security [0][1] with some
engagement from others [2].

[0] Christina - Infosec And Data Privacy Part 1
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~christina/InfosecAndDataPrivacy.txt
[1] Christina - Infosec And Data Privacy Part 2
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~christina/ISDP_2_SelfRating.txt
[2] Solderpunk - Data Security Ratings
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/data-security-ratings.txt

It's very interesting stuff which started on Mastodon and
continued in gopherspace. It's worth a read.

I had one last thought I wanted to share based on an exchange on
IRC. Some people have brought up threat levels and planning your
security for the type of danger you really face, not ridiculous
levels of paranoia. We're not all Snowden, after-all. That being
said, I wanted to share my email system so you can see what
happens when you go off the deep end with no real reason.

First of all, I use neomailbox for my mail provider. They're
pretty great, in a country with better data privacy laws than the
US, and have solid privacy policies and encryption measures in
place to protect their users. They offer a unique feature that
I've not found in other providers: they will auto-sign incoming
mail with your public key if you request it. While mail that
wasn't encrypted at the source may still be vulnerable in
transmission, after it hits their servers its safety just took
a major step up.

Next, I only connect to neomailbox over a VPN & Tor. Outgoing mail
relayed through their servers wipes metadata anyway, but it's just
another stupid thing to do in protecting the connection itself.
How do I connect? Good old pop3, baby. I don't leave anything on
the server.

Mail is fetched locally and the system auto-disconnects from the
internet. When browsing messages I remain offline. I reply and
queue up my outgoing mail. When ready to send, browsing shuts down
and the machine reconnects safely to send it on its way.

The local maildir is backed up over spideroak, encrypting the
mailboxes of already encrypted messages offsite to another machine
in case of calamity.

That's it! Fun right?

I want to reiterate, this is completely unnecessary for my threat
level and it was done more as a hobby project to see how far
I could push it. Airgapping, redundant encryption, it's too much
for people to bother with. It's a great illustration of why other
people give up and just settle for whatever.

If you're new to infosec, do yourself a favor and get a protonmail
account. That's about as good as you're going to do without
putting in a bunch of work. Is it as good as what Snowden does? Oh
hells no. But you're not on the run from the US government, are
you? It'll keep google off your back, and you're less likely to
fall victim to simple scams.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reunion</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180806-reunion/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reunion
August 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This past weekend I went to the Tomasino family reunion in Ohio.
It was good to see my sister and her family, and to run into all
the other relatives that I haven't seen since I was my son's age.
It was nice for him to experience a reunion as well. He doesn't
see anyone but my wife and I most of the time since we don't live
near any of our family and soon will be moving much further away.

I like to say that my sister inherited all the roots and I got all
the wanderlust. My parents and their parents all grew up in
Youngstown, Ohio, where our immegrant ancestors all settled. They
were fruitful and multiplied and most of the brood has remained
fairly close to that nexus. When my parents married they moved
away chasing work leading to my sister and I being born in
Virginia. We lived there briefly and then a few years in Maryland
before heading to New Jersey where we both completed high school.

That was enough for my Sister. She went to college back in
Youngstown and never left again. All the years growing up she
talked about going "back" and she didn't hesitate. 

I took the other approach. Growing up away from extended family,
I learned to love the move. After high school I did a brief stint
in college before joining the Navy. I moved a lot in the service,
and then a lot more afterwards. After college #2 and grad school,
the moves continued. I've managed to live in 15 states now, and
I'm thrilled to get out of the United States finally.

On the one hand, I think I can thank my sister for my own freedom
of place. She is an anchor in the family that allows me to float
free. While we were in Ohio I spent a few days in her company
wandering Youngstown, Austintown, Struthers, and Lowellville. In
every single place we stopped, be it restaurant or school or
grocery or playground, we met someone that knew her well enough to
stop by and talk. She is so entwined with the place it is a part
of her and she of it. My brother-in-law functions in the same way.
His family owns so much local farm-land and have roots so far back
it doesn't make sense. He is an engineer who built this or that as
we drove around, and who coaches this team and that team, or
helped review the building plans for this guy's daughter's shop.
It's a fascinating life they have, and I'm so happy they get to
have it.

That sort of thing may not appeal to me personally but I can see
the glamour in it and the comfort it can provide. I have no
argument against it. It's just not for everyone.

She and my brother-in-law talk about how exciting it will be for
my family to go abroad, but how they could never do it. I see why,
and it isn't sad at all. We have chosen vastly different paths and
both are thrilling in their own way.

~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~

At the reunion itself we had a few fun surprises:

 - My neice found out her science partner in school last year was
   actually her long lost cousin. If I have my math right, they're
   4th cousin's once removed, but it is a little tricky...

 - My great, great grandfather was married twice. The daughter
   from his first marriage married the brother of his second wife.
   Go ahead and unpack that a little while. I'll wait.

 - My cousin is the production manager for Hamilton on Broadway!

 - My 98 year old grandpa has been listening to the same GE radio
   for 50 years. It still works perfectly. Ridiculous.

 - I'm related to pretty much the entire town of Lowellville,
   Ohio. Here's a video from the 30s and 40s of the town
   celebrating a wedding in the 30s and the Feast of Our Lady of
   Mt Carmel (July 16th, 1946)[0]. I watched this with my grandpa
   and he named pretty much everyone in here at a glance. The guy
   with the suave hair at 13:13 is my great uncle, my grandpa's
   brother. He was a funny guy.

[0] Lowellville Ohio
    http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FMlhECYsxno

 - The best part of the parade is the Baby Doll Dance [1]

[1] Baby Doll Dance
    http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8xyZRLwZSkU#t=1m
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
