<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Sprezzatura</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181018-sprezzatura/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sprezzatura
October 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Castiglione wrote The Book of the Courtier between 1508 and 1528.
It's a fantastic read, if you've never tried it before. In the
book he introduces a newly created word: sprezzatura, defined as -

  "I have found quite a universal rule which in this matter seems
  to me valid above all other, and in all human affairs whether in
  word or deed: and that is to avoid affectation in every way
  possible as though it were some rough and dangerous reef; and
  (to pronounce a new word perhaps) to practice in all things
  a certain sprezzatura [nonchalance], so as to conceal all art
  and make whatever is done or said appear to be without effort
  and almost without any thought about it."

It defined the ultimate goal of the courtiers at the court of
Urbino. Look amazing at everything without trying.

Ever since reading the book in high school that has been my
personal motto. Even mentioning it "out loud" here in gopher
undermines the effort somewhat. Talking about trying to be awesome
at everything and seem effortless ... you get where I'm going with
this.

Anyway, I wanted to mention it for two reasons:

1) When I was thinking of a show for anonradio, my first idea
   centered around sprezzatura, but I couldn't come up with a way
   to make it a thing without also completely destroying that
   thing. It's tricky! Try it in your head.

2) Some people these days are all too eager to "own" their
   failings. There's a pride in being bad at stuff. It's probably
   a generational thing. Showing vulnerability is cool as shit, or
   something. I'm drunk and an old man when it comes to this
   stuff. I'm of the opinion that if you can be a total badass at
   every fucking thing, then you should be a badass at every
   fucking thing. If you're a badass at 90% of the things, then
   focus and fix that last 10% in the quiet of your bedroom until
   you can be a rockstar there too.

That's it. The whole point of this was to tell you all to go be
badass at everything. Not good at something? Don't tell me about
it. Go fix it. No.. don't fix it, master it. Master the heck out
of that thing and then do it routinely as if it's no big deal.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading Plain Text</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-reading-plain-text/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reading plain text
October 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

While reading moji's phlog [0] I started considering how I read on
gopher, or in plain text in general versus my methods on the web.
Certainly I do more scanning in a web browser, which I attribute
at least partially to the various font and style treatments that
both allow for and promote the bite-sized ingestion of content.
There is also an element of reading fatigue that plays out
differently here in plain text, and thats where my mind went (not
to say that moji was in any way tiring).

When I'm tired of reading on gopher it is instantly apparent.
I skim over blocks of text looking for something to jump out at
me, but that isnt how it works. Warning claxxons blare in my brain
and I shut down figuratively and literally. It's clear I need to
do something else and come back later. I get no such signal on the
web. I peruse long past the point of usefulness. I trade reading
for browsing. Surfing becomes skimming. Infinite scroll is
infinitely useless.

My time in text is short and productive in the sense that I get
something from it, whether information or entertainment. My time
on the web offers sone of that, but the trappings are extreme and
it is all too easy to give more time than necessary or helpful.

This is intentional. Capitalism demands attention, and it is that
monstrosity which guides the design patterns on port 80. Even
informational sites follow the patterns because that is what
drives engagement. Look at the analytics, measure your performance
goals. How do we keep them longer? How do we show them more ads?
How do we get them to spend a little more?

I'm sick of environmental leeches. I want my landscapes clear and
clean. Mow down the billboards and flashing neon and let me get
where I'm going on my own terms, please.

There is no way out on the web. The experience is condemned to
these patterns. People scream when you try to pull that bandage
off. They demand more convenience despite the cost. The masses
want to live like this. We're the weirdos for questioning it.

[0] moji - unlearning
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~moji/phlog/20180928-unlearning.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Little Free Library Part 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-little-free-library-part-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Little Free Library, part 1
October 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Below is a list of notes I've prepared while building my little
free ebook library. What is that, you ask? Well, it's a solar
powered rapsberry pi zero w that will live off-grid with an open
wifi access point. When a user connects to it, Captive Portal will
automatically trigger a "sign-in" page. The page isn't meant to
sign into anything, though. Instead it will present users with
free ebooks for download to their devices! 

My first go will likely be a collection of PDF maps from USGS,
some trail guides and bird identification things that are
appropriate for the trail that runs past my house.

My TODO list remains:
  
  - Test apple devices captive portal
  - Design a static site page to download the ebooks


# Starting from a raspbian lite install on a raspberry pi zero w:

# After setting up your local wifi connection in wpa_supplicant,
# then proceed to make your littlefreelibrary work when away from
# home...

# Update packages to prepare

$ sudo apt update
$ sudo apt upgrade -y

# Install dependencies, but disable by default

$ sudo apt install dnsmasq hostapd nginx -y
$ sudo systemctl disable hostapd
$ sudo systemctl disable dnsmasq

# Configure

$ sudo vi /etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf

    interface=wlan0
    driver=nl80211
    ssid=LittleFreeLibrary
    hw_mode=g
    channel=8
    wmm_enabled=0
    macaddr_acl=0
    auth_algs=1
    wpa=0
    ignore_broadcast_ssid=0
    country_code=US
    ieee80211n=1

$ sudo vi /etc/default/hostapd

    DAEMON_CONF="/etc/hostapd/hostapd.conf" # change only this line

$ sudo vi /etc/dnsmasq.conf # add the following to the end of file

    bogus_priv
    addrdess=/#/10.0.0.5
    interface=wlan0
    no-resolv
    bind-interfaces
    dhcp-range=10.0.0.50,10.0.0.100,12h

$ sudo vi /etc/dchcpd.conf # add the following to the end of file

    nohook wpa_supplicant

$ sudo vi /etc/systemd/system/autohotspot.service

    [Unit]
    Description=Automatically generate an internet Hotspot when a valid ssid is not in range
    After=multi-user.target
    [Service]
    Type=oneshot
    RemainAfterExit=yes
    ExecStart=/usr/bin/autohotspot
    [Install]
    WantedBy=multi-user.target

$ sudo systemctl enable autohotspot.service

$ curl http://www.raspberryconnect.com/images/Autohotspot/autohotspot-95-4/autohotspot.txt > autohotspot
$ chmod 755 autohotspot
$ sudo mv autohotspot /usr/bin/autohotspot

# Change hostname to littlefreelibrary

$ sudo hostname littlefreelibrary
$ sudo vi /etc/hostname

    littlefreelibrary

$ sudo vi /etc/hosts

    127.0.0.1 littlefreelibrary

# Set up a cron to detect changes

$ crontab -e # add the following to the end of file

    */5 * * * * sudo /usr/bin/autohotspot >/dev/null 2>&1

# Set up nginx to work with captive portal

$ sudo vi /etc/nginx/sites-available/default

    server {
            listen 80 default_server;
            listen [::]:80 default_server;
            root /var/www/html;
            index index.html;
            server_name _;

            # For iOS
            if ($http_user_agent ~* (CaptiveNetworkSupport) ) {
                    return 302 http://littlefreelibrary.local/apple.html;
            }

            # For Android
            location /generate_204 {
                    return 302 http://littlefreelibrary.local/index.html;
            }

            location / {
                    try_files $uri $uri/ /index.html;
            }
    }

$ sudo service nginx restart

# Add apple captive portal page

$ sudo vi /var/www/html/apple.html

    <!--
    <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <WISPAccessGatewayParam xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.wballiance.net/wispr_2_0.xsd">
    <Redirect>
    <MessageType>100</MessageType>
    <ResponseCode>0</ResponseCode>
    <VersionHigh>2.0</VersionHigh>
    <VersionLow>1.0</VersionLow>
    <AccessProcedure>1.0</AccessProcedure>
    <AccessLocation>LittleFreeLibrary</AccessLocation>
    <LocationName>LittleFreeLibrary</LocationName>
    <LoginURL>http://littlefreelibrary.local/index.html</LoginURL>
    </Redirect>
    </WISPAccessGatewayParam>
    -->

# Create your library page

$ sudo vi /var/www/html/index.html

    TBD HTML code

# To manage device when in AP mode

$ ssh pi@10.0.0.5
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bug Out Bag</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181012-bug-out-bag/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Bug-Out Bag
October 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I promised that I would revisit my current bug-out bag and here
I am to follow through. Much of this was first outlined on my web
blog and the gear remains much the same. I've augmented some
things, added some new stuff, cut back on others. Let's dive in!

                  ________         ___
                 /_  __/ /  ___   / _ )___ ____ _
                  / / / _ \/ -_) / _  / _ `/ _ `/
                 /_/ /_//_/\__/ /____/\_,_/\_, /
                                          /___/

Somewhere along the way I scored a free ign.com branded gym bag.
It's made of a heavy duty material and almost feels like a bag for
a bowling ball. It holds everyhing on the list below (just
barely). There may be a time to come where I'll need to upgrade.
I'm considering moving to a pelican case for added protection, but
it will also add to the weight.


                     __  ___       ____    _ __
                    /  |/  /__ ___/ / /__ (_) /_
                   / /|_/ / -_) _  /  '_// / __/
                  /_/  /_/\__/\_,_/_/\_\/_/\__/


Why have one when you can have two (or 11)? I have the most
redundency in my medical kit selection.

- Swiss Safe Premium First Aid 200 Piece

  This thing has a lot of the basics: cotton swabs, bandages,
  alcohol wipes, antiseptic wipes, sting relief pads, PVC gloves,
  tape, moleskin, scissors, CPR facemask, a trauma pad, emergency
  whistle, compass, sewing kit, and so on. This is a base-line for
  first aid. It also has a little first aid guide in there, though
  I have a better one.

- Emergency First Aid - A Pocket Naturalist Guide

  This is a folded, waterproof pamphlet outlining the basics on
  a number of first aid scenarios. Primary responses to water
  hazards, vehicle accidents, lightning, leaking gas or smoke,
  rescue breathing, CPR, choking, shock, eye injury, burns,
  poisoning... you get the idea. It packs a lot of info into
  a very small space. While I am comfortable in pretty much
  everything on the list, my wife isn't and neither is my son. If
  something were to happen and I were not around or incapacitated,
  I can trust that they have access to the basic info.

- ZET Rapid Spinning Tourniquet

  I squeeze this little guy inside the Swiss Safe kit to save on
  space. Hoping I won't need it.

- MTM Survivor Dry Box with O-Ring Seal

  My secondary and more serious medical kit all sits within the
  nearly indestructable and completely waterproof MTM case. Pretty
  hardcore? Not yet! Inside the MTM are three Otterbox 1000 Series
  Waterproof Cases, also waterproof and nearly indestructable on
  their own. It is inside these three cases that I keep the
  contents of...

- Medique 40061 First Aid Kit, 61-Piece

  Another fantastic assortment of medical thingies! Much like the
  first list, it sports an impressive array. But it's not enough
  on its own. Also in the MTM Dry Box with it is...

- Adventure Medical Kits Trauma Packwith QuikClot

  For everything up to and including gaping chest wounds from
  gunshots. Nice right?

- Quake Kare Emergency Thermal Blankets (4 Pack)

  A lot of serious medical injury is compounded by exposure. These
  can help in a pinch. 

- Potable aqua iodine for water treatment

  I used to consider this part of the water kit, but I've
  supplimented that elsewhere. This is more of the "oh shit" water
  treatment, which in my head belongs in the medkit for reasons.

Were you paying attention? All that fits into two containers!

                     _      __     __
                    | | /| / /__ _/ /____ ____
                    | |/ |/ / _ `/ __/ -_) __/
                    |__/|__/\_,_/\__/\__/_/

- waterBOB Emergency Drinking Water Storage

  I love this thing. It's basically a giant, heavy-duty plastic
  bag with some access ports and pump areas that is designed to
  sit in your bathtub. You fill it up when the power goes out
  before water pressure drops. It can hold over a hundred gallons,
  which is like 375 liters or so. That's a nice backup!

- Lifestraw (3 pack)

  These things are engineering miracles. The company has some
  seriously good cred with their work in Africa too. If you're not
  familiar with it, it's a tube about the size of a relay baton.
  You stick one end in water--pretty much any water--and just
  drink out of the other end. It filters amazingly well and lasts
  over 5 years in regular use. The shelf-life is pretty much
  forever before first use, so they're great for a bag of this
  sort.

See, I told you I had something better than iodine.

                       ______          __
                      /_  __/__  ___  / /__
                       / / / _ \/ _ \/ (_-<
                      /_/  \___/\___/_/___/


- Hand Axe / Hatchet

  If your kit needs to help you out past a day or two, being able
  to work with the natural resources around you is imperitive.
  Chop up some downed branches for a fire. Clear a space for your
  family. Make some posts for hanging a trash bag (instant trash
  bin). Be creative and live in outdoor luxury with this.

- Chainmate CM-24SSP 24-Inch Survival Pocket Chain Saw With Pouch

  If you find yourself working with tough wood that needs
  clearing, having the right tools makes all the difference. Your
  hatchet can do a lot, but sometimes its nice to have a saw too.
  This thing is tiny and super light. Add it to the bag and then
  hope you don’t need it.

- ADC Medicut Shears, 7-1⁄4”

  Most scissors are weak and useless when it comes to anything
  other than wrapping paper. These things have some real power,
  and they’ll get the job done again and again. You can even
  sharpen them! I'd put this on the medical list, but their
  utility goes way beyond that. Besides, I have a dedicated
  medical set inside the waterproof box that I didn't even mention
  because they're so small and insignificant. There's tongue
  depressors in there too. You don't need to know everything!

- Entrenching Tool

  My advice for survival scenarios: Learn how to make a latrine.
  Seriously. It’ll take you five minutes to watch a video on
  youtube and it will make your outdoor living much, much easier.

- Folding Camp Saw  

  Another backup for your chainsaw. Or maybe the chainsaw is the
  backup. If you’re going to stay outdoors for any length of time,
  bring a saw.

- Mora Sweden Classic #1 Red Wood Handle Carbon Steel Knife

  Very few knives are better than this one. At 15$, you can afford
  to get extras too. Treat them well: sharpened, oiled, not
  chipped. They’ll last a lifetime.

               ______        __      _     _ __
              / __/ /__ ____/ /_____(_)___(_) /___ __
             / _// / -_) __/ __/ __/ / __/ / __/ // /
            /___/_/\__/\__/\__/_/ /_/\__/_/\__/\_, /
                                              /___/


I'm all about roughing it, but even so it's good to have a few
items that use POWER. Sometimes you need to see at night, or know
what's going on with the weather.

- Etón FR160R Microlink Self-Powered AM/FM/NOAA Weather Radio with
  Flashlight, Solar Power and Cell Phone Charger (Red)

  This thing is a beast. I charged it with the hand crank for just
  over ten seconds and then sat listening to the radio all day
  long. If you plan on staying in touch with the outside world (or
  at least informed), having a backup radio with NOAA stations is
  important. Besides, this little guy will charge your cellphone
  too! 
  
- Petzl E97 Tikka Plus 2 Headlamp

  In the redundency department, along with your knives, add light
  to the list. A headlamp will keep your hands free to do work.
  They last a really long time with LEDs.

- Gerber Infinity Ultra Task Light

  Bring a flashlight, but not one with huge, honkin’ D batteries.
  They’re harder to find replacements than AA, and much heavier.

             ___                               _
            / _ |___________ ___ ___ ___  ____(_)__ ___
           / __ / __/ __/ -_|_-<(_-</ _ \/ __/ / -_|_-<
          /_/ |_\__/\__/\__/___/___/\___/_/ /_/\__/___/


- Rothco 550lb. Type III Nylon Paracord

  I’m an Eagle Scout, and thus I never feel lost if I have a good
  length of rope. Paracord is extremely strong for its size, but
  it packs down light and tight. Use it for everything and
  everything from a clothesline to animal traps in the worst of
  situations. 

- Other Paracord

  I got a handful of free paracord bracelets at some festival and
  tossed them in the bag. A little extra rope never hurts.
  
- Size #36 Dyed Black & Tarred Twine, 1lb

  This is work-horse line. The other stuff is special and high
  quality. When you just need to tie something up, this is what
  you use. It lasts well with a tensile strength of 320lbs.

- 3M Scotch Heavy Duty All-Weather Duct Tape

  Don’t settle for the cheap duct tape. Get the good outdoor
  all-weather stuff. One roll should be more than enough to patch
  things up, bandage you up, make a stretcher, or any number of
  other tasks. 
  
- Smith’s PP1 Pocket Pal Multifunction Sharpener

  A dull knife is almost as bad as no knife. If you’re going to be
  using them… really using them, keep them sharp. This will also
  help you in cases of accidental cuts. A clean cut heals much
  faster and with less chance of infection.

- Youngstown Glove General Utility Lined with KEVLAR Glove

  The most common place to injure yourself working in survival
  situations is on your hands. Protect them with more than a pair
  of designer cotton gloves. These guys have Kevlar on the insides
  and outsides of your hands. Fantastic, and worth the price. Test
  them out with some yard work and you’ll see what I mean.

                         ____             __
                        / __/__  ___  ___/ /
                       / _// _ \/ _ \/ _  /
                      /_/  \___/\___/\_,_/


I used to keep MREs and other rations in my bag, but that became
a hassle to keep in good condition. Instead, I have some gear that
will help me find food when I need it.

- Improvised Trapping - Pathfinder Outdoor Survival Guide

  Another waterproof pamphlet that outlines how to build snares
  and deadfall traps, how to gut & clean small game and fish, and
  other necessary info for basic food prep. It even shows how to
  dry meat for long-term storage. I love these guides. There's one
  on Mushrooms that I'm eyeing up.

- Spectra® Braided Cord 1050lb test - Heavy Duty Speargun Line

  This cord is great for any number of uses, but it is in the kit
  especially for hanging a bear-bag. I use the PCT method myself,
  so I have the tools to fit it. In a pinch, though, you can get
  away with just a bag and line. Wildlife have incredible senses
  of smells. Remember, if you are outside, you don’t have walls
  keeping your food and gear safe. Be wary and hang your food.

  This line is also great for setting snares and traps. It's
  extremely thin & strong, a great combo.

- Stuff Sacks (Bear Bag, etc)

  To go along with the line above, these stuff sacks from zpacks
  are wonderful. They weigh almost nothing and are very sturdy.

- Solo Stove

  This little wood burner is a beast. Go check out a youtube video
  or something. They're amazing and cheap for what they offer.
  I hate holding on to gas. It's dangerous and hard to get more.
  Wood is plentiful.

- Some other generic metal frame stove thing

  I'm not sure where I got it, but it's two half-round pieces of
  metal that intersect and form a platform to hold a pot. You
  build a fire in it or drop some embers in there and you're set.
  I don't use it that way most of the time. Instead, I use it as
  a wind-screen for the solo stove. It's wide enough to encircle
  the whole thing. Neat, right?

                         __  ___
                        /  |/  /__ ____  ___
                       / /|_/ / _ `/ _ \(_-<
                      /_/  /_/\_,_/ .__/___/
                                 /_/


I touched on this in an earlier phlog [0], but maps are an often
overlooked part of a survival bag. I use the 7.5 minute maps from
USGS as well as a fantastic survey series of my county. I keep
these all in a transparent waterproof map case. I guess I'll have
to look around for new ones of Iceland pretty soon, though.

               _  __     __    _        ___
              / |/ /__  / /_  (_)__    / _ )___ ____ _
             /    / _ \/ __/ / / _ \  / _  / _ `/ _ `/
            /_/|_/\___/\__/ /_/_//_/ /____/\_,_/\_, /
                                               /___/

All of the things mentioned live in that ign.com gym bag, as
I mentioned, but that doesn't represent all of my bug-out stuff.
In an immediate emergency that is indeed what I grab and take out
the door. 

In fact, a few months ago our Carbon Monoxide alarm sounded at two
in the morning. We jumped out of bed, grabbed the kid, grabbed the
bag and went out to the car. I called emergency services from
there and they came and cleared the house. (Note: carbon monoxide
detectors accumulate CO over time, weakening their ability to
identify a "spike" in the gas. It's important to replace them
every few years.)

In addition to the bag I grabbed, I also have a toolbag in the
back of my car that's always present. It has some extra helpful
tools, camping gear, etc. I keep it all in a well-waxed canvas
bag. There's more rope, another wood-fire stove, blades, saws,
car-tools, and so on. If it weren't late and if I were wearing
pants I'd go grab the bag and do an inventory here. I also keep
two fleece blankets and a fantastic quality 100% wool blanket from
Hudson Bay Company in the back of the car. Exposure kills.

Upstairs in my house is my backpacking/camping gear:

- Jacks-R-Better Sierra Sniveler

  I have horrible restless leg syndrome, and most sleeping bags
  feel like a coffin to me. A nice power-down quilt gives me the
  warmth I need at night without the restrictive footbox. Pick
  whatever works for you. The single most dangerous thing when you
  are forced to sleep outside is exposure. You will die from
  exposure in a single night. Make sure you have good shelter
  before you even worry about water or food.

- Z Lite Mattress

  Sleeping on the ground can be rough. Go easy on your back with
  a little layer. More importantly, get some insulation between
  your body and the ground. The earth will suck the heat right out
  of you.

- Snow Peak Ti-Mini Solo Combo Cook Set

  Have something to heat up water. In survival situations, many
  times “cooking” literally means, “add hot water”. Heat to
  purify. Heat to rehydrate. Heat!

- Snow Peak Ti-Double H600 Stacking Mug

  This mug stacks nicely with the cookset above, so I have a pot
  for heating the water, and a cup for eating. It keeps my cooking
  pot clean.

- Bibler Tempest Tent (4-season)

  There’s a lot of ways to make a shelter outdoors. This is
  a pretty hardcore 4-season lightweight tent. It’s not the
  cheapest solution, nor the best in all situations. I use it for
  a variety of camping conditions outside of my emergency kit. If
  you aren’t much of an outdoorsman, there’s probably a better
  shelter for you. Ask around at Gander Mtn or REI, or bug your
  local scouts when they try to sell you popcorn.

- Gossamer Gear Mariposa Ultralight Backpack

  I adore this bag. It's so light weight it feels like nothing at
  all. The padding and supports are great and it has a huge number
  of ways to distribute weight. Just brilliant.

There's other stuff in there too. I line the inside of my bag with
plastic to isolate dry stuff from wet. There's some other
fancy-schmancy gear I could go into, but it's all meant for
camping, not survival. Still, I wanted to mention that I have it
around. If the emergency provides a bit more planning all of that
gets bundled up too. If we will take the car, then the cast iron
stuff is coming with me, especially the dutch oven. If we're
running from zombies, I'll probably leave the weight behind.

   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   -   

That was a lot to cover, and I feel like I must be forgeting about
something important. Clothes? Solar panels? Probably some of that
stuff. Regardless, it's a nice reference to have out there in
gopherspace. 

What do you have in your bag?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Another Sdf Hiccup</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181012-another-sdf-hiccup/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Another sdf hiccup?
October 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

It looks like gopher.club isn't resolving again. SDF.org is
showing up. It's usually the other way around when it comes to
gopher. I'm sick of switching the phlogroll back and forth. I'm
going to leave things as they are for now and hope it resolves
itself in the next day or two. If you notice your phlog not
updating for a while, send me a note and I'll try to work around
it.

Also, welcome to a few new phloggers on the roll!

inpefess
    gopher://boris.shminke.me/1/
bradfonseca
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/bradfonseca/

Some good content brewing there!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Maps</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181007-maps/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Maps
October 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I intend to do a longer phlog soon with an update on my bug-out
bag and other emergency preparations, but in the meantime I wanted
to highlight one thing I value that many people probably overlook.
In the United States the USGS provides extremely detailed and well
maintained maps for free (digital) or cheap (print) covering
pretty much every inch of the country. The most popular of these
maps are the 7.5 minute stretches, which cover about 64 square
miles in each one. Here's the one that covers my house [0]!

[0] 7.5 Minute Map (large file warning)
    http://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/StagedProducts/Maps/USTopo/PDF/NJ/NJ_Trenton_West_20161025_TM_geo.pdf

In addition, I also have a map of the full county with topographic
information and water systems clearly labeled. I keep both of
these in a waterproof map case in my bag. I have a road atlas in
my car for the whole country, but around home there may be need to
understand the land more intimately in case of emergency. 

In short, maps are cool.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Restored</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181004-restored/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Restored
October 04th, 2018
----------------------------------------

The restoration of gopher.black was quite eventful with some
absolutely awful computer drama. If you care about such things,
here's a recap:

I have a few raspberry pis, model 3s and some zero Ws. One of them
has this sick metal case with a fan. It's a beast. Used that
hardware for gopher.black along with a 64gb micro sd card. The
only problem is, the fan sucks (or blows?). It has always been
really noisy, and it eventually pissed me off enough to do
something about it. Since the pis don't run hot anyway, I figured
it was unnecessary. But before I removed it completely I figured
I'd try lubricating it just in case that solved things.

It didn't.

So I opened the case up, ripped that bad boy out, and plugged her
back in. Only this time, something was wrong. I was up and
running, but the system was in read-only mode. Uh, oh! I decided
to reboot and try again. This time, even worse... no boot.
I plugged in an HDMI monitor to watch the boot sequence and it
sprawled a bunch of messages about read-only crap. A quick google
revealed that my SD card was likely at fault. It was going bad.
I assume it was related to me opening the thing up and closing it
a few times. I must have bumped it badly.

If the card was read-only, I figured I could still read it to get
an image. I did some dd magic and backed it up. Today I got a new
64GB sd card in the mail. I dd'd my backup onto that and plugged
it in but nothing happened. Not even a failed boot. Just nada.

I thought... Lets make sure it's the SD card! So I swapped my SD
card from my pi-hole and gopher.black into the other hardware and
confirmed... definitely the SD. I had to roll back to an earlier
backup. 

The most recent I had was from June (yuck). Luckily, 90% of the
crap on gopher.black is in git, so it's just a matter of updating
from repos after restoring things. I smiled to myself at my own
awesome and went over to my PC which houses the older backups.
I plugged in my new SD card, opened up Etcher to image it from the
backup and POOF, the MOTHERFUCKING drive hosting my backups
decided that it was the perfect moment to disappear!

Fast forward a bit to me restoring that drive from ITS backup,
eventually restoring my SD card from the old backup, plugging
things into the pi, booting it up, and we're back in business.

Things that still suck:
- Moku Pona is running again, but pretty much EVERYTHING updated
  since June, so the most recent phlogs is kinda a mess. It'll
  sort itself out in the days to come.
- All my web certs expired. I'm renewing them again now via
  acme.sh.
- Weechat's sec.conf does something weird. It doesn't know my
  master password. I have no idea what logic it uses, but this is
  the second time that's happened to me in a week. I appreciate
  that it externalizes passwords, but that's just BS. I'm better
  off typing them in each time I connect. It's not like I do it
  very often.
- Probably other stuff... I don't really recall everything I did
  on gopher.black over the last couple months. I'm sure most of it
  was content, but maybe there was something else that was super
  cool and I totally forgot. Meh, we'll make due.

If you notice anything wonky on my stuff in the next couple days,
hit me up.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Oops</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181001-oops/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Oops!
October 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

You might not be reading this right now unless you are checking
out one of my mirrors on SDF.org or tilde.town. That's because
I accidentally blew up gopher.black. OHNOES!

I was getting annoyed at the buzzing from the fan on my pi's case.
I opened it up and tried spraying it with a little lubricant, but
it didn't make a difference in the sound. So, what the hell, I'll
just pull it out. Unfortunately, in the process my jostling of the
SD card put it into read-only mode and now nothing works.

Since the card is still readable I'm dding it down to a backup.
I've got a new SD card ordered from Amazon and it should be here
by Wednesday. I'll restore, plug that bad-boy in, and hopefully
everything will be right as rain. If not, I've got 3 extra
raspberry pi's lying around that can happily become the next
gopher.black. I've got the data, I've got redundant hardware. This
shouldn't be too bad.

Still... derp.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sdf Gopher Servers</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180929-sdf-gopher-servers/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sdf gopher servers
September 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

As many of you are aware, sdf.org recently performed some
upgrading which somehow disrupted their gopher servers. As
a result, everything reverted to being run off bucktooth instead
of gophernicus. After a bunch of prodding on bboard, sdf.org was
reverted to gophernicus, but a very out-of-date version.
Gopher.club, the preferred DNS mirror of SDF for gopher according
to its tutorials, is still left using bucktooth.

There's a few painful parts to this. A few of the more active
gopher users hosting on SDF were actively using the cgi script
features of gophernicus which were not a part of bucktooth's
offering. As a result, some of their gopher holes failed to load
at all, or loaded incorrectly. Second, the constant changes in
server info means that our aggregators keep triggering as if
everyone on SDF posted new content. I know this has been
a challenge for logout [0] whose Bongusta! [1] aggregator has been
affected. It's also affected my moku-pona listings [2]. 

As a result, for the time being I have reverted all SDF
gopherholes to using the sdf.org domain instead of gopher.club in
my listings. This way they will display correctly at least. Sadly,
gophernicus outputs server information in a footer of gophermaps,
so it will likely continue to trigger the mass-update phenomenon
whenever NetBSD or gophernicus itself are updated. I think we've
all learned to work around this by now, though.

Finally, I've posted about all this on the sdf.org bboard in
a single requests post. I'm hopeful that seeing it all clearly
outlined will help the admins update gophernicus to the latest
version and get gopher.club back in line. Time will tell! If you
continue to see mass-updates on the aggregators I apologize, but
there's limited control unless I go through manually to clean
everything up each time (like logout does). It'll settle down
eventually.

[0] logout
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/
[1] Bongusta
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/en/bongusta/
[2] Phlog Roll
    gopher://gopher.black/1/moku-pona

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enforced Anonymity</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180924-enforced-anonymity/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Enforced anonymity
September 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Gopher has been filled with threads on the topic of anonymity [0],
but I want to take a different tack. There's a storm brewing in
the form of Codes of Conduct for online communities. I have
OPINIONS on these things, and the only appropriate place for
opinion on the internet is hidden in dead protocols.

Codes of Conduct attempt to accomplish a GOOD. They attempt to
ensure that individuals are not exposed to unfair prejudice. This
is a movement toward equality, which it itself is also a GOOD. (I
have argued in the past that I prefer liberty over equality, but
that is not a comparison of good vs bad, but rather a personal
stance on which is a greater good.) So far, we're all good here.

Codes of Conduct are also weapons. They are wielded by the
oppressed and marginalized with a powerful blow aimed at those
they feel have transgressed. Is this a GOOD? Providing
a reciprocal power dynamic is an expression of vengeance, not of
justice. It does not guarantee liberty or equality. It guarantees
a shifted power-base and a new set of mores to be navigated, or
else. This is not good. This is bad.

Hold off on the pitchforks. Go re-read the second paragraph again
if you're getting steamy at me.

If you're sitting there feeling like a Code of Conduct is a vital
tool in your arsenal as an objectified person, a minority, or
other disenfranchised group member, I can totally understand why.
It's good to not be shit upon or taken advantage of. But at the
same time, role reversal perpetuates a never-ending cycle of
anger. "It's our turn," is the voice of a failed morality. It may
feel good, but it gives no high ground and it leads to more
suffering for more people.

(I'm skirting around going into some deeper ethics talk on the one
hand, or going off into sci-fi territory and making a bunch of
Dune parallels, but I'm going to leave it alone and get to the
point instead).

"So what, tomasino? If Codes of Conduct aren't the answer, what do
you think we should do?"

Thanks for asking! First, I don't believe it is a necessity for
a criticism to offer an alternative solution. It is okay to point
out that something is wrong but not have a better alternative
prepared. And guess what? I don't! I have a ridiculous alternative
that we most definitely SHOULD NOT DO. I'm going to share it with
you as a thought exercise.

Here's my idea: 100% enforcement of anonymity. Boom! Meritocracy
blind to identity politics can only be 100% guaranteed if there is
no identity to politic. Go ahead and create your company, your
online group. Share your code, grab commits and share and merge
and whatever else technocrats do. But... no signatures. No names.
No personal sharing. You want an online identity, grab a number,
or we'll pull a string of dictionary words and assign them to you.

Now everyone is safe, has an equal voice and can be judged by
their own contributions. You want a code of conduct in the mix?
I got you covered. It's got 2 rules:

1) If you share your identity, or provide information that
   establishes a personal identity with the community, you're out.
2) If you share another person's identity or personal details
   about them, you're out.

This magical, mystical utopia actually sounds good to some people,
I'm sure. But it's not. It overlooks the beauty of human
interactions and the infinite possibilities for the advancement of
our species. It's an act of fear. Don't do it. Seriously, please
don't do it. Also, cool it with the Codes of Conduct. Protect
people, don't burn them.

And yes, Linus is an ass.


[0] I was really going to go look these up, but then I got
distracted. Take my word for it. There were a lot of posts on the
subject earlier this year.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
