<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Green Energy In Iceland</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200218-green-energy-in-iceland/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Green Energy in Iceland
February 18th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I don't complain about many things in Iceland because, frankly,
there aren't a whole lot of things to complain about. By almost
every measure, life here is superior to the United States. In
fact, the thing I'm about to complain about in this phlog is
nitpicking. The situation in the United States is worse, frankly.

What I'm talking about in green power, or carbon neutral power, or
sustainable energy, or whatever else you want to call it. You may
be aware that Iceland's grid is pretty much 100% renewable energy.
Put a period there at the end of that sentence and things feel
pretty damn good. The island has rich resources in terms of
hydroelectric power, geothermal power, and wind. You can read all
about it on this site [0].

Why Iceland - Competitively Priced Green Energy
    https://www.invest.is/why-iceland/competitively-priced-green-energy

So what's the problem then? Two things. I'll call one the lesser
evil and the other one the great lie.


The Lesser Evil

Power distribution in Iceland is not balanced between individuals
and corporations. The rates are different, their power channels
are different, and their use and the care with which is is taken
is different. In short, companies can get away with some shady
stuff. 

Is it as bad as the US? Oh hell no. After all, we're not dumping
toxic coal ash into major waterways or anything [1] here. 

Duke Energy Coal Ash in North Carolina
    https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article238898708.html

Even so, there's some ecological impact at stake, and a misuse or
unbalanced use of public resources that favors large capitalist
enterprise without paying back into the local economy. I could go
into more detail here, but I'm just gonna leave it vague because
I really want to focus on...


The Great Lie

Iceland sells its green resources as credits that companies can
pay for to offset their own polluting behavior. If a shitty
polluter like Duke Energy wants to seem cleaner, they can pay
Iceland and claim the renewable energy as their own despite not
using it. This lowers Iceland's real contribution to the Earth in
a major way, all but removing it as a good from the world because
it allows these other companies to continue their damage while
claiming to be better.

It's a short term gain for a country that was recently in
a financial crisis. What a great way to bring in extra funds for
doing nothing, right? Except it does have a major cost to the
world as a whole.

Is this worse than what the US is doing? Well, no. The US is
actively polluting and subsidising fossil fuel industries. But
that doesn't give Iceland a pass. This country has pinned its
reputation in the world as a Green Nation while it makes back-room
deals to sell off the fruits of that labor at the cost of our
future. There are many MPs here who are working on this and
a number of other issues. Fundamental to all of these efforts is
the new constitution that was passed by public referendum years
ago but has not been ratified by the alþingi, our parliament. It's
a powerful document that returns natural resources to the public
and out of the hands of a small number of oligarchs. You can see
why it hasn't happened yet right there.

The people all want it. Many MPs want it. It will happen. These
petty corruptions that take advantage of the fisheries, of the
power systems, of plundering the Namibian fishing quotas [2], they
will all be outed. We'll get there.

Icelandic Fishing Company Engaged In Bribery, Tax Evasion, Plundering African Resources
    https://grapevine.is/news/2019/11/13/icelandic-fishing-company-engaged-in-bribery-tax-evasion-plundering-african-resources/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>I Don T Give A Damn</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200212-i-don-t-give-a-damn/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
I don't give a damn
February 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I saw some posts on HN recently in the style of "Why I quit
working at Google" or "Lessons from a former Facebook Engineer".
These things pop up pretty frequently and I'd like to share my
opinion with this hidden corner of the internet that I don't give
a damn. More than that, I find the entire situation that feeds the
ego of these people despicable. Your having worked for an evil
(yes, evil) company does not put you into a special category that
warrants extra attention. It does not prove you are on some higher
level of computing prowess, for I know so many world class
intellects who know better than to soil themselves at one of these
behemoths.

So yeah, I don't give a damn.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Repair</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200203-repair/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
repair
February 03rd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Jan posted recently [0] about the awesomeness of fixing stuff. It
was timely for me since I've been on a bit of a repair renaissance
here. 

[0] jan - on fixing stuff
    gopher://jan.bio/1/phlog/20200131-on-fixing-stuff

When we moved to Iceland I knew it was going to be problematic
finding some things, especially specialty parts and quality goods.
In the midst of that dawning situation I was also staring at my
hobbies filling multiple rooms, offices, the basement and garage.
We were moving from a very large 5-bedroom home to a cozy
apartment. If I wanted to keep active on a hobby, I thought, then
it should serve a purpose and fit in our space.

I love waterproof, locking, stackable containers. I have a bunch
of the 20 gallon ones that we use in the move and in storage (no
worries about flooding!). I have smaller ones that stack and sit
on an industrial metal shelf beside my office desk. In each of
these containers is a hobby. That's the space I give them,
generally. Flutes all fit in one with the music books. All my
electronics fit in another. All my spinning tools, accessories,
and fiber in a 3rd (the wheel itself is a special exception). Our
hand-tools and sharpening stones fit in a 4th. Everything in its
place.

I also debated on bringing my 3D printer to Iceland since it
seemed extraneous and extravagant, but later decided it would be
useful to 3-D print parts that were hard to source in-country.

So now that I've been living with this stuff for 7 months, how is
it working? Well, I've done more sewing by hand here in Iceland
than I did at home with a machine and a full room dedicated to it.
I'm constantly repairing the kid's clothes, creating stuffed
animals, toys, sleeves for tools, and so on. I 3D printed sturdy
handles for our shopping bags since we walk to-and-from the market
a kilometer twice a week. My wife's chromebook's touchpad stopped
working this week and I opened it all up, cleaned everything,
re-seated leads, and it's like new. I'm even spinning wool
regularly now!

Maintaining things is a joy. Fixing them up and not wasting money
on new things means more freedom from work. We can subsist on
lower incomes and spend more time enjoying life this way. The
world has less waste. My hobbyist yearnings are itched. Life is
good.

Now if I could find a reliable tabletop RPG group, life would be
perfect!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Film A Day And Other Mental Magic</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200116-a-film-a-day-and-other-mental-magic/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A Film A Day and other mental magic
January 16th, 2020
----------------------------------------

In the early days of the web I had a site called A Film A Day.
Why, oh, why, did the Internet Archive fail to archive it, I shall
never know. For about 5 years I kept up a practice of watching (on
average) one film per day and reviewing it. Of course I didn't
watch something every single day, so I'd bank by watching a few on
the weekends and so on. The important part wasn't getting my
yearly quota, though. I was on a mission to prove a point in an
argument I'd had at a diner.

                      Every movie is a
                      five star movie
                      if you watch it
                      the right way.

That was my angle, you see. My reviews weren't about giving
ratings to the films. It was all about figuring out how to watch
them to get the most enjoyment. I managed it, too! with a few
notable exceptions (no one can get 5 stars from Battlefield
Earth).

You need an example? Let's take the unfortunate film, Alien Vs.
Predator. What should have been a bloody affair was hamstrung by
a PG-13 rating and a setting so isolated in the arctic that
nothing really felt at stake. But... twist it in your mind and let
it become the greatest video game trailer of all time and entire
story now has purpose and drive.

Sometimes that's all it takes. Just tweak your mind a little bit
and see things from another angle and it's awesome! Other times it
takes much more work. 

I've been thinking on the Star Wars films and how I might approach
them so they're enjoyable. I think the best angle might be through
compassion. I imagine the filmmakers as a kid in high school who
adores this fandom. He eats up everything he can about the
theories and fan-fiction. He lives his life so deep in it that he
forgets there are casual fans. There are people who watched the
movies once and then moved on. There is no place left in his world
that hasn't been taken over with esoteric knowledge of this
imagined universe.

We feel a little sorry for that kid and wish he could enjoy
something else, something more. But we know, also, that he gets
such joy from this that we feel for him and want him to experience
it where he can.

And so, these other Star Wars movies are his. They are not part of
the series. They are not "real". The universe bestowed a gift upon
that nerd and let him use real actors and studios to produce his
opus of fandom. It is filled with false nostalgia and fan theories
jumbled up into a hodgepodge. It is not there to make sense. It is
not there to complete a great epic. It is a fulfillment of
a nerd's dream, and we can compassionately enjoy it with him.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
January 01st, 2020
----------------------------------------

I've got a little history [0,1] of making new years resolution
posts on this phlog. I suppose I'll continue the trend. Three
years in a row makes it a tradition, wouldn't you say?

[0] Resolution (2018)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
[1] Resolution (2019)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions

In 2018 I resolved that I'd try to avoid time traps and spend time
on things that matter. I picked up a few new hobbies and did
pretty well with the effort. In 2019 I taught the phlogosphere
about my buddy's ridiculous resolutions and said that it would be
the year I was impeached. While I didn't manage to get impeached,
at least someone did.

This year I haven't really been thinking about it much, so as the
fireworks go BANG in the background I'll do some real-time
pondering. Perhaps it might be a good opportunity to affect some
sort of ridiculous word usage, like 'whilst' or 'whomst'. That's
pretty saucy, but is it resolution material? What about something
more serious and purposeful, like de-googling completely. But one
of my contract gigs uses Google apps for everything, so that's
probably out. I could pick one of my hobbies, like yarn spinning,
and set a public goal. That might be good.

I should probably start with the silliness, though. Those come to
me more easily anyway. Lets see... what's something that would be
impossible for me but is definitely attainable by SOMEONE. Hmmm...
I've got it!

2020 will be the year Taylor Swift releases an album featuring ME!

Perfect. I'll just practice my hip-hop stylings by singing my own
name over the start of her songs. This is gonna be bangin'.

As for a real resolution, I could stand to burn some weight, pray
more, eat better, walk more. That's all a constant goal, though.
It doesn't need a special new year kickoff.

I think 2020 will borrow some sentiment from 2018 and a bit from
Dune. This will be the year of my Butlerian Jihad, if you will.
I don't want the computer to be my default place to hang out. As
much as I love you guys, it's an easy trap for me here in Iceland.
I don't need to work to inculturate, practice my language skills,
or any of that jazz. I am instantly connected to everyone and it's
too easy to let that fill my day.

So there it is, my 2020 Resolution is "Thou shalt not make
a machine in the likeness of a human mind". In this case I'll use
a (very) liberal interpretation of that to mean my own mind shall
not be trapped by machines. (Yeah, yeah, I know that's not what it
means. Shuddup!)

Never fear, dear gopherites. I still work on the computer and will
surely be around plenty even with this goal. It's inevitable.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/2019/</link>
  <pubdate></pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
2019-12-23 - webmentions and microsub
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191223-webmentions-and-microsub
2019-12-16 - poisoning the well
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191216-poisoning-the-well
2019-12-15 - QR codes
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191215-qr-codes
2019-12-15 - years of journaling
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191215-years-of-journaling
2019-11-15 - sdf minecraft question
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191115-sdf-minecraft-question
2019-11-15 - re: gopher resiliency
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191115-re-gopher-resiliency
2019-10-31 - nanowrimo 2019
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191031-nanowrimo-2019
2019-09-28 - Living as an RPG - Textbooks
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190928-living-as-an-rpg-textbooks
2019-09-23 - Banshee
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190923-banshee
2019-09-21 - AV-98 gopher proxy on gopher.black
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190921-av-98-gopher-proxy-on-gopher-black
2019-09-18 - av-98 and vf-1 daydream
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190918-av-98-and-vf-1-daydream
2019-09-18 - compassion is important
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190918-compassion-is-important
2019-09-06 - the apocrypha of cat - the desert
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190906-the-apocrypha-of-cat-the-desert
2019-09-02 - busses
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190902-busses
2019-09-01 - Hammer Time! (extended)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190901-hammer-time-extended
2019-08-27 - re: lambdalab - email thoughts
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190827-re-lambdalab-email-thoughts
2019-08-16 - music as milestone
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190816-music-as-milestone
2019-08-06 - Making VF-1 Sexy
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190806-making-vf-1-sexy
2019-07-29 - Gemini first impressions
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190729-gemini-first-impressions
2019-07-19 - zine
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190719-zine
2019-07-05 - Some replies from Iceland
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190705-some-replies-from-iceland
2019-06-15 - Nobody leaves without singing the blues
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190615-nobody-leaves-without-singing-the-blues
2019-06-07 - gopher 2.0
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190607-gopher-2-0
2019-06-05 - strike a pose
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190605-strike-a-pose
2019-06-01 - everything is evil
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190601-everything-is-evil
2019-05-29 - board games
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190529-board-games
2019-05-24 - Not going anywhere
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190524-not-going-anywhere
2019-05-24 - robots.txt
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190524-robots-txt
2019-05-23 - offline for a bit
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190523-offline-for-a-bit
2019-05-10 - tea and shakuhachi
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190510-tea-and-shakuhachi
2019-05-02 - ASMR
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190502-asmr
2019-04-29 - Poppy
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190429-poppy
2019-04-26 - net news on tilde.black
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190426-net-news-on-tilde-black
2019-04-26 - net news on cosmic.voyage
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190426-net-news-on-cosmic-voyage
2019-04-25 - solarpunk thoughts
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190425-solarpunk-thoughts
2019-04-21 - tilde.black online
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190421-tilde-black-online
2019-04-20 - ssh over tor
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190420-ssh-over-tor
2019-04-16 - re: cat dispossession
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190416-re-cat-dispossession
2019-04-16 - gopher conlang? Yes please!
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190416-gopher-conlang-yes-please
2019-04-14 - ssh keys
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190414-ssh-keys
2019-04-11 - opening gopher links from firefox in lynx
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190411-opening-gopher-links-from-firefox-in-lynx
2019-04-11 - phlog listing updates
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190411-phlog-listing-updates
2019-03-30 - Fun Questions
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190330-fun-questions
2019-03-17 - The Spam Files - Central Intellegence Agency
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190317-the-spam-files-central-intellegence-agency
2019-03-02 - ada
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190302-ada
2019-03-02 - tilde.tel
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190302-tilde-tel
2019-02-19 - re: cdmnky - crazy bugs
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190219-re-cdmnky-crazy-bugs
2019-02-18 - On the separation of artists from their art
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190218-on-the-separation-of-artists-from-their-art
2019-01-30 - Heavy Breathing
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190130-heavy-breathing
2019-01-29 - nerds in time
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190129-nerds-in-time
2019-01-28 - lxd
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190128-lxd
2019-01-21 - free speech
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190121-free-speech
2019-01-20 - Cosmic Voyage - Part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-cosmic-voyage-part-1
2019-01-20 - gophernicus TLS howto
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-gophernicus-tls-howto
2019-01-15 - Little Free Library, part 3
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190115-little-free-library-part-3
2019-01-09 - Little Free Library, part 2
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190109-little-free-library-part-2
2019-01-02 - talkd on ubuntu
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190102-talkd-on-ubuntu
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Webmentions And Microsub</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191223-webmentions-and-microsub/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
webmentions and microsub
December 23rd, 2019
----------------------------------------

This phlog is about web stuff. Specifically it's about Indyweb
things and microformats.

I use my website https://tomasino.org as an IndieAuth [0] portal.
When logging into sites that understand the IndieWeb concept,
I provide my "Home" URL as an identifier. Then the site scrubs
through all the various links I have on that page and picks out
those that it can understand for authentication. In most cases
I get GPG and GitHub hits, though occasionally a site will support
more. I oAuth in, and bam... identified. It's pretty neat and
requires very little effort on my side.

[0] IndieAuth
    https://indieauth.com/

There are much fancier IndieWeb doodads though, and I wanted to
start taking advantage of some. In particular Webmentions had
drawn my attention. It's a different way to handle commenting
that, honestly, reminds me of what we do here in gopherspace.
Instead of leaving a comment on a post somewhere, you just write
your own blog post and "notify" the original. The original page
can then choose whether to add a link to yours or ignore it or
whatever. Everyone maintains control of their own words and all is
well!

So I opened up the IndieWeb sites and went digging into
Webmentions [1]. I was immediately reminded why I abandonded this
the last time around. While the concept is incredibly simple, the
implementation is annoyingly complex and the terminology for
things is as bad as git [2].

[1] Webmentions
    https://webmention.net/
[2] Git Man Page Generator
    https://git-man-page-generator.lokaltog.net/

Since my sites are all static I wasn't looking for a plugin or
even something that automatically displayed anything on the
front-end at all. I just wanted something to process webmentions
and give me a way to see that they happened. For my low traffic
sites, a Webmention-to-Email system would have been perfect.

There are a number of things out there already. Some support the
Webmention client role and others the server because--did I not
mention this?--you need webmentions set up on both sides for it to
work. So to actually do it you need reading, writing, discovery
and parsing. There are a handful of projects doing the various
points and most of them are "in development" to varying degrees.
Almost all of them have complex esoteric documentation that only
makes sense if you're already familiar with the protocol enough to
write your own software. Lovely!

There are a few 3rd party services that offer the basics without
charge. I don't know if they work or not, but that's what I ended
up trying. I really don't want to spend the whole Christmas break
figuring this stuff out. I don't expect to get many, if any,
mentions anyway. Webmention.io is the service I went with. I used
IndieAuth to log in and then grabbed the links it gave me to paste
on my various blogs. I have no idea how to "use" Webmentions from
the other side, and no idea how to test if I'm set up correctly.

I wonder if I need to IndieAuth with the blog URL itself and then
use webmention.io directly to that property only and then repeat
the process for the other site. It says I should be able to use it
on many sites though, so hopefully it's fine. Time will tell.

Webmention.io provides a microformat feed of the mentions you
receive. I was going to grab the RSS one and plug it into my RSS
reader until I noticed the mention of this other IndieWeb format,
Microsub.

Oh joy! Another one. :D

Microsub seems like an abstraction layer above microformats that
can be interpretted as feeds or notifications. RSS and Atom are
valid inputs, but so are other bits. Like other IndieWeb things,
there's a big push to separate client & servers. In this case
I found Aperture [3] as a server and I'm using a couple different
clients to see the front-end.

[3] Aperture
    https://aperture.p3k.io/

Most of these projects are also "in development", but they seem
functional enough that I was able to dupe my tt-rss contents over.
As I mentioned in my last post [4], I'm looking for a replacement
for that software anyway so maybe this will work out.

[4] Poisoning the Well
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191216-poisoning-the-well

Eventually I'd like to run all these services myself (though
I have no desire to write the software to do so myself). I have
nginx running on this webserver already so if I can dockerize the
bits & pieces together into an IndieWeb multi-container and
reverse proxy everything that would be perfect. For now I'm
putting a pin in it. Things are good enough.

- - - - -

Are any of you running IndieWeb goodness? Have thoughts or
suggestions? Wanna vent? Send me a mention in the lovely gopher
style!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Poisoning The Well</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191216-poisoning-the-well/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
poisoning the well
December 16th, 2019
----------------------------------------

This week I learned that the RSS aggregator I use, tt-rss, is
developed by an individual whose personal politics are at odds
with my own. This morning I became aware that the creator of the
television show, The IT Crowd, appears to be a scumbag. If we look
back over the last year or two it's easy to spot Chik Fil A and
Harvey Weinstein and a hundred other cases where a person or
organization has become pariah. Their works are stained forever.

A number of questions came to me after considering our present
reality:

  - Is it universal? Does the idea of individual moral judgement
    apply the same way to all people? What about companies?
  - Is this new? Is it a continuous development from some earlier
    state?
  - Is it "fair", not to the subject of the moral judgement, but
    to the works? What about collective works where only a single
    contributor is a problem? Does their position of authority
    change the judgement?

There's too much to go into in a gopher phlog. I'm not going to
write some massive moral treatise here. There's really two bits
I'm focused on anyway, so pitter-patter, as they say…

First is the question of large collective works, like film.
According to some web page I read in passing, which queried data
from the top IMDB films, the average crew on a film is about 588
members strong. If we assume that the moral distribution of
individuals on a given film is representative of the general
population (safe enough, not given a specific film) then we might
expect some sort of normal distribution of morality (if such
a thing were quantifiable). If one of these individuals were to
score at an extreme to one degree or another it will not shift the
distribution noticeably. The overall morality of those making this
piece of collective art is unchanged.

But we punish them, don't we? Many of us will boycott the movie
because of what that actor said, or what the director did. We will
spite the 587 others on a film for that one person. They have, in
effect, poisoned the well. 

But maybe it's not about the math of morality. Maybe it's because
we must take action in the face of injustice. Something we
perceive as wrong cannot be allowed to occur, even if our methods
will cause harm to others. That sounds silly, doesn't it? It does
to me.

Maybe it matters more when justice would not be done without the
masses acting in protest. If the courts won't prosecute, then the
voice of the consumer will blacklist them. Let capitalism rear its
power for justice for once, right?

Ultimately I think it's harder to let go of something we see as
wrong than it is to ignore the damage we cause others. Collateral
damage is a shame, but at least we got THAT guy.

So yeah, there's some moral ambiguity here in collective works,
but what about individual creators? Should everyone boycott
tt-rss? Should we avoid using suckless code? Stop listening to
somebody's music? Maybe that's easier here. After all, we're not
hurting anyone else with this sort of mob justice.

There's just so many "what ifs" floating around. What if the
despicable person created something that helps people? What if
they pioneered a green energy revolution? What if they found
a disease cure? What if they make a really good software package
for the blind?

Yes, on the one hand it is the old debate about whether you can
separate art from artist. But there's the question of utility as
well. At what point does the good of the work outweigh the bad of
the individual.

This is where my head has been all morning and I'm not coming up
with any concrete answers. That's probably a sign that I shouldn't
expect a fixed set of rules to apply. In the case of films, I'll
probably keep seeing them. In the case of tt-rss, I will probably
jump to another project if I find one comparable. In the case of
the IT Crowd, I'll continue to quote and enjoy it and probably use
that moment to also inform others around me that Graham Linehan as
a shitbag. Double-win, right?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Years Of Journaling</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191215-years-of-journaling/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
years of journaling
December 15th, 2019
----------------------------------------

A few of you brilliant gopherites have been talking about the
length of time they've been blogging [0,1]. 20 years is a lot of
blog posts whether collected on the web or gopher. It's great to
see collections like this all together surviving so long.

[0] It was 20 years ago today
    gopher://gopher.conman.org/0Phlog:2019/12/04.1
[1] On 16 years of blogging
    gopher://republic.circumlunar.space/0/~slugmax/phlog/2019-12-13-on-16-years-of-blogging

I've had people go spelunking down into my own blog [2] archives
before and I have to say it's a really cool feeling. Journaling is
inherently about yourself. When another human decides to spend
their time reading your personal thoughts and history, it's very
flattering (at least to me).

[2] tomasino blog
    https://blog.tomasino.org

There are technical blogs aplenty which focus on code or math or
science or whatever topic that isn't the self. They're great too,
but I don't see them the same way. I'm sure they provide great
interest to people when they're published, and interesting history
to those that come later. Sharing a personal blog is so much more
intimate. Keeping one up for an extended period of time is its own
type of vulnerability. It's not just showing your timely thoughts
of today, but also the cringe-worthy worries of younger you. It's
easy to spotlight the mistakes, the lack of understanding, and the
ideas that you'd eventually grow out of. That's beautiful stuff,
if horribly embarrassing.

I started journaling when I was 14. I have a shelf of paper
journals sitting over there --> that I flip through still. I still
do some paper journaling these days, too. Those moleskines aren't
going to fill themselves, after all.

It wasn't until 1998 that I started writing a blog online. I was
off to college and learning how to do all this crazy web stuff.
I kept text notes on that website for a while (lost now even to
the wayback machine, sadly). I later moved to livejournal and kept
a pretty decent journal there with a ring of friends. Thankfully
I harvested some of those old posts before nuking my livejournal
account years later. Those earliest posts on my blog now were
written there. They've been updated a few times to move to
wordpress, jekyll, and now hugo. I keep that stuff in git now,
too. Better peace of mind, for sure.

Anyway, I don't have much more to say on the subject. It's pretty
cool that I've almost got 20 years of journaling history up on the
internet myself. I hope I have much more to offer down the line in
gopher as well.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Qr Codes</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191215-qr-codes/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
QR codes
December 15th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I've been sitting on this link for a while. I couldn't come up
with a magical brilliant use for it though. So... here it is.


      █▀▀▀▀▀█ ▀▀   ▀  █ █▀▀▀▀▀█
      █ ███ █ █▄ ███▀▀  █ ███ █
      █ ▀▀▀ █ ▀█▀▀ ▀█▀▀ █ ▀▀▀ █
      ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀ ▀▄▀▄▀ ▀▄▀ ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀
      ▀███  ▀▄▀▄ ▄▀▄▀ █▀ ▄▀▀▀▄▀
      ▀█ ▄▀ ▀ ▄  ▀ ▄█▄ █▄█ ▄▄  
      ▀▀█▀ ▀▀▀▄▀▄▀███▄ ████ ▀▀█
      ▄▀▀ █ ▀▄▀██ ▄ ▀ ▀▄█  ▄▀▀▄
        ▀   ▀ ▄█ ███ ▄█▀▀▀█▀▀▀█
      █▀▀▀▀▀█   █ █ █▄█ ▀ █▀▀█▀
      █ ███ █ ▄███▄ ▀ ▀██▀█ ▄██
      █ ▀▀▀ █ █▄▄▀ ▄▄▄ ▀█▀█▀█▀ 
      ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀ ▀▀▀▀ ▀▀  ▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀

Maybe you all can think of cool ways to use it. :D
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
