<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Irc Migration</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210519-irc-migration/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
IRC migration
May 19th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Wowza! Freenode is in meltdown. There's some major drama about
a for-profit company snaking control from under the community.
Well, the ircops revolted and all resigned and went to form a new
network at libera.chat. I've moved my few channels over there and
left freenode behind. You can find me in:

  #stutter - for my browser speed-reading add-on
  #gopher  - a more elegant weapon for a more civilized time
  #gemini  - for unofficial chat

Peace.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Rss</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210429-re-rss/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: RSS
April 29th, 2021
----------------------------------------

sloum just wrote about RSS [0] wondering what happend to it and
why nobody links to their feeds anymore. It's a good question.
I have an RSS feed on my blog and my labs blog, but I don't have
a link in the webpage to them. The <link rel='alternate' is in
there.

[0] sloum - RSS
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~sloum/phlog/20210428.txt

I do publish the feed links on cosmic, but that's sort of
a byproduct of doing it on gopher where there's no link element to
do it behind the scenes. So why don't I link to them on more
sites? I think it's partially habit. Browsers just used to expose
RSS feeds and subscription buttons so naturally in the browser
interface I got used to it. When they stopped that I didn't
retroactively promote it on my pages.

Now that I'm thinking about it actively, that's pretty stupid. I'm
going to spend some time to add feed links back onto my pages
soon. The attack on RSS/Atom has been ongoing and should be fought
on all levels including individual action. Google Reader shutting
down and the major browsers removing feed reading were arguably
the biggest blows to the standard, but the efforts haven't won out
yet. Podcasts have a stronghold still and there are still plenty
of readers out there. I'll do my part.

If you want my blog & labs feed, here they are to copy/paste:

  https://blog.tomasino.org/index.xml
  https://labs.tomasino.org/index.xml

Oh, and this gopher phlog has a feed at:

  gopher://gopher.black/0/rss.xml

which you can reach via proxy or by piping it through curl if your
rss reader can't do gopher.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Python Virtualenv Invoking Without Activate</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210426-python-virtualenv-invoking-without-activate/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
python virtualenv invoking without activate
April 26th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I like python. I do not like python packaging. I run into the same
problem again and again: I want to make a useful tool like
'burrow' that can be distributed and used by others (or myself on
other systems). Inevitably I'll need to use other packages,
though, so I'll need to pip-install those. I don't want to pollute
the system, though, so I'd better create a virtual environment and
install those there. So now I have my requirements.txt file and
can do things inside this little container, but now what?

Do I bundle this thing and put it in pip? Am I now expecting
someone else will pip install it globally to run it on their
system? Of course not, because everything python should be safely
stored away in a virtual environment. But I don't want them to
write a program that uses my program as a library. I just want to
invoke it? Does that change the rules? Will my app's dependencies
then pollute their system?

And then I throw my hands in the air and give up and do something
else.

Well, recently I decided I wanted to work on a side-project on
cosmic that khuxkm started in python: an anonymous remailer that
actually works over email. We'd gone down this path in the past
and it almost worked. I had motivation and wanted to see it
through. Immediately I knew I was about to hit that problem from
above, though. In fact, I was going to hit it with even more
complications.

See, in order to handle incoming mail and pass it off to a script
I was using a feature of ~/.forward that lets you do that. The
.forward file works just like the aliases system file, but only on
the right-hand side of an alias definition. That means you can do
more than just specify an email or emails to deliver the mail to,
you can pipe it to a script like so:

  |/home/anonhmmst/mailhandler/parse_email.py

That leading pipe is important. It's also important to know that
scripts invoked this way are passed the contents of the incoming
mail, but invoked by the 'nobody' user. That's a security thing
and for the best, but it complicated my script running.

If I used the anonhmmst user and installed python packages for
this parse_email.py script at the user-level they wouldn't work
when invoked by nobody. I needed to set up a virtual environment
to get everything bundled, but I also needed a way to invoke it
without having to manually activate the virtual environment first.

The solution turned out to be pretty simple:
  - make the python script executable
  - point the hashbang at the virtual environment python binary

In my case:

  #!/home/anonhmmst/mailhandler/env/bin/python3

I had to do a bit more work on cosmic with the sudoers file to
enable the nobody user to run some cosmic-specific scripts, but
the virtual-environment setup was the big take-away. It doesn't
solve all my python packaging woes, but it fixed this one nicely.

What about you? What do you do in these situations? Do you pip
install binaries as your user without virtual environments for
utilities or do you wrap them in a virtual environment somehow?
How do you distribute your own projects?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Limited Resources</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210330-limited-resources/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
limited resources
March 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Tonight I set up resource limits on cosmic. Specifically I set up
CPU and Memory limits for users. I don't get a lot of bad eggs
amongst the voyagers, but it's easy to take a bigger slice of the
pie than you intend on a tiny tilde. Someone had a newsreader
running tonight that was accidentally using the entire 1024MB
I have to offer.

I wasn't sure how to set this up, so I did a little research and
for once systemd came to the rescue. Here's what I did:

----

mkdir -p /etc/systemd/system/user-.slice.d

cat > /etc/systemd/system/user-.slice.d/50-memory.conf << EOF
[Slice]
MemoryMax=80M
CPUQuota=8%
EOF

sudo vim /etc/systemd/system.conf

# uncomment and set the following values in that file:
DefaultCPUAccounting=yes
DefaultMemoryAccounting=yes

systemctl daemon-reload

----

And that's it! I may tweak those quota values over time to make
sure the system stays healthy but people can still use it. So far
so good.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Remind</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210330-cli-tricks-remind/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CLI Tricks: remind
March 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

remind - a sophisticated reminder service

One of the little cool CLI utilities I've been meaning to use is
remind(1). It's a tool with a plain text, human readable calendar
format and some hefty power under the hood.

Let's look at an example entry in a reminder file:

  REM July 6 +7 MSG tomasino's birthday %b%

In looking at this line you can have a pretty good guess what it
means without any help at all. These insructions can become far
more complex and esoteric as you start using the powerful
programming features built into remind, but most of your entries
are probably going to be as simple as this.

The main structure of a remind entry is:

  <trigger> <action> <body>

In the example above the trigger is:

  REM July 6 +7

The action is:

  MSG

And the body is:

  tomasino's birthday %b

Technically the "REM" at the start is optional, except in some
weird cases where the line might begin with OMIT or RUN. It's
safest just to keep it. Every line ends in % also.

Want the full list of options for a REM line? Sure...

REM  [ONCE] [date_spec] [back] [delta] [repeat] [PRIORITY prio]
[SKIP | BEFORE | AFTER] [OMIT omit_list]  [OMITFUNC  omit_func‐
tion] [AT time [tdelta] [trepeat]] [SCHED sched_function] [WARN
warn_function] [UNTIL expiry_date | THROUGH  last_date]  [SCAN‐
FROM scan_date | FROM start_date] [DURATION duration] [TAG tag]
<MSG | MSF | RUN | CAL | SATISFY | SPECIAL special | PS  |  PS‐
FILE> body

The trigger section is often a date and they follow some really
simple and intuitive rules. If you list a full date including day,
month, and year, then it will trigger on that day. If you omit the
year then it will remind you on that calendar day every year. Omit
the month and it will remind you on that day every month. Simple,
right?

What if you want the reminder to occur for several days leading up
to the date? Just like in my example above, the +7 following
a date will do that. In my case you get a full week's worth of
reminders leading up to my birthday.

Date's can be more than just calendar days, though. For instance:

  REM SUN 1 --7 at 23:30 MSG Tilde Trivia with Tomasino %

Here I'm setting the date to the first Sunday of the month, minus
seven days at 11:30pm. Well, if you move backwards one week from
the first sunday that gets you the last sunday of the month.
A nice trick, right? Here we have a reminder for my radio show on
tilderadio.org. I should note that all times in remind(1) are in
your local timezone. If you are scripting something with external
data and need to convert timezones there are functions built in
for that, though.

So far I've just shown off the MSG action, but there are several
others. Most notably there's the RUN action, which lets you
execute a program on your machine when the trigger occurs. Perhaps
you want to use that to output your todo list every Monday? Or
maybe you have it automatically email you a system report on the
second Tuesday of the month. There's no limit to the options
available.

So how do you use it?

Well, first you install remind(1). It's available in apt and most
other package managers. There's a package for MacOS as well. It
will come with two executables: remind(1) and rem(1). The latter
is a shortcut that will run remind(1) with the default remind file
(normally ~/.reminders, but you can change it with an ENV var).

In my .profile I have the environment variable set to use a remind
file in XDG_CONFIG_HOME since I like a clean home dir.

  export DOTREMINDERS=$XDG_CONFIG_HOME/remind/reminders

Then inside that 'reminders' file I use a tiny script to
automatically include any files that match "*.rem" inside
a special syncthing folder:

  SET HOME getenv("HOME")
  include [HOME]/.syncthing/remind/

This means I can organize my stuff into relevant files like
"work.rem" and "birthdays.rem".

There's an incredible amount of depth you can get into with this
thing. It can output to a terminal calendar or even an html
calendar or just the plain reminders. It can generate a postscript
printer file and allows advanced commands for shading. It has
a robust programming language built in as well that will make you
scratch your head at first and then scoff at the childish
limitations of Outlook and Google Calendar. You can even build
your own custom functions in this thing.

The remind(1) man page is well written and packed full of
examples, but there's also some great tutorials online. Here's
a few to start your explorations:

Keep your calendar in plain text with Remind
    https://lifehacker.com/geek-to-live-keep-your-calendar-in-plain-text-with-rem-186661
Roaring Penguin's Remind FAQ
    https://www.roaringpenguin.com/wiki/index.php/Remind_FAQ
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stallman</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210326-stallman/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Stallman
March 26th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Richard Stallman is back on the board of directors at the Free
Software Foundation (FSF) after having resigned eighteen months
ago under mounting public pressure for him to be removed for his
controversial comments about consent in reference to Jeffrey
Epstein sex-trafficking charges. 

Virginia Roberts Giuffre was a 17 year old victim of Epstein who
in her deposition stated that she was directed to have sex with
Marvin Minsky, a member of the MIT faculty. In response to an MIT
CSAIL (Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory)
email thread planning a protest at MIT over the institution's
relationship with Epstein, Stallman raised issues with the term
"assaulting", stating, "The word 'assaulting' presumes that he
applied force or violence, in some unspecified way, but the
article itself did say no such thing. Only that they had sex."

In addition to the immediate backlash, statements from Stallman's
blog added fuel to the flames. I am skeptical of the claim that
voluntarily [sic] pedophilia harms children." (Stallman, 2006)

In 2019 he later amended, "Through personal conversations in
recent years, I've learned to understand how sex with a child can
harm per psychologically. This changed my mind about the matter:
I think adults should not do that. I am grateful for the
conversations that enabled me to understand why."

Though often accused of defending Epstein, Stallman has made it
clear that he sees the man as a serial-rapist and condemns his
acts. It is instead these statements surrounding the ideas of
consent and sexual violence that have sparked the majority of the
outrage.

Many people feel it is appropriate to separate Stallman from the
FSF and other libre software movements as these personal
statements and views reflects negatively on that community and
their efforts. Others see in him a champion unmatched in calling
for libre software engagement and adoption. Many groups in the
field have been forced to make a public stance in favor or against
his involvement, such as Mozilla and the Tor Project [0].

[0] Mozilla and Tor join calls to oust ...
    https://www.fastcompany.com/90618666/mozilla-and-tor-join-calls-to-oust-richard-stallman-from-free-software-foundation

                           - - -

So what do I think? I think the man is a mixture of good ideas and
bad. I think he's naturally brusque and his elevated position in
his narrow community has fed his ego dangerously, as any power is
wont to do. 

I am also guilty of having been wrong in the past. I'm thankful
that most of my wrongness isn't in permanent written form and
I don't have enemies who seek out my own poor behavior in the past
to drag it into the light today. It's hard enough to change your
mind without being anchored to those past decisions through
constant reminder.

Stallman has lived his life in a tech world with tech solutions,
logic, and a type of pseudo-logical rhetoric that can make his
statements seem detached or disingenuous. It's something I see
commonly in communities dominated by autistic people, though it's
not limited to those or necessarily present among all autistics.
Whatever the case, it doesn't mesh well with the highly emotional
topics such as sexual predation. The tone itself harms, which is
something I suspect Stallman is both unaware of and incapable of
addressing. Coming from a white man in position of power adds to
the harm and further alienates those who hear what he says. All
this harm comes separate from and in addition to the comments
themselves. He was rightfully argued against in that email list
and I think the escalation of the issue into a public forum was
necessary to balance the scales of power. Unfortunately in an
institution like MIT and in a group like CSAIL the opinions of
Richard Stallman are not in balance with the others speaking.

We do not currently have a mechanism in our society to address
these public social grievances of powerful people beyond seeking
punishment through their employment, platform, sponsorship, and
other mechanisms that enable their power. Our public speech is
unbalanced in power in favor of the rich and powerful, and so some
measures will necessarily be taken to counter it. 

Is it right? Is it just? It is literally our only recourse. It's
hard to make an ethical judgement without alternatives. I would
love a world where there were other means of public censor.
History doesn't provide us many options without blood to model
after, though. Perhaps getting someone removed from a board of
directors isn't such a bad course.

And now that he has returned, just 18 months after the incident of
note and without much change in public opinion, what are we to
think? Is his short statement on his blog about learning that
pedophilia is wrong sufficient to let him off the hook for his
statements minimizing sexual abuse? No, I don't think so. That may
address his 2006 statements, but not those regarding Virginia
Roberts Giuffre.

                           - - -

But what of the FSF and libre software in general? Without
Stallman at the helm will that effort fail?

Here first I will make an ethical statement that libre software is
not important when juxtaposed by the physical safety of a human
being. It is not important when juxtaposed with the safety of
minors, of women, or in relation to sexual abuse. If Richard
Stallman was the one and only human being who could make libre
software succeed or fail it is still not worth giving the man
power if it leads toward the increase in actual harm to actual
human beings.

Thankfully Stallman isn't that important. He has done quite a bit
of work in the field. That is unarguable. 

In political theory there is the idea of the Overton window [1].
There is a spectrum of political discourse from far extreme to
moderate to far extreme in the other direction. The Overton window
represents the scope along this spectrum of politically acceptable
policies. Notably, though, is the need for actors that exceed the
boundaries of this window to widen it in their given direction.
For instance, an extreme leftist view allows for a more moderate
leftist view to be politically acceptable. Without that extremist
view the window will shift to the right and the moderate practice
will seem extreme.

[1] Overton window
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Overton window

I think this idea is applicable to more than politics, or perhaps
more than traditional politics. The politics of technology and
thir place in the world has extremists and Richard Stallman is
one. The idea that all software and hardware on a user's system
must fit his libre definition is one such view. It enables us to
have more reasonable discussions about the importance of the open
source community, of public access to code, and intellectual
property in general.

For this reason I appreciate the Stallmans in the world, but not
enough to give him a pass on other behavior. Thankfully we still
have plenty more assholes expanding our Overton window. We don't
need Stallman for that anymore.

In some cases it is difficult to separate art from artist when the
artist does something heinous. This is most often if the art
represents a substantial and important cultural work, or if, as is
more often the case, it is not an individual work but the work of
many people. Take the Cosby Show as an example here. Do we
write-off that television series because of the acts of Bill
Cosby? That unjustly punishes all of the other actors, staff, and
production crews that put their work into a very good program to
spite one man. This is a difficult ethical choice. In the case of
Richard Stallman it was fairly simple to punish the man and ignore
the FSF itself 18 months ago. The choice of the board to reinstate
him, however, now stains the rest of them with the conscious
choice to value him over the harm his statements cause.

So that's my extremely long-winded way of saying I agree with
Mozilla and the Tor Project. We must censor Stallman and the FSF
board of directors. The means of doing so is their removal from
that position. Let it be done and done peacefully. Let them learn
from it as Stallman learned that his 2006 statements were
dangerous and damaging. Maybe by removing them from power others
will learn as well. These ideas they're arguing are widening an
Overton window around sexual consent that doesn't need widening.
Lets quiet the extremists and bring that window to a healthier
place.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cold</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210227-cold/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cold
February 27th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I've got a cold. It's just a regular one, don't worry. Even so,
it's so frustrating. I go to few places, mix with very few people,
wear a mask in public, wash my hands and disinfect things, and
still I get a cold. It's not the first one either. I've been sick
a lot this past year.

The source is probably the kid and his friends. Little kids bring
all the illnesses with them and I tend to get them all. Even
taking that into account, though, they're isolated and their
spaces are cleaned religiously. They should be a smaller vector
now too. But my sniffly nose disagrees.

I've started taking in-person Icelandic classes this past week.
No, the illness isn't from there. Nobody there is sick and we're
all distanced and whatnot. I go back on Monday and I hope I'm
feeling better by then. I can't willingly bring a cold into that
room and I know if I start missing classes I'm not going to keep
up.

Hurry up, nose!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bun Day</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210213-bun-day/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Bun Day
February 13th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Monday is Bun Day here in Iceland. Bollur, the buns of the day,
are sort of like cream puffs. Folks get jams and whipped cream and
mix them together and stuff the buns to overflowing, then smother
them in chocolate sauce. It's a healthy time!

There's also a super-duper Icelandic tradition with bun day that
many parents choose to not teach their kids. Early on Monday
morning children in the know will wake up early, sneak into their
parents' bedroom and WHACK WHACK WHACK them in their bed with
sticks! However many whacks they get in before the parents get up
is how many buns they get. Lovely!

Following Bun Day is a sort of Fat Tuesday-like holiday that
involves gorging yourself on all sorts of special foods that are
terrible for you. I forget the name of that one, but it's nice
too. 

Finally we get to Ash Wednesday. Here in Iceland Ash Wednesday is
the costume & candy holiday. Halloween is a relatively recent
phenomenon here and not very popular mostly because they already
have most of those traditions at the start of lent. Kids dress up
in all sorts of costumes, go to school that way, and then later go
around begging for candy. But here they don't go to individual
homes and say "trick or treat". Instead they go to businesses and
sing songs for their treats! If you head downtown to Reykjavik on
Wednesday you'll see this in full swing. It's really cute and so
strange to see bank-branded popcorn bags and the like.

Needless to say the next 3 days are pretty much party-time for the
kids. No school work will get done and that's a joy in itself.
Everyone is going to be on a crazy sugar rush. Good for them. :)


</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Inauguration</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210120-inauguration/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
inauguration
January 20th, 2021
----------------------------------------

A tangible weight has been lifted from my chest.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
