<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Another Sdf Hiccup</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181012-another-sdf-hiccup/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Another sdf hiccup?
October 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

It looks like gopher.club isn't resolving again. SDF.org is
showing up. It's usually the other way around when it comes to
gopher. I'm sick of switching the phlogroll back and forth. I'm
going to leave things as they are for now and hope it resolves
itself in the next day or two. If you notice your phlog not
updating for a while, send me a note and I'll try to work around
it.

Also, welcome to a few new phloggers on the roll!

inpefess
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/inpefess
bradfonseca
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/bradfonseca/

Some good content brewing there!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Maps</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181007-maps/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Maps
October 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I intend to do a longer phlog soon with an update on my bug-out
bag and other emergency preparations, but in the meantime I wanted
to highlight one thing I value that many people probably overlook.
In the United States the USGS provides extremely detailed and well
maintained maps for free (digital) or cheap (print) covering
pretty much every inch of the country. The most popular of these
maps are the 7.5 minute stretches, which cover about 64 square
miles in each one. Here's the one that covers my house [0]!

[0] 7.5 Minute Map (large file warning)
    http://prd-tnm.s3.amazonaws.com/StagedProducts/Maps/USTopo/PDF/NJ/NJ_Trenton_West_20161025_TM_geo.pdf

In addition, I also have a map of the full county with topographic
information and water systems clearly labeled. I keep both of
these in a waterproof map case in my bag. I have a road atlas in
my car for the whole country, but around home there may be need to
understand the land more intimately in case of emergency. 

In short, maps are cool.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Restored</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181004-restored/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Restored
October 04th, 2018
----------------------------------------

The restoration of gopher.black was quite eventful with some
absolutely awful computer drama. If you care about such things,
here's a recap:

I have a few raspberry pis, model 3s and some zero Ws. One of them
has this sick metal case with a fan. It's a beast. Used that
hardware for gopher.black along with a 64gb micro sd card. The
only problem is, the fan sucks (or blows?). It has always been
really noisy, and it eventually pissed me off enough to do
something about it. Since the pis don't run hot anyway, I figured
it was unnecessary. But before I removed it completely I figured
I'd try lubricating it just in case that solved things.

It didn't.

So I opened the case up, ripped that bad boy out, and plugged her
back in. Only this time, something was wrong. I was up and
running, but the system was in read-only mode. Uh, oh! I decided
to reboot and try again. This time, even worse... no boot.
I plugged in an HDMI monitor to watch the boot sequence and it
sprawled a bunch of messages about read-only crap. A quick google
revealed that my SD card was likely at fault. It was going bad.
I assume it was related to me opening the thing up and closing it
a few times. I must have bumped it badly.

If the card was read-only, I figured I could still read it to get
an image. I did some dd magic and backed it up. Today I got a new
64GB sd card in the mail. I dd'd my backup onto that and plugged
it in but nothing happened. Not even a failed boot. Just nada.

I thought... Lets make sure it's the SD card! So I swapped my SD
card from my pi-hole and gopher.black into the other hardware and
confirmed... definitely the SD. I had to roll back to an earlier
backup. 

The most recent I had was from June (yuck). Luckily, 90% of the
crap on gopher.black is in git, so it's just a matter of updating
from repos after restoring things. I smiled to myself at my own
awesome and went over to my PC which houses the older backups.
I plugged in my new SD card, opened up Etcher to image it from the
backup and POOF, the MOTHERFUCKING drive hosting my backups
decided that it was the perfect moment to disappear!

Fast forward a bit to me restoring that drive from ITS backup,
eventually restoring my SD card from the old backup, plugging
things into the pi, booting it up, and we're back in business.

Things that still suck:
- Moku Pona is running again, but pretty much EVERYTHING updated
  since June, so the most recent phlogs is kinda a mess. It'll
  sort itself out in the days to come.
- All my web certs expired. I'm renewing them again now via
  acme.sh.
- Weechat's sec.conf does something weird. It doesn't know my
  master password. I have no idea what logic it uses, but this is
  the second time that's happened to me in a week. I appreciate
  that it externalizes passwords, but that's just BS. I'm better
  off typing them in each time I connect. It's not like I do it
  very often.
- Probably other stuff... I don't really recall everything I did
  on gopher.black over the last couple months. I'm sure most of it
  was content, but maybe there was something else that was super
  cool and I totally forgot. Meh, we'll make due.

If you notice anything wonky on my stuff in the next couple days,
hit me up.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Oops</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181001-oops/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Oops!
October 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

You might not be reading this right now unless you are checking
out one of my mirrors on SDF.org or tilde.town. That's because
I accidentally blew up gopher.black. OHNOES!

I was getting annoyed at the buzzing from the fan on my pi's case.
I opened it up and tried spraying it with a little lubricant, but
it didn't make a difference in the sound. So, what the hell, I'll
just pull it out. Unfortunately, in the process my jostling of the
SD card put it into read-only mode and now nothing works.

Since the card is still readable I'm dding it down to a backup.
I've got a new SD card ordered from Amazon and it should be here
by Wednesday. I'll restore, plug that bad-boy in, and hopefully
everything will be right as rain. If not, I've got 3 extra
raspberry pi's lying around that can happily become the next
gopher.black. I've got the data, I've got redundant hardware. This
shouldn't be too bad.

Still... derp.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sdf Gopher Servers</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180929-sdf-gopher-servers/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sdf gopher servers
September 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

As many of you are aware, sdf.org recently performed some
upgrading which somehow disrupted their gopher servers. As
a result, everything reverted to being run off bucktooth instead
of gophernicus. After a bunch of prodding on bboard, sdf.org was
reverted to gophernicus, but a very out-of-date version.
Gopher.club, the preferred DNS mirror of SDF for gopher according
to its tutorials, is still left using bucktooth.

There's a few painful parts to this. A few of the more active
gopher users hosting on SDF were actively using the cgi script
features of gophernicus which were not a part of bucktooth's
offering. As a result, some of their gopher holes failed to load
at all, or loaded incorrectly. Second, the constant changes in
server info means that our aggregators keep triggering as if
everyone on SDF posted new content. I know this has been
a challenge for logout [0] whose Bongusta! [1] aggregator has been
affected. It's also affected my moku-pona listings [2]. 

As a result, for the time being I have reverted all SDF
gopherholes to using the sdf.org domain instead of gopher.club in
my listings. This way they will display correctly at least. Sadly,
gophernicus outputs server information in a footer of gophermaps,
so it will likely continue to trigger the mass-update phenomenon
whenever NetBSD or gophernicus itself are updated. I think we've
all learned to work around this by now, though.

Finally, I've posted about all this on the sdf.org bboard in
a single requests post. I'm hopeful that seeing it all clearly
outlined will help the admins update gophernicus to the latest
version and get gopher.club back in line. Time will tell! If you
continue to see mass-updates on the aggregators I apologize, but
there's limited control unless I go through manually to clean
everything up each time (like logout does). It'll settle down
eventually.

[0] logout
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/
[1] Bongusta
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/en/bongusta/
[2] Phlog Roll
    gopher://gopher.black/1/moku-pona

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Enforced Anonymity</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180924-enforced-anonymity/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Enforced anonymity
September 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Gopher has been filled with threads on the topic of anonymity [0],
but I want to take a different tack. There's a storm brewing in
the form of Codes of Conduct for online communities. I have
OPINIONS on these things, and the only appropriate place for
opinion on the internet is hidden in dead protocols.

Codes of Conduct attempt to accomplish a GOOD. They attempt to
ensure that individuals are not exposed to unfair prejudice. This
is a movement toward equality, which it itself is also a GOOD. (I
have argued in the past that I prefer liberty over equality, but
that is not a comparison of good vs bad, but rather a personal
stance on which is a greater good.) So far, we're all good here.

Codes of Conduct are also weapons. They are wielded by the
oppressed and marginalized with a powerful blow aimed at those
they feel have transgressed. Is this a GOOD? Providing
a reciprocal power dynamic is an expression of vengeance, not of
justice. It does not guarantee liberty or equality. It guarantees
a shifted power-base and a new set of mores to be navigated, or
else. This is not good. This is bad.

Hold off on the pitchforks. Go re-read the second paragraph again
if you're getting steamy at me.

If you're sitting there feeling like a Code of Conduct is a vital
tool in your arsenal as an objectified person, a minority, or
other disenfranchised group member, I can totally understand why.
It's good to not be shit upon or taken advantage of. But at the
same time, role reversal perpetuates a never-ending cycle of
anger. "It's our turn," is the voice of a failed morality. It may
feel good, but it gives no high ground and it leads to more
suffering for more people.

(I'm skirting around going into some deeper ethics talk on the one
hand, or going off into sci-fi territory and making a bunch of
Dune parallels, but I'm going to leave it alone and get to the
point instead).

"So what, tomasino? If Codes of Conduct aren't the answer, what do
you think we should do?"

Thanks for asking! First, I don't believe it is a necessity for
a criticism to offer an alternative solution. It is okay to point
out that something is wrong but not have a better alternative
prepared. And guess what? I don't! I have a ridiculous alternative
that we most definitely SHOULD NOT DO. I'm going to share it with
you as a thought exercise.

Here's my idea: 100% enforcement of anonymity. Boom! Meritocracy
blind to identity politics can only be 100% guaranteed if there is
no identity to politic. Go ahead and create your company, your
online group. Share your code, grab commits and share and merge
and whatever else technocrats do. But... no signatures. No names.
No personal sharing. You want an online identity, grab a number,
or we'll pull a string of dictionary words and assign them to you.

Now everyone is safe, has an equal voice and can be judged by
their own contributions. You want a code of conduct in the mix?
I got you covered. It's got 2 rules:

1) If you share your identity, or provide information that
   establishes a personal identity with the community, you're out.
2) If you share another person's identity or personal details
   about them, you're out.

This magical, mystical utopia actually sounds good to some people,
I'm sure. But it's not. It overlooks the beauty of human
interactions and the infinite possibilities for the advancement of
our species. It's an act of fear. Don't do it. Seriously, please
don't do it. Also, cool it with the Codes of Conduct. Protect
people, don't burn them.

And yes, Linus is an ass.


[0] I was really going to go look these up, but then I got
distracted. Take my word for it. There were a lot of posts on the
subject earlier this year.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Burrow 1 7 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180924-burrow-1-7-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
burrow 1.7.1
September 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Wow, so that was a big change. I was annoyed with some of my code
in burrow so I did a bit of surgery and blew up some features and
made some more generalized helpers instead.

burrow recipe
burrow topic
burrow create-config
GONE!

burrow edit-config will generate a new config for you if you don't
already have one. I've also added a new super-powerful command
called:

burrow gophermap

Enter that and hit enter and it'll open your root gophermap. But
that's not all!!! Hit tab after that bad-boy...

burrow gophermap <tab>

It'll list all your directories and any gophermaps you've got. You
can crawl your way through with more tab completion. You don't
need to be in your gopher directory for it either. It'll figure it
all out! :D

Once you hit enter it'll strip out "i" types and tabs and server
info from your gophermap temporarily so you can edit it. Once you
save it again it'll add all the fancy codes back in place. Open up
a new filename that you make up on the spot to create a new
gophermap. It'll default to no title, but you can fill in that
bit.

burrow phlog # still exists

Neat stuff. Pull, make, make install
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Choose Your Own Adventure Episode 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180920-choose-your-own-adventure-episode-2/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Choose Your Own Adventure - Episode 2
September 20th, 2018
----------------------------------------

The second episode of my aNONradio show aired tonight. If you
missed it, check out the archive page here on gopher. It has
a link to the episode audio so you can catch up!

Episode 2
    gopher://gopher.black/0/cyoa/2018-09-20-episode-002.txt

If you're free next week, the show airs at 0100UTC on Fridays.
That's 9PM EST on Thursday nights if you're in the United States.

You can listen by going to http://anonradio.net or opening a vlc
stream to "http://anonradio.net:8000/anonradio"
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anonradio Show</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180907-anonradio-show/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
aNONradio show
September 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Yesterday cat posted on Mastodon that someone should jump on
openVOIP and monologue. That sounded like a great idea and
I wasn't busy, so I decided I'd go for it. My first thought was
that I'd read some Virgil or maybe Bronte. I walked into my dining
room which has the main collection of our books and looked over my
shelves for something good. Boy Scout Handbook... Nimzowitsch...
Harry Potter in Latin... ahh, here we are:

ZORK #4: Conquest at Quendor

Is there a more perfect book for the SDF crew than a choose your
own adventure ZORK? I snapped a quick picture of the cover and
posted it to mastodon, then walked upstairs to my office. A note
on IRC or two and I was dialing in to the openVOIP line. At first
there was some sort of text adventure being played out with
Daniel's robot voice narrating it. That wrapped up and I got
started.

It was awkward, silly, and entirely too much fun. Instead of
picking the choices in the book myself I tossed them out to the
crowd to chime in. The engagement from people in com, mastodon,
and IRC made the experience for me. I was riding a high afterwards
and talked myself into doing it again. This time, though, I'll do
it right.

The anonradio mailing list folks agreed that the show was worthy
of a time slot, so now on Thursday nights/Friday mornings at 0100
UTC, or 9PM EST, I'll be continuing our adventures. This first
"real" show I'll finish up the ZORK story so I don't leave
everyone hanging, and then we'll start a new adventure. I don't
know that I'll make a point of finishing the adventures or not. If
time runs out I may just start a new one the next week instead of
trying to pick up again. On the one hand, it's nice to have some
completion, but these are books designed to be tried again and
again. Also, the authors aren't getting paid for this beyond me
buying a book or two, so I like the idea of enticing people with
the show so that they might go out and pick up a copy if they
enjoy it. That makes the whole thing seem much more legit, right?

To support the new show I've added a new section to my gopher
hole. You can find it on the root gophermap and here: 
Choose Your Own Adventure (anonradio)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/cyoa

For those who want to check it out, details about the first real
episode can be found here:
Episode 001 (2018-09-14)
    gopher://gopher.black/0/cyoa/2018-09-14-episode-001.txt

Please join me next week for the first show!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Blogging</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180904-blogging/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Blogging
September 04th, 2018
----------------------------------------

So I just published a regular old boring blog post and now I feel
dirty. I mean, not really, but I do feel something. I think it's
frustration or annoyance. You see, I wanted to open the blog with
a screenplay style intro, but it turned out to be painfully
difficult. I'm using Hugo which in turn uses markdown for
formatting and generally that's just fine. But in this case
I wanted to do some very specific text formatting that would have
been obvious and immediate in gopher but which took me five or six
iterations to figure out over there.

But it has a picture! :/ Meh, I guess so. More-over, the content
fit the theme of another blog post I wrote about Clue (this one is
about Guess Who, btw). It made sense to put it on the web.

I guess it once again illustrates why I prefer gopher. I can just
write stuff here and I'm done. In the world of HTTP I need to
massage stuff, play with themes, etc. Moops to that.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
