<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Compassion Is Important</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190918-compassion-is-important/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
compassion is important
September 18th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I started this phost intending to say something about RMS [0] and
the various responses I see coming out on the web and in
gopherspace.

[0] Richard Stallman and the Fall of the Clueless Nerd
    https://www.wired.com/story/richard-stallman-and-the-fall-of-the-clueless-nerd/

The thing is, nobody really cares about "yet another opinion".
It's just another example of how comments are useless [1].

[1] "Comments" on Labs blog
    https://labs.tomasino.org/comments/

Instead I think I'll say something about compassion.

Right now people are suffering. Richard Stallman is watching in
shock, outrage, and yes, in pain, as the world he built around
himself falls apart. He is suffering.

Also, the dozens of individuals he has interacted with over the
years who have been the targets of his well-meaning pedantry, of
his priviliged musings, and of his "hot takes", are feeling the
painful effects of those encounters. They feel demeaned,
less-than, or ignored. They feel injured, helpless, outraged, and
yes, in pain. They are suffering.

Epstein's victims have suffered horrendously and suffer still as
the government closes their options for compensation in the wake
of his suicide.

In short, there's a whole lot of pain going around and we'd all be
a little bit better people if we took a moment to consider it
before we launch into our next diatribe. That's not to say you
should shut up. Just try not to forget there's humans on the other
side of your outrage.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Apocrypha Of Cat The Desert</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190906-the-apocrypha-of-cat-the-desert/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
the apocrypha of cat - the desert
September 06th, 2019
----------------------------------------

It is said that before the desert, there was no cat.

It is also said that before cat, there was no desert.

What is known is that when cat left the desert he left a piece of
himself behind and took something different in its place. For
before the desert was a time when cat wore colors, when he sang
karaoke, and most importantly, when he had hair.

The sages speak of a time before myth and before legend when the
world held its breath waiting for a story to begin and set all in
motion. In some traditions this began with a Word, or a song that
can be heard in the Vedas, but the true devotee knows the truth.
The story began with a baby doll crying.

Cat found the doll at the edge of the great expanse stretching
endlessly beyond horizon covered in scrub brush and dust devils.
Low in the sky, the sun was quickly fleeing the heat of the day.
The baby cried once, twice, and a third time as a true harbinger.
In that aged voice-box a clarion rang from the heavens and opened
cat's eyes to Truth, such as needs capitalization and archaic
meter.

He lifted the baby in his arms with tender care and when he looked
down again his shoes had become Doc Martens. He knew these boots
were meant for walking, and that's just what he did as they
carried him deeper into the void. A voice then spoke, and cat knew
it to be his own though it carried no identifiable accent. It had
the cadence of an American and the diction of an Aussie but
scrambled deep in the bowels of bargain-bin Anime and food trucks.
The words themselves sounded like carnies trying their best to
hide their shame on a home visit for Christmas. It was glorious
and held the true power that can only be found in softness.

When cat asked the wind, "Why do I sound like this?" The wind
responded with a susurrus more brutal and jagged than cat's own
voice. In that moment the wind relented knowing that cat had
become as wind himself. And so he drifted forward further into the
desert.

In the desert he found many things. Boredom was chief amongst his
discoveries, though. His ennui bore a hole into the Earth,
hallowing it out and filling it with monsters and myth. It
expanded to the heavens and cast aliens from the sky raining down
across time. It filled our oceans and created Seaquest DSV, which
it is said nobody watched, ever. Finally his boredom brought him
back to the baby with it's soft coos and stuttered cries. In that
beatific countenance he saw the purity of purpose of the crafted
doll and it spoke a second Truth. Forever would he seek such
perfection in all things that crossed his gaze.

But his quest for beauty was at odds with the desert, for the only
beauty of the desert is in its solitude. While cat remained it
could never be itself. To love a thing and to crave for it such
beauty as he did, cat knew he had to leave.

And so, with the pure will of his element, he breathed outward
across the landscape and painted it with all his colors. The pinks
and fuchsias washed across the sky and land. The deep blues of his
eyes filled the sky. But green, which he always had avoided in his
youth, would not come from him. And so the desert would hold its
purity and its beauty for all time while cat was left with only
darkness to shroud himself.

In Doc Martens he walked forth and it is whispered that he left
three secrets behind in the vastness. The first was a fax number
of unknown purpose. The second was a horde of unused raspberry
pis. And the third was the greatest mix tape of all time.

These days cat wanders the Earth in search of beauty and truth
while battling those forces diametrically opposed. Chiefly among
these is Salesforce, which cat has made his personal dragon to
slay.

One day cat may return to the desert and teach it the secrets he
has learned. It is said you can find hints of these secrets buried
underground in the depths of his latest baby, if you know where to
look.

Remember what cat does for us each and every day and give thanks.

cat
    gopher://baud.baby/1/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Busses</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190902-busses/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
busses
September 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I never spent much time on busses growing up. We were a car family
in the suburbs. I either rode my bike places or we drove a car.
Nothing was accessible by foot, and busses didnt run close by.

Upon moving to Reykjavík we decided to go without a car for the
first year to save money and get to know the area more intimately.
It forces me to walk place to place, which is exercise I need, and
it slows the pace of life.

Today I wanted to buy new 3D filament. I've only found one store
that sells it so far, and it took me almost two hours to get there
and make the purchase with all the transfers. A single errand is
a day's outing. 

Even now as I'm on the bus home I feel a strange reaction from
completing a simple task. It reminds me of the pleasures of the
Slow Internet.

My wife went grocery shopping this morning. She walked the 2 km
into town (down a big hill and up another) then shopped and rode
the bus home. She accomplished something more significant than it
would have been by car.

This is all of mind due to the convergence of solderpunk's
ROOPHLOCH and kensanata's thread on creating, or rather the notion
of being productive. It seems to me that the method contributes so
much to the worth that I'm not sure end products are of much use in
determining quality of time spent.

Another case in point, sewing. I routinely did the sewing in our
last home by machine. It gave satisfaction for creation, but since
moving all my needle work has been by hand. It took me an hour to
make finger puppets for my son, but the satisfaction scaled more
rapidly than the increased effort. Some of that may be novelty, but
the same could be said for the machine.

Working manually by choice gives strange fruit.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hammer Time Extended</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190901-hammer-time-extended/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Hammer Time! (extended)
September 01st, 2019
----------------------------------------

We got a few submissions in for the first zine by midnight last
night, but a few people expressed disappointment that they'd
forgotten. So... Let's do a small extension. I'm not going to
start assembly on whatever weird format this thing will take until
next weekend. That means that any stragglers out there have until
Saturday morning GMT to toss your hammer in.

Thanks to everyone who submitted or will. I think this will be
a fun little thing.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Lambdalab Email Thoughts</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190827-re-lambdalab-email-thoughts/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: lambdalab - email thoughts
August 27th, 2019
----------------------------------------

The lambda lab wrote [0] about setting up email and asked for some
thoughts on relaying that mail to others around gopherspace. I do
something like that on cosmic.voyage. Namely, I have installed and
enabled postfix to allow for outbound emails only to specific
hosts. [1,2] Since I'm targeting other tildes and not big email
providers I don't need to worry about ending up on spam lists
because of unauthenticated emails to Biggy-G. It also means I can
be lazy about it.

If you're using the host yourself and not sharing it with others
then you don't even need to go that far. Just be selective about
who you email, I guess.

But honestly, setting up DKIM, SPF, etc, isn't too bad these days.
The hard part is dealing with the Notorious-G and others
blacklisting you because they don't care, forcing you to manually
intercede and get clearance. The last time I dealt with that with
them I had to do a bunch of extra crap to figure out how to see
the error message that had some obscure URL they wanted me to
visit. Yuck.

[0] thelambdalab - email thoughts
    gopher://70/0/phlog/2019-08-27-Email-woes.txtthelambdalab.xyz
[1] postfix transport
    ttps://tildegit.org/cosmic/cosmic/src/branch/master/postfix/transport
[2] postfix transport install
    https://tildegit.org/cosmic/cosmic/src/branch/master/Makefile#L55-L62
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Music As Milestone</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190816-music-as-milestone/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
music as milestone
August 16th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Passing through major change makes itself manifest in a number of
ways. For me, one of the most notable is a musical genre shift.

At the end of a long and tumultuous relationship I set out on
a thirteen hour drive home, newly single, skipping through
stations at 5am in search of something to capture the hole I felt
inside. I caught the beginning of Mountain Stage on NPR (National
Public Radio) as a trio was just starting out. The band, The Be
Good Tanyas [0], are a folk/Americana band from Canada. They
started out their set with a cover of the gospel song, "In My Time
of Dying", most famously performed by Led Zeppelin & Blind Willie
Johnson [1].

[0] The Be Good Tanyas
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/The Be Good Tanyas
[1] In My Time of Dying
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=352KDhl4i4c

There it was, the resonating echo of my inner self. I was hooked
and would go on to binge the bluegrassy/folk/Americana
scene--especially the likes of Jolie Holland--to great depths over
the next few years. It was a music for the time.

Years earlier I experienced something similar with Enya that you
can all thank for my multi-hour "All Enya" streams on tilderadio.
Joining the Navy took me on a wild ride of electronica and
euro-vocal-trance. My time in Alaska introduced me to the depths
of Nordic electronic minimalism.

And so, with the move to Iceland I expected something to develop.
I know that my tastes would shift. I already adore so many
Icelandic bands, would that grow and encompass a major part of my
life? Would I slide deeper into the fediverse's obsession with
vaporwave? Apparently the answer is no.

Somehow--illogically--I've found myself listening to Reggae [2,3].

[2] Mike Love - Permanent Holiday
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fU7hZ3smj0g
[3] Chronixx - Here Comes Trouble
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LfeIfiiBTfY

I'm not sure if I can say definitively that this is my new jam,
but it sure is happening a lot. I guess it proves that you can't
predict what the future will hold.

What are your signs of change? Do you change tastes in music like
me, or is it something else? Change nicknames? Take up new
hobbies?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Making Vf 1 Sexy</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190806-making-vf-1-sexy/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Making VF-1 Sexy
August 06th, 2019
----------------------------------------

VF-1 is fast, but it's also pretty basic. It doesn't (yet) do
pretty colors by types or anything sweet like that. Many of you
are probably fine with that. "Colors are useless" people... I 
hear you, but I don't agree.

In fact, even if the colors aren't structured, I still want them!
I've been piping my VF-1 output through lolcat for a few months.
It's brilliant, but was incomplete.

Not to mention any names, but some of you don't wrap your text. I
try not to be picky about whether wrapping happens at 80cols or at
67cols, but when a gopher doesn't wrap at all it makes it very
hard to read. I'll be honest, I usually just skim those posts as a
result.

"Why," I ask myself, "don't they just run it through fold(1)?"

"Duh," I answer myself, "they don't want to or don't care."

"But self, it would make my reading more convenient!"

"Come'on, tomasino. What part of _don't care_ did you not get?"

"I suppose you have a point. You're pretty smart."

"Damn right..."

"So..."

"Oh crap--"

"Why don't you solve it on the client end?"

And I sigh and say, "Of course. VF-1 lets me lolcat. Why not fold
as well? It should be simple."

If you don't care about lolcat and only want to fold output
automatically in VF-1, here's what you do. Add the following line
to your ~/.vf1rc:

  $ cat ~/.vf1rc

  handler text/plain fold -sw 80 %s


If you want to lolcat it too, like me, then you need to do a
little bit more. I'm not sure what method VF-1 uses internally to
parse the handlers, but it chokes hard on pipes. So, I wrote a very,
very basic shell script to do it for me.

  $ cat ~/bin/goph

  #!/bin/sh
  FIN=${1:-"/dev/stdin"}
  fold -sw 80 "$FIN" | lolcat -f
 
Put that in your PATH and now you can pipe anything you want to
'goph' and have it be pretty. It'll also take a file input. Then,
in your ~/.vf1rc, you can add:

  $ cat ~/.vf1rc

  handler text/plain goph %s

Let there be color, and pretty wrapping. Enjoy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gemini First Impressions</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190729-gemini-first-impressions/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Gemini first impressions
July 29th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I finally spent the 5 minutes necessary to download one of the few
available Gemini clients. I went with AV-98 [0] from solderpunk.
It's interface is basically the same as VF-1, so it had that going
for it. Also, I didn't need to download a rust compiler. ;)

[0] AV-98
    https://tildegit.org/solderpunk/AV-98

While there's not a lot of content around gemini-space (more on
this in a second), it was still nice to have a way in to poke
around. I see some journal activity already taking shape, and
that's a great place to start.

I'll be honest. At first I thought of Gemini as a neat but
ultimately useless side project of the already-tiny gopher
community. The more I've seen it worked on and thought about it
the more I've come to consider it a "real thing" of some
importance. But lets come back to that idea in a minute.

First, lets talk about the naming of things.

"Gemini" is the protocol. It appears to be capitalized in all
occurences within solderpunk's FAQ. 

"Gemini maps" are the temporary term for the document format of
a Gemini server. It's coined by solderpunk here [1] and only named
that "until a better name comes along."

[1] Gemini maps
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/gemini/gemini-maps.txt

"Geminiholes" - mentioned by solderpunk, but noone is using it.

"Gemini server/client" are the defacto name for individual tools
that power it.

"Gemini-verse / Gemini-sphere / Gemini ecosystem" - I haven't
noted any special term for this akin to "the web" or
"gopherspace". Is there something already in use?

"Journal" - weB LOG / goPHer LOG like structure. Is there
a playful term for these yet?

What other terms are we missing?

Okay, enough of that. Time for THOUGHTS OF IMPORTANCE!

The built-in TLS by design of Gemini is great, and combined with
the natural ability to run it unpriviliged and require very little
bandwidth I can see it serving a valuable purpose in safely
providing a platform for authors in situations where the web is
not. Take Khazikstan, for instance, who is MITMing the entire
country. Gopher was always a nice idea to help in these
situations, but the lack of reliable security on it meant major
problems for real applications. Gemini fixes that. What's more,
Gemini over tor adds in anonymity.

I have more thoughts on the tor thing, and around real-world
applications for a minimalist hyperlinkable publishing protocol
with built in anonymity and safety, but my internet connection is
dying and I have to finish this post while tethered to my phone.
Thank goodness for low bandwidth stuff like gopher and Gemini,
right?

In the meantime, what are your thoughts on using Gemini (one day)
in a setting that's not just hobby play?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Zine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190719-zine/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
zine
July 19th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I'm going to make a zine.

SDF said they were going to do one last year and I volunteered to
contribute, but it seems like nothing came of it. So, what the
hell, lets get our zine on.

Are you unfamiliar with zines? A zine is a small-circulation
self-published work of original or appropriated texts and images,
usually reproduced via photocopier. (Thanks Gopherpedia) [0] They
were really big in the early 90s. They also went digital and there
was a whole Usenet alt for them at one point. Here, check out
a famous hacker one. [1]

[0] Zine
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Zine
[1] Phrack
    gopher://fnord.one/1/Mirrors/Phrack/Archive/Issues/

I've got some ideas around this zine, so let me blast you in the
face with some awesome. 

1. Issues will be published in entirely arbitrary times. I'm not
   going to make this a regular thing, and I'm not promising
   you'll see an issue number 3.

2. The format is mutable. You may get a PDF for one, a weird
   side-scrolling website for another, or a weird port listener
   interactive experience [2] that fails to meet any common
   definition.

8[2] Allegra	help	cosmic.voyage	1822

3. There will be a theme to each issue. The glue that binds it all
   together will be the theme (and possibly horse parts). Expect
   wild takes on the theme, possible nonsense.

4. It must be community driven.

   Here's where you come in! See, I want to put it all together
   and have fun and stuff, but I don't want to create 100% of the
   weird crap on my own. So, I figure I'll announce the theme and
   give you guys a way to contact me if you're interested in
   contributing.

   In fact, lets just cut to that part right now.

The yet-to-be-named zine will have its inaugural issue soon. If
you'd like to be a contributor, it's easy! Here's what you do:

- Contact me via email. You can find my addresses in the About
  page on this gopher hole [3].

[3] About me!
    gopher://gopher.black/1/about

- Tell me that you want to contribute something. You don't need to
  tell me what it is you want to contribute. I don't care what
  format it is in, whether it's words or art or music or a dance.
  I don't care if you're cutting out cardboard creatures and
  snaping pics of them doing naughty shit. If it fits the theme,
  go to town.

- Meet the deadline. I'll set a date when I need stuff by. Gimme
  access to whatever you've done by then or I'll assume you flaked
  out again, Jeff.

- Let me know if you want to be identified, or how you want to be
  identified for your work.

- Bask in the glory. Seriously. This is a requirement. No sitting
  back and gracefully accepting praise is allowed. You MUST bask
  in the glory. I'll be watching.

So, what's the theme of this first issue, already? What format
will it take? When's the deadline? What other questions can I ask
as I type out this phlog because I'm stalling while I try to make
a decision on the fly? Who else expected that I knew these answers
before I started this post? Did anyone really expect me to have
a well thought out plan here, or is it obvious this is coming out
of my butt right now? Is my internal monologue-turned-gopher-phlog
making you smile at least?

The theme is...

                            HAMMER

Yep, Hammer. What sort of Hammer am I talking about? Is it the
former M.C.? Or maybe the tool? Or the sport? Or maybe the
weapon!? Or maybe it's the part of a gun you cock (teehee). Or the
tiny bones in your ear. Or maybe it's something else entirely. I'm
not saying! You figure it out, suckas.

As for the format of the first zine... that depends on what sort
of shit I get back. I'm not telling you, so you can go off the
deep end if you want. I'll just have to deal with whatever comes
in. 

Again, absolutely ANYTHING is okay to submit if it fits the theme
in any way. If you have a stirring and deviant fursona fanfic of
Logan's Run that you've been dying to share, then find a way to
make it about HAMMER and you're in. If you want to draw me
a picture of a HAMMER, cool. Maybe you have a really good
technique for keying in MORSE? That arm thingy is kinda like
a HAMMER, right? Be creative, be technical, be personal, be
awesome.

Also, I'm not censoring anything here. If you have stuff that's
wildly inappropriate, bring. it. on.

So, when's the due date? Hmmmmm....

                          Tomorrow!



                       no. not really.

      That sounded fun in my head, but it would be idiotic.


                       Let's go with...



                         August 31st.
                        
Got it? That's just over a month to put together something,
anything, that can be shoved into a weird-ass package and put out
into the intertubes. Once I get all the shizzle, I'll make
something fo-rizzle. Capice?

Now, my minions, GO FORTH AND CREATE! (and also email me if you're
doing something so I know that this is gonna work).
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Some Replies From Iceland</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190705-some-replies-from-iceland/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Some replies from Iceland
July 05th, 2019
----------------------------------------

Hi everybody! I'm in Iceland now. We moved this past weekend and
we're settled in an airbnb for July getting everything in place.
If you're interested in my expat adventures, that's something I'm
writing over in web-land so my parents and wife's friends can
follow. Check it out [0].

[0] tomasino blog
    https://blog.tomasino.org

Tonight I thought it would be fun to take stock of recent things
happening on gopher and send some feedback. So, here goes:

moji, over on circumlunar, has detailed their efforts to cut back
on the caffeine [1]. It's a solid post and raises some good
thoughts on what it means to be reliant on something like coffee.
Addictions, even relatively benign ones, have some hold on you.
I can totally respect the effort. More power too you.

[1] moji - caffeine
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~moji/phlog/20190107-caffeine.txt

pkotrcka, whose name I have to be very careful typing out, wrote
a neat phlog about cameras that put my head in weird places [2].
Mainly it made me sad that photography is pretty much dead.
I mean, not really at all, but as a profession it's gone from this
highly technical artform with super expensive equipment, years of
training required and it's been overrun by quick snaps with your
phone and bottled filters. There's little spots left for the art,
like wedding photos and... is that it? Really though it's a "dead"
technology in the same way gopher is.

There's the part where my mind turned happy again. When we say
it's dead that just means that capitalism stopped seeing monetary
value. That's not the same thing at all. Why is there no money in
gopher? Well, not enough people to be worth the effort investing.
Photography? Same thing. Niche stuff sure, but other than than
just let it return to the afficianados. Let the pkotrckas of the
world have their fun, right? Keep on keeping on, pkotrcka.

[2] pkotrcka - cameras
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/pkotrcka/0022

The amazing, incredible visiblink did some hard work recently
cleaning up insulation and maybe asbestos [3]. Well done. That's
not what I wanted to comment on at all, though. At the very end of
the phlog they mention that the gopher hole switched over to a pi
zero w, saving more power. I love this ultra-low power stuff.
I have some basic notes on how I stripped my pi zero down to the
minimum draw for the little free library project. I recommend
checking it out in my archives for tidbits.

[3] visiblink - asbestos
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~visiblink/phlog/20190702

Ubergeek kayaking with son

ubergeek got his son out kayaking and that's so awesome [4].
I adore kayaking. It was really sad having to sell my kayak when
we moved. There's something really ... perfect about being out on
the water. I can close my eyes and feel myself relax just thinking
about it.

I learned to kayak in Alaska in Resurrection Bay, near Seward. It
was cold and beautiful. I saw bears and salmon and eagles and was
forever in love. I love lakes now. They're so smooth and you can
just pull yourself a bit with the paddles and drift away.

Anyway, I can see why his son is connecting with it. I wish you
both the best. It's some special stuff, there. Good dad-ing.

[4] ubergeek - kayaking
    gopher://yourtilde.com/0/~ubergeek/feels/20190703.txt

Our pal heavysquare sent me an email the other day asking me to
point his phlog roll post to the root directory where he's added
a really killer gophermap. There's so much more to see than just
the "noise" phlog I had there before. Check him out [5].

[5] heavysquare
    gopher://heavysquare.com/1/

Finally, there was a lot of talk this past week about Gemini's
link syntax [6,7,8]. Out goes the [|] and in comes the =>. I'm
into it, guys. It's cool as heck. Here's my 2-cents:

1. Spaces optional. You can split on whitespace easy enough with
   regex alone and not care if it's one space, zero, or
   a tab-space-tab-space salsa.

2. Link first. We're talking about clients doing some magic in the
   gemini world, but how much should we rely on the client's
   display choices to fulfill that important note that a URL
   should always be shown. If we have it at the end it could get
   cropped off screen or hidden in a wrap or any number of things.
   Link first is more likely to be seen, easier to parse across
   languages, and MOST importantly, means that the label can be
   optional. 

   You see how I'm linking to things paragraph by paragraph in
   this post? I have numbers referencing things with the square
   bracket syntax because it's my convention, but the position of
   the links in context to the copy says enough about what they
   are. In many cases I just described the link in a paragraph and
   the label on the link is redundant. If the label in gemini is
   optional then you can just do something like:

   => gemini://cosmic.voyage

   And let it live on its own.

[6] solderpunk - quick update on link syntax
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/gemini/quick-update-on-link-syntax.txt
[7] ascraeus - peter frampton reference
    gopher://ascraeus.org/0/phlog/019.txt
[8] sloum - commentary on link syntax
    gopher://colorfield.space/1/~sloum/phlog/190704-21.txt

Thanks gophers. Keep gophin' around.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
