<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>The Left/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180717-the-left/</link>
  <pubdate>17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Left
July 17th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I just received the following email on an account I have which
monitors conservative political action. I have similar feelers
into a few different areas so I can keep tabs on things. This one
stood out, especially in light of Trump's recent meeting with
Putin.


----------------------------------------
|   Authorized By Trump Headquarters   |
----------------------------------------

James,

Have you seen the Democrats lately?

They're completely unhinged.

They’re all over this country vowing to go further and further to
the Left. For weeks, they’ve been calling for harassment,
intimidation, even the abolishment of ICE! Now, they’re promising
to block President Trump’s Supreme Court nominee from ever
reaching the bench.

They want to ignore our laws, abuse our people, and obstruct our
agenda by subjecting Judge Kavanaugh to a long, drawn out
confirmation process.

They think their new tactics will chase all “deplorables” into
hiding… but the silent majority is not backing down. We’re getting
together and we’re standing up. We’re knocking on doors and
reaching voters for our National Week of Action to protect our
President and make sure we win big in November.

And we need YOU to join us by going door to door to spread our
message
 
REGISTER TO VOLUNTEER

James, the way I see it, if liberals want to come for our borders,
for our jobs, and OUR Supreme Court, and they’re willing to stop
at nothing to make that happen.

We CAN win for the Silent Majority -- not by stooping down to the
left’s level -- but by volunteering in your neighborhood to turn
out voters and spread our positive message of putting America
FIRST.

Please, join us for the National Week of Action.

Thank you,

Chris Carr
Donald J. Trump for President, Political Director

------------------------------------------------------------------

What struck me most was the blatant use of the Left as an entity
of otherness. Notice that it's the Left coming for OUR borders,
Supreme Court, laws, and jobs. The Left wants to abuse OUR people.
This is an interesting and dangerous shift in rhetoric. It is
essentially calling liberals anti-American and digging deeper the
divide.

In a similar email last month the language used was based on
fighting, shooting, and violence in general. "Strike back!" they
cheer.

This is the stuff that later generations will point to with
disgust and say, "how did they not see it coming?"
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cwondr/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180716-cwondr/</link>
  <pubdate>16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CWONDR
July 16th, 2018
----------------------------------------

yargo writes [0] about a cool Morse/CW project he's working on.
A low-power, pocket-sized CW transceiver for the 430 Mhz band: for
Morse code. I love it! I don't have much interest in getting into
HAM stuff (mainly because I know it would end up being a huge time
sink for me) but I love Morse and I think I could dig something
little and portable like this. If you make it, I'll use one!

[0] yargo - CWONDR, another Morse/CW project
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/yargo/glog/t18414-cwondr.txt

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Flashcards/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180714-flashcards/</link>
  <pubdate>14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Flashcards
July 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

User jakob phlogged recently [0] about getting back into flash
cards & spaced repetition. He found a fantastic solution using
emacs as he seems to be slowly adopting the "all things are emacs"
principle. I'm not quite to that extreme with vim, but I do love
me some command line solutions.

[0] jakob - replacing anki with org-drill
    gopher://jakob.space/0/phlog/replacing_anki_with_org_drill/text

Plain text is just simpler. I don't need fancy guis for 99% of my
stuff. Flash cards are definitely in that list. So, what's a man
to do? Obviously the only solution is to roll my own!

I started by searching a bit on the different styles of spaced
repetition (there are many) and quickly settled on the Leitner
System. It's usable by hand, so I should clearly be able to
replicate it with a program, right? It turns out that there's not
really any agreement on the specifics of the system. I watched
several videos on youtube who would almost get there and then say
something that didn't make any sense. The wikipedia page is such
a hot mess I'm not even going to link you there. If you want to
read some train wreck stuff, you'll need to go there on your own.

In the end I settled on the following as my interpretation of
Leitner:

- Flash cards get a front and a back
- Flash cards are sorted into levels based on your proficiency
  with the card
- All cards start at level 1
- Cards move up one level when you successfully identify the back
- Cards return all the way to level 1 if you fail to successfully
  identify the back in time
- Time is important. Sitting there staring at a card and working
  it out is not the same as "getting it right". That is a failure.
- The number of proficiency levels you use isn't important
- The frequency of cards being shown is determined by the level:
  - Cards at level 1 are shown every day
  - Cards at level 2 are shown every other day
  - Cards at level 3 are shown every 3rd day
  - Cards at level 4 are shown every 4th day
  - and so on
- Cards are reviewed only once per session with the exception of
  cards at level 1. They can be reviewed multiple times until they
  move to level 2.

I started putting together these notes yesterday into a README
file intending to build a bourne shell app like I did with burrow.
I was reminded by a coworker that I said I'd build something in
node soon, so I caved and used javascript instead. Yes, I felt
incredibly dirty the whole time. Even worse, it was really, really
fun and easy. Puke.

If you have node installed you can try out my app by running:

  yarn global add flashleit
  or
  npm i -g flashleit

That's right.... Flashleit! Get it? Leitner... Flash Cards...
Huzzah!

When you run the app you can start by adding cards. There's a menu
option for it. Cards creation will launch your $EDITOR. Card
fronts & backs can be multi-line. Ascii art welcome!

You can also mess with some of the settings in the app. Change
some colors, change the maximum proficiency level, or the delay
before the card flip happens. There's more color settings in the
configuration file if you want to go digging. It's usually at:

  ~/.config/config/configstore/flashleit.json

but it may vary on your system. All the data is stored in that one
file, including your cards. If you want to import a list or
generate one, just look at the pattern in there and mess with the
JSON itself. You're big kids.

Source is over on github [1]. If you try it out and have any
recommendations or spot any bugs, leave me an issue there. 

[1] flashleit on github
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/flashleit
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Jynx On Life Segmentation And Happiness/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180711-re-jynx-on-life-segmentation-and-happiness/</link>
  <pubdate>11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: jynx on life segmentation and happiness
July 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

jynx wrote [0] a note about separation of life and employment and
the freedom it's given him. It's been an extremely helpful read
for me and helped me put things back in perspective. I keep
re-reading it.

[0] jynx - On life segmentation and happiness
    gopher://gopher.club/0/users/jynx/phlog/typezero/20180709.post
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Freelance/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180709-freelance/</link>
  <pubdate>09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Freelance
July 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm not sure why I bother with freelance. I mean, I like having
some extra income, but I'm so burnt out from work already, do
I really want more?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shut It Down/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180708-shut-it-down/</link>
  <pubdate>08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
shut it down
July 08th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Sometimes the little frustrations add up and spill over. I tend to
get very quiet when I'm at my breaking point. I shut down. I walk
away. When I was young I'd walk away in grandiose ways: from
relationships, jobs, responsibility. I've learned how to siphon
off the steam before reaching that point. I meditate, I walk,
I pray. I can roll with it a lot more than when I was a kid.
Still, sometimes it feels like it would be easier to shut it all
down and walk away from my life. It's not a rational thought. My
life is pretty damn good. The frustrations are minor things,
meaningless really. You can't compare lives that way, though. It's
not rational, as I said, and it's not logical.

I'm going to drink a nice glass of gin, read a bit, and go for an
evening walk. Tomorrow will start a busy work-week and I'll be
walking into it already stressed. It's not a good recipe.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Keyboard/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180706-new-keyboard/</link>
  <pubdate>06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
New keyboard
July 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Today marked the arrival of my newest mechanical keyboard,
a Planck from Massdrop. Planck is an ortholinear, minimalist,
mechanical keyboard. It's just 4 rows tall (no number row or
Fkeys). It supports multiple layers, though, so you can switch
between keymaps, or meta-layers, or whatever else floats your
boat. Right now I'm running with two layers [0]:

 - Dvorak
 - Num-pad & arrows

The Planck comes as a kit that you need to assemble. That means
laying out the PCB and base plate and popping all the key switches
in to place (careful to align the pins just right). Then there was
a great deal of soldering. I'm happy to say it went smoothly and
I had no issues with my joints whatsoever. The board is then
screwed into the milled bottom, some rubber feet are attached, and
you're good to go.

In my case I also had to flash the firmware to get my sexy layout
installed. There was a hiccup there as the software I was using to
create the layout had placed the spacebar in the wrong location.
Everything worked but the space! I actually took it all apart,
remove the switch, resoldered in a replacement, only to find out
that it wasn't a hardware issue at all. I changed one setting in
my firmware and we're all good again.

I'll need to practice using it, especially the layer changes.
Here's hoping I pick it up quickly. I suspect this will become my
favorite little keyboard buddy.

[0] Tomasino's Keyboard Firmware
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/tomasino-dvorak-keyboard
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Space Gopher 2000/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180705-space-gopher-2000/</link>
  <pubdate>05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Space Gopher 2000
July 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

What if quantum entaglement and spooky action at a distance allow
for us to create extremely long range connections, but with very
low bandwidth. "Why would that be the case?" you might ask.
Frankly, I have no idea. If you don't think about the details too
much it seems like something you could gloss over in a story,
though.

I want to explore that idea in a short story as a vehicle to
reintroduce gopher as the web of the space-future. No nonsense,
text driven communication across vast spaces would make for an
incredible aesthetic and a great reason to draw some attention
back to port 70.

I think of films like Alien and their use of text for
communication and it makes sense to me. Local running AIs and
super-powerful UI crap is neat, but for anything at a distance we
fall back on the age-old safety of text. If you imagine a universe
populated by ships launched and traveling at relativistic speeds,
we quickly encounter vast distances in relative time, not only
space. These time gaps are a bigger threat to communication than
distance. We cannot innovate because it leaves behind all those
that have gone out before. We cannot shift paradigms. We must
speak to a common level.

Isn't that a cool thought? I want to read stuff in that universe.
I want gopher featured prominantly. I guess I should start working
on it at some point.

Do any of you have any ideas to pile on top? I don't have a story
here at all, just setting, so I could use all the help I can get.
Or, I guess if one of you is feeling the creative juices flowing,
take it and run. I want to read it more than I want to write it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Myths And Truth/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180705-myths-and-truth/</link>
  <pubdate>05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Myths and truth
July 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Joseph Campbell was fond of saying that all myths are true. His
line of thinking is that the myths we know and that our societies
have developed are culturally dependant expressions of a universal
story. 

In comparative mythology or comparative religion we see the same
aspects echoed across time and space. In his mind there were two
possible reasons why:

  1. There are similarities in human psychology and physiology
     that lead us to generate the same responses to our
     experiences regardless of culture and climate.

  2. There is a shared truth which all of our myths and symbols
     help us to express. That expression is unique to our culture
     but it speaks to a universal truth which itself is ineffable.

That is a tragically simplified summary, but it should do for my
purposes as there's only a small point I'd like to make regarding
myths. 

  Myths are not true, they reveal truth.

When Catholics look at the bible and read the story of creation,
that story is a myth [0]. It is not literal. It is there to teach
us something about creation in language and stories that make
sense to the culture of the time. This reading with a cultural
lens is vital to a Catholic reading of scripture, even the
Gospels.

[0] Genesis 1
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Genesis/genesis-1.txt

In the book of Luke [1], there is a passage that should be
familiar to even the most lapsed of Christians. It is the story of
Mary and Joseph arriving in Bethlehem for the birth of Jesus:

  In those days a decree went out from Caesar Augustus that all
  the world should be registered. This was the first registration
  when Quirinius was governor of Syria. And all went to be
  registered, each to his own town. And Joseph also went up from
  Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of
  David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house
  and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed,
  who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for
  her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and
  wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger,
  because there was no place for them in the inn. [1]

[1] Luke 2
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Luke/luke-2.txt

I want to focus on just two phrases in this paragraph:

  "he was of the house and lineage of David"

  and

  "laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in
  the inn."

Starting with the first phrase, this is an important note for
a few reasons, biblically. It touches on prophecy fulfillment
because it satisfies the messianic idea that the figure will come
from the house of David. It is also important because of the
political implications of the house itself. The house of David was
the most prestigious of the Jewish people, after all. Heading to
the ancestral home of that people is a big deal in a culture
dominated by family value. This is a key point to remember in the
story, too. Mary and Joseph aren't going to some small town in the
middle of nowhere. They're going to the home of the wealthiest,
most prestigious family. The people of the house of David would be
many. This is not a land of strangers for them.

It's also important to remember that for these people at the time
there is a great emphasis put on the idea of hospitality. Elijah
is going to return, and they must be ready. He may come in the
guise of a beggar to your door. And so, welcoming in the traveler
has a major role in daily life. It has such a role, that it even
affected the architecture of first century Palestine.

The typical home at the time was made up of two main rooms. The
first was the family's room. It would be raised up off the ground
a few feet and be all open. On one side there would be a ledge
that drops down to ground level as the room extends into the
animal enclosure. The animals would stay inside in poor weather or
seasons, and their heat would be shared by the family. On the
floor by this ledge were impressions in the ground where feed was
placed: the manger.

The second room was attached, often with a separate entrance. This
was the guest house or reception room, and it was intended for
visitors and extended family. We see such a room referenced twice
in the bible by the Greek word kataluma. A kataluma is the room
used by Jesus and his disciples during the last supper. It is also
the word used in this paragraph and translated as "inn".

In the ancient world there were no hotels. The closest you might
find was a tent filled with straw mats, called a caravansary. This
word was translated to "inn" during the story of the good
Samaritan. When the man is injured and placed in the inn for care,
that was a caravansary. In Luke we're talking about a very
different thing.

Taken together with our understanding of Jewish culture and the
importance of the family of David, it is inconceivable to imagine
the holy family alone in a barn on that first Christmas. The
kataluma was full, so they were instead brought into the family
room in communion with many others. When the child was born he was
placed there in the manger where all could see him.

So why do I bring this up? It isn't to criticize those poor
Christmas pageants. It's to talk about the myths.

The story of Jesus birth is not vital to the story of his teaching
or his role within the faith. If Jesus is born in the midst of the
most powerful Jewish family instead of alone in a barn, there's no
fundamental truth being assaulted. In fact, if you spent your
entire life believing one idea vs the other idea, it would have
almost no bearing on your understanding of Jesus at all. Does that
mean it doesn't matter? Does that suggest that a bunch of these
stories are filler and don't have an impact on us? Well, no, not
exactly.

The stories, the myths, and our comprehension of them are trying
to tell us something, but it's almost never the literal histories.
Here in the story of Christ's birth we are being made to
understand his place in the culture of the Jewish people, and his
relationship to the prophets that came before him. In this way we
can understand that he is legitimate. His role is appropriate.
He's not just some guy who found a bunch of metal plates in his
backyard [2].

[2] Problems with the gold plates
    http://www.equip.org/article/problems-with-the-gold-plates-of-the-book-of-mormon-2/

Each myth is meant to communicate something to us that words alone
can't. They are intricately tied to the culture of their creation,
and when that culture changes so must the myths. Without this
change they become distance, misaligned, and misconstrued. Before
you know it you are taking words from Leviticus and applying them
to a whole different world.

  As for your male and female slaves whom you may have: you may
  buy male and female slaves from among the nations that are
  around you. [3]

[3] Leviticus 25
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Leviticus/leviticus-25.txt

Whether we're looking at stories of the Buddha or Brahman,
Gicelemû’kaong or Birrahgnooloo, the myths create and communicate
our understanding of their truth. The myths are not the truth, but
they are true, all of them. 
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Essence Of Gopher/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180703-the-essence-of-gopher/</link>
  <pubdate>03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The essence of gopher
July 03rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Our dear friend cat is at it again. He recently flew the coop
from SDF and has planted his seed in a new project called
baud.baby [0]. He's a resourceful guy and has quickly conquered
some of the more tedious aspects of getting your own gopher hole
up and running. Kudos, cat!

[0] baud.baby
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20180628.txt

His most recent phlog touches on one of his passions, vintage
phones [1]. In my humble opinion it is EVERYTHING that gopher
should be summed up into a microcosm of aussie geekdom. It has
passion for a vintage technology, collection, curation, more
technical details than you could have imagined, and a neverending
thirst for more. It's also beautiful. His manual text layouts
really shine on things like his phone collection page [2].

[1] A bunch of Touchfone stuff
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20180703.txt
[2] Weirdly Specific Collection of Phones
    gopher://baud.baby/1/phones

I've run across similarly brilliant curation in places like
mateusz's DOS software repository [3], or Logout's new ASCII table
[4], or dbucklin's intelligence analysis documents [5]. This stuff
is gopher gold. 

[3] mateusz's DOS software repository
    gopher://gopher.viste.fr/1/abandonware
[4] Logout's ASCII table
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/en/ascii
[5] dbucklin's Intelligence Analysis Documents
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/dbucklin/files

I've been really phlog focused in the past, but I think that
overlooked some of the best stuff around. Now I'm finally starting
to add more links to these collections and repositories over on my
Gopher Places [6] section. Check it out and discover some awesome.

[6] Gopher Places
    gopher://gopher.black/1/places
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
