<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Divination</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200717-divination/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
divination
July 17th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A few days ago I coded a shell-script version of the I Ching (Book
of Changes), and made it accessible on Gemini [0]. In the process
I added a note on the Gemini site quickly addressing some concerns
over the use of digital tools for divination. It all felt rushed
and incomplete and I think I have more to say on the subject,
perhaps a lot more. Gemini isn't the place for that, though. This
is definitely a gopher topic.

[0] I Ching Shell Script
    https://github.com/jamestomasino/iching

I practice a number of forms of divination including consulting
the I Ching, tarot cards, tasseography, cleromancy (whether with
dice, dominos, or runes), and so on. There's a number of forms
I don't practice for various reasons: horoscopy, gematria,
extispicy (ew), ouija, augury, and oh so many more. Someone has
figured out a way to use just about anything for divination.

Before we get too far into this, let me drop some dictionary magic
on you. Here's the definition from two online dictionaries: 

  Divination: 
  
  1. the practice of seeking knowledge of the future or the
     unknown by supernatural means

  2. the art or practice that seeks to foresee or foretell future
     events or discover hidden knowledge usually by the
     interpretation of omens or by the aid of supernatural powers

Seeking knowledge, usually hidden knowledge, by the aid of the
supernatural. Cool. Got it?

So there are a billion forms of divination out there, but why? Do
they all work? Do any of them work? How do they purport to work?
Lets focus on the last bit first. How does divination work? This
is the interesting bit for me at least.

In cleromancy the mechanism of action is some sort of randomness.
Cleromancy is about "tossing stuff" like dice and seeing what
comes up. Some practitioners suggest that the randomness allows
the supernatural to take direct action and influence the results
of the toss. Other practitioners would say that the toss and its
randomness is just that and not influenced by the supernatural,
but the querent (person seeking information) must use their
intuition to understand the results of the toss. That type of
practitioner moves the supernatural action internal to the
unconscious mind and changes its domain of action to the
interpretation alone. But there are still other types! Some see
the unconscious mind as affecting the toss itself in a sort of
blend of the first two. Others shy away from intuition and suggest
self-reflection and psychology allow the interpretation of any
symbol to be helpful as a means of thinking in a new way about the
issue.

Yeesh, that's a lot, and that's just cleromancy! But what about
chartomancy (books & cards)? Is the mechanism of action different?

On the one hand, there are far more established symbols present
in, say, a tarot card than in a rune. Consulting the I Ching or
the Bible likewise greatly increases the available symbols and
interpretations. The act itself is still governed by some sort of
randomness, or chaotic action as I like to call it. Shuffling
cards, separating yarrow stalks, even flipping pages promotes some
sort of uncertainty and allows for the possibility of and unknown.

Does this unknown mean that a supernatural power is guiding the
result? That's a matter of faith and, ultimately, irrelevant. What
about the interpretation? Is that guided by a supernatural power?
Again, a question of faith that has no ultimate bearing on the
value of divination. What‽

Yeah, you read me correctly. I'm saying that it doesn't matter if
there's no supernatural involved at all or if there is. The aim of
divination is to seek to foresee the future or discover hidden
knowledge and divination can succeed in  both cases regardless of
the origin of its power.

Lets side with the pragmatic doubter practitioner for a moment and
assume that there's no magic at work here at all. We're going to
go through some exercise that will result in symbols ready for
interpretation. The process we have just taken was designed to
orient our mind to the problem, focus upon it seriously, perhaps
spending a significant amount of time in so doing. We are now
asked to review and interpret these forms which have a variety of
possible meanings requiring we try to apply them systematically
and in various combinations to the problem or subject. That
thought process involves mental judo and an openness to new ideas.
It will inevitably bring insight and... wait for it... hidden
knowledge. It will also undoubtedly influence future actions and
have a major impact on the events to come. BAM! Divined.

Now, allow yourself to take the seat as an individual who has
faith in the machinations of the supernatural. Given even a hint
of influence from that "other", the results gain significance and
their origins may carry more weight, but the interpretation and
internalization of that information is unchanged. It really
doesn't matter.

I really enjoy the processes, especially the lengthy ones with
much ritual like the yarrow stalk I Ching method, or the ones that
are inherently delicious like tasseography (reading tea leaves).

If I have any advice to give on the subject it is to enter into
divination with healthy skepticism, not to undermine the results
but to fully engage with them. Don't take any reading at face
value or you've done yourself a disservice.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What Is Gemini</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200612-what-is-gemini/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
What is Gemini?
June 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Last night I recorded a video about the new Gemini protocol [0],
created by solderpunk [1] which has been _taking off_ remarkably
well. If you aren't familiar with Gemini by now, it is a new
protocol that is very similar to gopher but with some
enhancements. It is still far, far away from being anything like
the web, but it brings some modern thought and consideration to
hypertext browsing.

[0] gemini protocol
    gopher://gemini.circumlunar.space/1/
[1] solderpunk
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/1/~solderpunk

You can watch my video on peertube or on youtube! [2,3]

[2] peertube
    https://toobnix.org/videos/watch/8ee54700-971c-4da3-a8b4-7a78ed9ac42e
[3] youtube
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DoEI6VzybDk
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fun Questions Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200605-fun-questions-part-2/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fun Questions - Part 2
June 05th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Last spring I asked gopherspace a few fun questions to get some
interactions rolling [0]. Lots of people participated and
I personally got a lot of joy from seeing both the feedback and
learning a bit more about all of you. Well, I'm in desperate need
of some joy right now so I figure it's a good time for part 2!

[0] fun questions
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190330-fun-questions

I'll keep with the theme and ask 3 questions again. If you want to
participate, you can answer any or all. Phlog the answer over on
your own gopher hole and we'll read up on them. Send me a note if
you do so and I'll add a link to the bottom of this post so
everyone can read your responses.

1. Think back and try to remember the most satisfying drink of
   water in your life. What's the story of that drink?

2. Have you ever personally witnessed an act off human compassion
   that brought you to tears?

3. When is the last time you fell off a bicycle?

Replies:
seedy
    gopher://seedy.xyz/0/phlog/2020/jun/20200605.txt
christyotwisty
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/christyotwisty/phlog/2020-06-05.txt
jebug29
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/jebug29/log/2020-06/09-0348
tfurrows
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~tfurrows/phlog/2020-06-24_reFunQuestions2.txt
plugd
    gopher://thelambdalab.xyz/0/phlog/2020-06-23-Eight-Answers-(Replies-to-Tomasino-and-Christina).txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>More Deaths Poetry</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200602-more-deaths-poetry/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
more deaths - poetry
June 02nd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Another high school friend died on Saturday. I met her in poetry
class in my junior year. She sat behind me and we had a lot of
fun. In fact, we had so much fun that we attracted the attention
of another person across the room, Kristin. She came to join us
after a few weeks in our little area and would eventually become
my best friend.

In honor of Erin, may she rest in peace, I'm reading back over my
poetry here on gopher and in old notebooks. So much of it makes me
cringe now (I obviously read too much Dickenson & Browning at the
time) but I can still feel the youthful passion. I wish I had some
of her poems around.

Old poems of dubious quality
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/poetry
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Car</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200526-new-car/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
new car
May 26th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A funny thing happened to me on Saturday. I went to a lovely BBQ
with some friends in Reyjkavík and had to head home around 2300 in
order to catch the last bus from the capital out to my little
suburb. The bus picked me up and deposited me there 20 minutes
later as planned. While I was on the bus, I took out my kindle to
do some reading.

When I got off that bus I needed to make one transfer onto the #7
bus which would take me into my neighborhood, saving me a 1km walk
from the town center. I've done this many times and knew the bus
would be along any moment, so I kept reading. As expected, the bus
came around the corner and up the hill toward me. I hopped on and
kept reading.

See, here's where things get a little silly. I may have been
pretty drunk at this point owing to said BBQ earlier in the
evening. I was most certainly not paying attention as I was
reading. I also forgot completely that the number 7 bus travels in
both directions from the same bus stop I was at. I usually would
check the exact timing of the bus because there's no way to tell
from the signage whether it's headed to my neighborhood or away
from it. In fact, during that last nightly route both busses
appear at that stop within two minutes of one another.

So yeah, I was a little surprised when I looked up to find myself
in another town and not in my neighborhood. I was screwed. Ugh.

There were no more busses and taxis don't just wander the streets.
You need to call them and arrange a pickup. So what's a drunk guy
to do in this situation? If you guessed "walk 10km home around
a mountain in the middle of the night in Iceland" then you win
a prize!

I took a shortcut across the middle of a golf course at one point,
and marveled once again at the well maintained and numerous trails
and paths available in my area. Almost everything was well lit and
clean. It was lovely! It took me over two hours to get home and
I got a few hot-spots on my heels since I was walking in flimsy
slip-on shoes and not my boots. Still, no harm no foul.

Anyway, today I bought a car. :D It's a 2017 SsangYong Tivoli. It
is white and in pretty good shape with only about 60,000km on it.
I'm not sure you'll believe me now, but this was actually in the
works before Saturday's adventure. My wife and I were talking
about how nice it is here to be able to take the bus everywhere
and how it was probably better for our health to do all the
walking. We also admitted that it's frustrating not to be able to
go out into the countryside. We live only 25 minutes from
þingvellir, after all, but we never go. We want to head up north
this summer and we were considering renting. But there's little
annoyances too. 

This summer there are a number of activities available to the kids
in the area. One is a little zoo and horseback riding place where
the kids can learn to take care of the animals. It would be
perfect for my boy. The farm is only 5 minutes away, but that's by
car. It's directly on the other side of the mountain behind my
apartment. To walk there would take an hour, each way. That's not
something we could sign him up for before. Now it's no problem.

People here also just assume you have a car or access to one. It
can be tricky when activites happen at odd spots. Even travelling
to IKEA from my place is a chore because it takes 4 transfers and
over 2hrs to get there. Now with a car it's an 18 minute drive.

We don't intend to use it for everything. Certainly we want to
have it to go out into the country and see the sights. We also
will use it for things like IKEA trips. But we want to keep using
the bus to go downtown and walk to go shopping for groceries.
I don't know how realistic that goal is, but we shall see.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Bottomless Pit</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200516-a-bottomless-pit/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
a bottomless pit
May 16th, 2020
----------------------------------------

That's what it feels like right now, even with all the
preparation. I lost my dad tonight. About an hour ago, in fact.
I didn't get to say goodbye, but my sister did. I'm glad for that.
He's not suffering anymore, and neither is my mom. I'm glad for
that too. I'm glad I had time to prepare for it, to think on it
and test my emotions in the years leading up to this. I'm also
really glad for all the time I had with him.

It's just that after all of that gratitude and reason I eventually
hit a memory where he isn't my dad, but he is daddy and I'm eight
years old again and it is an unfathomable pit of despair that
opens around me knowing that he's gone and I can't ever hold him
or talk to him again. I'll carry that part until my own days are
up.

I won't want my son to feel this way. I'll want him to be happy
with his life and live it brilliantly. My dad surely wants the
same. I'm glad for that knowledge too. I just miss my daddy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Few Years Of Gophering</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200513-a-few-years-of-gophering/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
a few years of gophering
May 13th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Our good gopher citizen, solderpunk, recently shared his past
three years of gophering [0]. What an awesome view, seeing how
many posts we make on gopher month by month.

[0] solderpunk - three years of gopher
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/three-years-of-gopher.txt

I wanted to see the same thing on my own gopher history and he was
kind enough to share his code. With very little tweaking, I found
this:

Aug 2017: 13 posts |**************************
Sep 2017: 15 posts |******************************
Oct 2017: 09 posts |******************
Nov 2017: 10 posts |********************
Dec 2017: 08 posts |****************
Jan 2018: 19 posts |**************************************
Feb 2018: 11 posts |**********************
Mar 2018: 34 posts |************************************************
                  +|********************
Apr 2018: 23 posts |**********************************************
May 2018: 14 posts |****************************
Jun 2018: 12 posts |************************
Jul 2018: 17 posts |**********************************
Aug 2018: 07 posts |**************
Sep 2018: 07 posts |**************
Oct 2018: 10 posts |********************
Nov 2018: 11 posts |**********************
Dec 2018: 05 posts |**********
Jan 2019: 09 posts |******************
Feb 2019: 02 posts |****
Mar 2019: 04 posts |********
Apr 2019: 11 posts |**********************
May 2019: 06 posts |************
Jun 2019: 04 posts |********
Jul 2019: 03 posts |******
Aug 2019: 03 posts |******
Sep 2019: 08 posts |****************
Oct 2019: 01 posts |**
Nov 2019: 02 posts |****
Dec 2019: 04 posts |********
Jan 2020: 02 posts |****
Feb 2020: 04 posts |********
Mar 2020: 06 posts |************
Apr 2020: 02 posts |****
May 2020: 01 posts |**

March of 2018 was CRAZY! 34 posts in 31 days. I guess I had a lot
to say. We'll see how this goes in the future. :D Thx solderpunk!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Plaintext Passwords</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200512-plaintext-passwords/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Plaintext passwords
May 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A recent set of exchanges on the fediverse reminded me that
there's still plenty of poorly run websites and institutions who
are still storing user credentials in plain text. Yes, unencrypted
plain text.

I remember the horror in my heart back in 2008 when I was trying
to learn about virtual credit cards from my bank (a cool idea
which went away for no good reason). I was on the phone and the
customer service representative asked me for the 3rd and 5th
letter in my password to verify my identity.

Did it hit you too? Did that little pit in your stomach open up
like it did for me? How could this person know a specific
character in my password?

Needless to say, the conversation I had with the bank that day
quickly changed. I wish that was the only time I had the
experience, but it happened a second time in the same year in
a conversation with Fidelity, who ran my 401k at my job at the
time. In that case I was stuck. I couldn't choose to move my 401k
to another provider. Thanks America.

Anyway, there's a ton of these places including a downright scary
number of banks (looking at you Tesco). I figured gopher needed
some place to reference the list of shame, so I made one [0] over
in my Experiments section. There's a link over there to the master
list managed in github as well. If you have others to add, make
a PR and help shame them.

[0] List of sites storing passwords in plain text
    gopher://gopher.black/0/explorations/plaintext/list-of-plaintext-passwords.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Out Of The Past</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200430-out-of-the-past/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Out of the past
April 30th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I adored this band when I was a teen. They were local and played
mostly in bookstores and small venues or the occasional folk
festival. I would see them as much as possible, listened to their
music around the clock... you get it.

Well, 20+ years later, the keyboardist and main songwriter was
stuck at home due to covid-19. He sat at his piano and started
playing a song that he'd forgotten all about. It was from the time
leading up to their second indy album but the feel wasn't right
for that collection. Much later on he thought he'd lost all traces
of it: gone from memory and never recorded. Here we was, just
barely remembering the tune.

Then serendipity struck. Today he dusted off an old, ancient iPod
and plugged it in. Amazingly it still worked. He put it on shuffle
with his collection of thousands of songs when what should start
coming through his speakers but the very mystery song he'd lost.

Sometime in the mid-nineties he had put together a demo track with
just him and the lead singer. One take, no practice. It had been
mis-labeled as a different track ("More to This") and tossed into
a collection and forgotten.

Today it speaks across time not just to him, but to all of us who
loved that music and the band, and to everyone who spends the time
to listen. I can't even put into words how much it means to me.

Story to Tell (Soundcloud)
    https://soundcloud.com/dwayne-keith-kessel/itunesexport-m4a/s-Zq9n0kPcDms
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Renting A Video Game</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200429-renting-a-video-game/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Renting a video game
April 29th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Nostalgia struck. I'm back in a childhood home giddy with
excitement over the Nintendo Entertainment System which stealthily
arrived as the last present opened at Christmas. My parents sprung
for the unit that came with two game cartridges, not just one:
Super Mario Bros. & Duck Hunt on one cartridge, and Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles on the other. It's visceral. I can smell the box.
Feel the plastic.

Games then were expensive. I suppose they're still expensive, but
I don't buy so many. A game like Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles cost
about $50 in the late 80s. With some napkin math, that's around
$80-85 today. Pricey, as I said. We didn't get new ones often.
Years--and many garage sales--later, I have 57 games in my
collection. As a kid, I had around 20 at the most.

Don't get me wrong. I'm not suggesting games were worth this much
back then, but it's what we had. There's games I've got that
aren't worth a dime. The Adventures of Dino Rikki comes to mind.
What a piece of trash! Still, it cost a fortune and I had no way
of knowing if it was going to be terrible. Maybe a friend had it
and could warn me. Maybe it would get a mention in Nintendo Power
magazine. Otherwise, you're shopping by box art.

That was until the video rental stores got in on the action. It
was a brilliant outgrowth from home video. For a dollar or two you
could take home a game for a few days. Sure, you weren't likely to
master it or beat it, and your save game was gone when it was
returned. Even so, what an incredible tool to avoid wasting big
money on flops.

I vividly remember renting Life Force [0] from the Video Stop.
What a brilliant game that was. I loved the gameplay and the
sprites. There was one that looked like an uncooked chicken
crawling on the ground. Awesome. I believe that eventually many of
those sprites, sound effects, and much of the gameplay code would
get revisited in The Guardian Legend, my favorite NES game of all
time.

[0] Life Force
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dt-pMJiQTTk

That rental was awesome and eventually I'd get my own copy of the
game. Others... well [1], I own some of those anyway.

[1] Not so awesome NES games
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2KgwO0N6e8U

I don't really have a big reason for sharing this. It just came to
my mind and was worth a smile. Hope it gave you one too.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
