<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Buying Books</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220306-buying-books/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Buying Books
March 06th, 2022
----------------------------------------

A fedi post from @DL6MHC@mastodon.radio I just read said:

"I've started to abuse Amazon for browsing articles, getting
inspirations, reading (hopefully non-fake) reviews and finding out
what a solid price for an article is. Then I buy my stuff
somewhere else."

For years I would go to big booksellers like Barnes & Noble or
Borders (before it shut down) to browse books and discover
interesting things only to then purchase them online from Amazon
where it was much cheaper. Sometimes I'd even purchase while I was
still there browsing. I felt so clever.

My battle then was against the big bookseller who came in and
killed so many beloved tiny bookshops. Amazon was the scrappy
alternative in my mind, and a means of revenge.

These days I will browse Amazon for things, read reviews, gather
intel, and then purchase else where, just like the fedi user
above. I wish I could say that it was an act of will power and
ethical justice at work, but it's mostly because ordering from
Amazon to Iceland is prohibitively expensive.

I take solace in the world of coffee, though. When Starbucks swept
in and killed many of my beloved local coffee shops I did not bow
down, but fought back by supporting those who remained or
abstaining completely. When the third wave of coffee brought back
the renaissance of local shops I was ready to dive right in. 

But books... sadly, my options are less stellar. For one thing
I try not to gather too many physical books. I can't move them
easily or cheaply and I end up giving them away. So I favor ebooks
or library books. Those I could still get cheaply from Amazon,
I suppose. The general mentality that "Amazon isn't affordable"
I've developed here seems to have clouded that issue in my head.
I'm more likely to seek a 3rd party site, direct-from-author
purchase, or grab from the library. For older works, out-of-print
stuff, or obscure things I dust off my tor browser and visit
z-library.

Anyway, not sure where I was going with this, but there ya go.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ukraine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220221-ukraine/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Ukraine
February 21st, 2022
----------------------------------------

Oh no. Poor Ukraine.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Computer Science</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220202-computer-science/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
computer science
February 02nd, 2022
----------------------------------------

I came across one of those lists of free computer science classes
curated in a github gist or some other such place. I knocked it
around in my tabs for a couple hours and let my mind go back to my
own CS education.

I started at Rowan University in 1998 in the Computer Science
department following the coattails of a friend from Boy Scouts who
had been doing well for a year already. In high school I didn't
really have any direction at all or idea of what I wanted to do.
Computers happened to be a thing I was familiar with, spent a bit
of time on, and it appeared likely to have a future that paid
well. My dad's only restriction on my choice was, "No art."

He had gone to Kent State and studied in the Visual Communications
department there and was unable to turn that into a career. He
instead took the long way through a retail job and eventually into
sales. Because of his experience he hoped to save me the trouble.

The thing is, had he not had that restriction I likely would have
gone into some form of art education. It was the course track
I enjoyed most in school, continuously excelled in, and got me
motivated. But, in the long run the joke is on both of us. As I'll
explain in a moment. But first, back to Computer Science!

In 1998 I got my start. I had some great introduction to
programming classes that dove right into C. I had a killer lab
techniques practical course that taught me the ins and outs of the
command line, jobs, rediection of outputs, and all sorts of mighty
cool things I use every day. I also had some heavy-duty math
classes which bored the ever-living snot out of me.

My first semester went well. My second semester saw a marked dip
in my grades, though. I was getting involved in stuff that was
taking my focus away from class, and part way through that year
I developed an extreme clinical depression and insomnia. Entering
my sophomore years I find it difficult to relate details because
I have some intense memory loss due to the insomnia. I basically
accomplished nothing is school, failed everything, and was on the
edge of academic probation when I somehow signed up to enlist in
the US Navy. That gave me an excuse for a leave-of-asence from
school (delaying repaying those loans!) and in a matter of weeks
I was gone.

All in all my computer science education is the equivalent of two
pretty solid semesters of foundations.

In the Navy I was a nuclear electronics technician, so I picked up
more skills in hardware which was really cool, but didn't do much
to further my computer expertise.

Finally, after the Navy, I ended up returning to school and
beginning anew at Indiana University. I transfered pretty much
nothing from my first school as I wasn't going into a CS
department. I think 2 of my math classes may have worked and
that's it. But, this time around I had a Navy work ethic and also
the a limited time payment due to my medical discharge. The Navy
had me covered for about 3 years of school, so I went to town.
I managed to go from nothing at all to a masters degree in those
three years. Fun part about it? It was in this lovely new program
that just launched called "New Media". It was, in fact, a visual
communications degree + computers. Hah!

So, as I'm remember all this stuff I'm also lementing how I can
whiz through and code really well and professionally at a senior
level in a few niche areas, but if you need skills that get past,
say, data structures and algorithms level, I never learned it.
Systems programming? No idea. Operating systems? Nope. Parallel
computing? Huh?

I'll sum it up this way: I never got to learn how to link to
a system library. Not sure what to do to make that happen.

I can muddle around in about 15 languages, but without that
conceptual level to fall back on there's not a lot I can actually
DO outside of the web.

So yeah, I need more education. And here are all these free
courses. My formal education was a quarter century ago, so I'm not
going to rely on memory. I've decided to start from the beginning.

The following is a list of courses with video lections I found
which roughly run in linear order. I may end up shuffling one or
two things later on, but for now I'm just watching lectures one by
one and soaking it in. I'm pretty sure I won't need any note
taking for the first couple of courses, but we'll see.

Stanford CS106A - Programming Methodology
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS106A
Stanford CS106B - Programming Abstractions
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS106B
Stanford CS107 - Programming Paradigms
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/CS107
Stanford CS110 - Principals of Computer Systems
    https://web.stanford.edu/class/archive/cs/cs110/cs110.1202/
MIT - Mathematics for Computer Science
    https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-042j-mathematics-for-computer-science-spring-2015/
Wheaton - Discrete Mathematics and Functional Programming
    http://cs.wheaton.edu/~tvandrun/dmfp/
Stanford CS161 - Design and Analysis of Algorithms 1
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXFMmlk03Dt7Q0xr1PIAriY5623cKiH7V
Stanford CS161 - Design and Analysis of Algorithms 2
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLXFMmlk03Dt5EMI2s2WQBsLsZl7A5HEK6
Stanford CS261 - A second Course in Algorithms
    http://timroughgarden.org/w16/w16.html
Stanford EE261 - The Fourier Transform and its Applications
    https://see.stanford.edu/Course/EE261
CMU 18-447 - Introduction to Computer Architecture
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5PHm2jkkXmhayPxddp9z5MixV8Q5Ty8u
CMU 15-418 - Parallel Computer Architecture and Programming
    http://15418.courses.cs.cmu.edu/spring2015/
CMU 15-721 - Database Systems
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLSE8ODhjZXjbisIGOepfnlbfxeH7TW-8O
CSE 421/521 - Introduction to Operating Systems
    https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLE6LEE8y2Jp-kbEcVR2W3vfx0Pdca0BD3
Berkeley - SICP Python
    https://cs61a.org/
MIT - SICP Scheme
    https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-001-structure-and-interpretation-of-computer-programs-spring-2005/index.htm

The last two entrants are both courses based around SICP. There's
the famous Scheme original from MIT, but also one in Python which
I grok better. In April I'm picking up the Javascript SICP book
too. Between two courses and a book in three different languages
I hope I'll be able to muddle my way through.

I hope I finish it all. I think it's doable. I'll keep pressing
forward as best I can. If you read this and think about it at some
point in the future, feel free to ping me on IRC or Mastodon
sometime and ask how I'm doing. Who knows, I may be stalled and
need a little nudge back on track.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cheating At My Reading Goal</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220101-cheating-at-my-reading-goal/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
cheating at my reading goal
January 01st, 2022
----------------------------------------

A new year is here and a new reading goal is set. I'm sticking
with my goal of 100 books like the last few years. It's attainable
even if I hit a slump. Even so, to start my year off on a good
note I like to read easy, quick stuff. Last year I read like 10-15
books of this Witch P.I. series that's honestly pretty terrible,
but I just tear through it. It helps that the books are cozy as
hell and nothing serious is ever at stake more than a knitting
contest.

This year I was thinking about what series to binge to get ahead.
I'm just getting started on the Jill Kismet series (I have the
whole thing in an omnibus). I also have the Alex Verus series of
which I've read book one and will likely binge quickly. But
instead of either of those I realized that my Calibre library has
page numbers in it (because I'm diligent about good data). So...
I'm going to sort by shortest book and clean house on a bunch of
novellas I've been sitting on for years. I have about 20 books
under 50 pages! If I want to read a bunch of the Shadow stories
this year I could do my entire 100 and stay under 150 pages each.
Wild! Such cheating! Hahaha.

I'll mix it up soon enough and I don't stop at 100 books, so I'm
not really cheating anything. This is just a little mental trick
to help me feel like I'm well invested in reading for the year. My
own motivation wanes if I fall behind schedule and it becomes
increasingly hard to pick up my Kindle. It's best to stay well
ahead of goal.

Anyway, here I go!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
December 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Be it resolved:

This year the name 'tomasino' will become a standard unit of
measurement.

2021 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20201231-resolution
2020 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution
2019 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions
2018 Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bbs</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211230-bbs/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
BBS
December 30th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I installed WWIV on one of my VMs. I walked through all the set up
and got it all configured out of some spark of nostalgia. Then
when it was done and ready to start adding content I decided I had
no content I wanted to share in a BBS. I have enough channels for
my creative outputs already. Too many, really.

So I deleted it.

It was too easy to conflate the installation and configuration of
a BBS as "having a BBS" in my head. I wanted to recapture the
feeling of the BBS days and the setup process faked its way into
my day masquarading as a solution. The BBS experience was one of
community, though, and of reaching out for a bit of nerdy contact
that pierced a veil of separatation. 

That veil doesn't exist anymore. The internet killed it. And so
what is left to penetrate? I already have contact with you here.

Do I add door games to this little corner of the internet and
entice you with FIDONet access? Maybe I dust off Phrack archives
or ANSi art galleries? With a lot of work I could decorate my
space like the ones of my youth and possibly entice visitors for
a drive-by of the museum I'd created, but that's still a pale
approximation.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Merry Christmas</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211224-merry-christmas/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Merry Christmas
December 24th, 2021
----------------------------------------

It's just about bed time here on Christmas Eve. The tree is
decked, the presents stuffed gloriously below. We have cookies and
milk for Santa on the table (and a few red pepper slices for the
reindeer). Soon this little boy will lie down and rest and we can
all wake up bright and early.

It's a peaceful moment. Merry Christmas from our peace to yours.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Purpose In Life</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211218-a-purpose-in-life/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A Purpose in Life
December 18th, 2021
----------------------------------------

How do you find your purpose in life? That's a question that just
popped up on the Fediverse. I wanted to respond right away, but
I suspect my thoughts on the subject are going to expand beyond
a reasonable reply-toot. Let's explore the question together here!

First of all, the question was immediately followed by a sentiment
about searching for happiness, suggesting that a purpose in life
and being happy are related ideas, maybe even the same thing. It
may be the case that finding purpose leads to happiness, but
I would caution against drawing those parallels too soon, for as
you'll see, there's a possibility doing so may blind you to your
own possibilities.

In religious life we talk about finding ones purpose by using the
term "vocation." That word harkens back to Latin roots from the
idea of a "calling". Whether you are religious or not, I think the
term does a good job representing the idea that an individual may
be aligned well, or be well-suited to succeed at a certain
occupation or activity. If you believe in a higher power, you may
understand it as being meant to follow a path, or that you're led
to it. If not, it may just be something that naturally aligns with
your skills, morals, and sense of being. A vocation is a powerful
idea.

Which is cool and all, but how do you determine what YOU are meant
to do? Should you expect a big clear sign that says, "Dear
jackass, you should be a fire fighter. k thnx bye!" Even in
religious literature that sort of calling is super-rare. Instead
you should expect to have to go about it the hard way. That means
figuring things out on your own through exploration, testing, and
some deep introspection (and prayer if you're into that sort of
thing).

Where do you start? I'd recommend a simple list to get started:

  - Needs of the world
  - Your skills & gifts
  - Your true desires

The needs of the world are wide and varied. Some are enormous
tasks, like fighting climate change. Others are smaller and more
local, like volunteering at a food pantry. Everywhere you look
there are people in need, animals in need, nature in need,
probably even charismatic rocks in need. Maybe you feel
a particular affinity toward one of these needs. Maybe you feel
like your abilities are well suited to address one of them.

Thinking about what you're good at or uniquely qualified to offer
is another angle for approaching your path. Do you like to work
with your hands? Are you personable? Do you love spreadsheets? Can
you juggle? It really doesn't matter what the skills are, there's
probably a place they can be applied.

And maybe it's neither of the above. Maybe there's something
stirring deep in your heart that sounds damned interesting. Is
there an idea that persists inside you, itching away in a little
voice? Is there a subtle yearning to try it, to do something new?
That may be a deep or true desire of your heart, or it may be
something else entirely. You'll need to learn how to test it.

All of these ideas above are a starting point, not an actual
answer. Once you have something that has sunk its hooks into you,
however tentatively, it's time to test that voice to make sure
it's coming from the right place. Once again in religious terms we
call this testing the spirits, and once again the principles apply
even if you are non-religious.

There are several techniques for testing a decision. Here's
a couple:

1. Imagine you are very old. You've reached the end of your days
   on Earth. It's time to wrap it up any moment now. Here at the
   end you've taken a moment to think back on your life that
   you've lived. Think about that decision you made and imagine
   how it played out. Do you feel proud of that? Does it give you
   a sense of consolation to have done it or does it leave you
   cold?

   Now flip the script. Take some time to clear your head, then
   imagine the exact same scenario, but imagine you chose
   differently. How does that make you feel, looking back?

2. Test the spirit for its communion. Does this decision bring you
   closer to the people you love? Does it bring you closer to the
   community? Does it bring you closer to your faith? Does your
   choice build up those around you or does it build up you
   yourself? Think about those relationships that are important to
   you and think about how the decision feels next to those
   relationships.

One thing you'll notice here that we're not looking at is
happiness. Focusing on a decision that brings you joy can easily
mask the harm it's doing to those around you, to your
relationships with those you care about or your own spirituality.
Finding your path will hopefully bring you a sense of peace, which
then should bring happiness with it, but don't use it as a way to
test the spirits. It's too easy to be misled.

One other thing I want to mention is the freedom to give up your
own control. In most of the ideas above there's a sense that you
are choosing something for yourself based on some logical
criteria. If that's not resonating with you, or if it's not
drawing you to something strongly, you may want to try
surrendering yourself to a different sort of freedom. 

Sometimes our own sense of control is blocking us from the
possibilities of what we can really accomplish. We think we are
good at X, so we do X. We can't imagine we'd be good at Y, so we
never try Y. Perhaps Y even scares us. We're not well equipped for
it. We don't have those skills.

By actively choosing something new that scares us, that we feel
unequipped to handle on our own, we have no choice but to
surrender to the task and hand over that control. We might say
that we put it in God's hands. We might say that we're leaving our
comfort zone.

Try this: When you're thinking about the needs of the world or
listening to those sneaky desires deep in your heart pay close
attention to anything that bubbles up that scares you. Working
with kids? Working in hospice care? Visiting the incarcerated?
Whatever it might be, if it seems impossible and frightening don't
dismiss it. Give some consideration to testing it out. Imagine
yourself on your death bed looking back on it. Give it some
freedom to be possible for a moment.

Finally I'd like to reassure you that there's not just one answer.
You're not called to do one and only one thing. You will be called
again and again. You can reinvent yourself. You can expand to be
more and do more. You can change, and you WILL change. Even right
now at this very moment.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Scrobbles</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211210-scrobbles/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
scrobbles
December 10th, 2021
----------------------------------------

When Tidal first came out I jumped on it right away. I hadn't ever
used a music subscription service before and I liked the hifi idea
and also the higher artist payout rate than the competition.
I stuck with it for a few months but ultimately felt it was too
buggy and dropped it.

Fast forward to this week. I decided I've been using Plex for free
enough for several years that I should contribute financially.
I have no real reason to get Plex Pass since it doesn't actually
offer any features I felt I was missing, but what the heck. So
I picked up the life-time Plex Pass and while I'm doing it
I notice they're promoting Tidal.

It's not part of Plex Pass itself, but the Tidal subscription has
a discount and integrates with Plex. That sounded pretty solid,
and they had a 30 day trial. I figure, lets pick it up and try out
the holiday music. Maybe I'll discover new albums to join my
collection!

It was an easy setup and it's running well. I remembered that
I saw Robert Plant and Allison Krauss have another team-up album
that just came out (spotted the vinyl at the record shop on
Saturday) so I checked it out (very good, like Raising Sand before
it). I also tried out the new Tangerine Dream album (good for
background, but boring for a focused listen). Overall I've been
poking around more in an exploratory nature. 

A quick aside…

I prefer to listen to music by album rather track. It's one of
a number of reasons I've never had much interest in Spotify.
I really like the arrangement of an album. How did the artists and
producers compile it together? Does it sweep through emotions or
jostle them? How did it kick off and what track is batting
clean-up? Is there a theme? There's just so much to it! I don't
buy songs; I buy albums.

But back to Tidal/Plex…

I'm clicking around trying out all this new stuff and I have
a moment of worry. You see, I don't really like subscription
services. If I can pay a one-time-fee I'm much more likely to
purchase, even if the cost seems cheaper to "rent" with a monthly
charge. Tidal's monthly fee is going to annoy me sooner or later
and I'm going to cancel it. When that happens there goes my
history of my explorations. Boo.

But wait! Scrobbles!

That's right, there's things like LastFM that let you scrobble
your plays to them so you can track them between services and
devices and get insights into your listening habits. I love that!
I have it configured for all my music players that support it on
this laptop, but I never thought about it in Plex, let alone Tidal
via Plex.

A bit of searching revealed that both Plex and Tidal have options
to link to LastFM (yes, I know there are open source alternatives
like OpenFM and I have accounts there too, but most apps are
hard-coded to support just LastFM, so I use it still). I added my
links and now my glorious Christmas binge is scrobbling. But wait,
there's a problem! I configured scrobbling for Tidal via their web
music player. Plus I can play it through Plex as a player, so one
of those two things should work, but they don't. I think it's
broken. *sniffle*

So that's sad and I feel robbed of my scrobbles. It's funny, but
it actually makes me want to use Tidal less! If it doesn't
scrobble does it even count? Haha. No, not that. It's not that
I need credit for listening. I want that data so I can reference
it later or get recommendations based on it. That's valuable to
me! Boo.

Maybe it'll get fixed soon. For now, back to Christmas.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
