<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Git</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180603-git/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Git
June 03rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's some panic in the air over Microsoft courting Github.
Alarmists are pulling their projects down, moving to self-hosted
Gitlab instances and so on. I'm confused by the whole thing,
though. Git isn't github. My repos aren't property of github, even
if it's one of the remotes. I have everything up there mirrored in
several remote locations. That's the beauty of git! It's
distributed. Every repo is the complete repo.

orbifx summarized it best over here [0].
[0] Decentralised Git
    gopher://notes.orbitalfox.eu/0/note/15ec76d8-a67c-4c19-abc4-103184760186

This gopher hole is a great example. It's currently located:
- on this laptop I'm writing on
- on gopher.black (raspberry pi)
- on SDF
- on Tilde.town
- on bitbucket.org
- on my macbook air at work
- on a backup tower at work
- on my PC in a VM in VirtualBox
- and probably some other places I forgot about

I think the lesson here for people shouldn't be to fear Microsoft
nabbing Github. The lesson should be, distribute your shit,
people! Use git for awesome.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mastoconflict</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180602-mastoconflict/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Mastoconflict
June 02nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Mastodon is having a little tiff right now over the introduction
of a new feature: trending hashtags. As the project maintainer
puts it, it has been the most requested feature addition for over
a year. When it rolled out, though, it was met with widespread
criticism and, in many cases, open hostility. The rebuttals back
and forth quickly escalated and became personal. Pretty much
everyone involved is greatly unhappy, regardless of their position
on the issue.

Meanwhile, I'm sitting back here thinking to myself, "democracy in
action." A collective developed and idea with their voices (the
addition of trending hashtags). When that idea was implemented,
other collectives disagreed. They weren't aware of its
development, they argue. It is unsafe and can be used for evil. It
will target groups who are often targets and make Mastodon unsafe
or unwelcoming.

There's one person in charge of the project. He must be the
problem. If it weren't for him, surely the issue would be put to
rest. It's as simple as that, because a "pure" democracy will
always work things out. This is an example of corruption of the
perfect, federated state.

Sound familiar? Yeah, I thought so. The issue isn't having
a single leader. The issue is that groups of people have different
wants and needs. This is inherent to any sized group of people
greater than one. You cannot make them all equally happy. You
cannot serve every single use case simultaneously. The utopia of
democracy does not exist, just as it does not exist for communism,
or socialism, or even monarchy.

So what do we do? We use our brains. We make decisions that help
as many as we can. We use our morals and make decisions that hurt
as few as possible. We don't cross lines that shouldn't be
crossed. We listen to the words of the suffering and try to ease
that suffering. We say to those with excess, "you have excess.
Your priorities are lower than those who need help."

This is all but impossible in systems that favor group-think. The
power in those systems comes from those who can manipulate the
system. Who can speak loudest is often the one with the most
money. The wider the spread of power, the more this systematic
influence becomes absolute. It can devolve to cult of personality
eventually. The key to the recipe is broad reach of voice.

What is the countermeasure? Strong-willed leaders who can champion
the "right" decisions. What makes those decisions right? The
things I listed above. What ensures a leader will execute those
decisions and not others? That depends on your system. In
government, there's not much, though a constitutional system can
help balance it. It's easy to slide into despotism. In social
systems like open source projects, the answer is the freedom to
move on. The system is open source and the protocol can work with
other projects. Mastodon can be forked and formed into something
else by others with a different set of principles. If the current
leader of the project does not implement policy (in the form of
software features) that reflects the needs of the people, that's
the easiest path to take. No bloodshed, just moving on and
building something new.

But back to the question of trending hashtags themselves. Are they
a good idea? Probably not, at least in the way they've been
implemented so far. There's been a lot of valid points about how
bad actors already abuse similar systems in other networks.
There's nothing currently in place to prevent that, and the
distributed nature of the network makes stopping those attacks
even harder than on Twitter. There have been very good ideas to
tweak the feature to avoid the abuse. Ultimately it should come
down to a cost/benefit analysis. Unfortunately it's more likely to
come down to the loudest screamers. But that's democracy.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Bicycles</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180602-bicycles/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Bicycles
June 02nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

I posted a picture of my bicycle over on Mastodon. As I mentioned
there, I have no real background with bikes beyond riding one as
a kid. I bought an old racer off a guy in college and that's been
my bike for most of my adult life. It was seriously uncomfortable.
The seat was like a spear into my butt and I sat completely folded
in half. The bike was really light weight, but that doesn't matter
if you are sitting on top of it.

A few years back I decided that I deserved a more comfortable
bike. I went to the shop in town and told them I wanted to sit
upright and have a squishy seat. They found me a great bike that
I tested out. It was so much better than my old one. The frame
says "Specialized", or something like it. It might be the brand or
the model. I have no idea. It's a 7 speed thing and easy to shift
with a twist of the right handle. It mostly doesn't hurt me to
ride it, and that's a plus.

So, all you bike nerds, what can you tell me about my bike? Is it
a decent thing? Is there a reason my hands still go numb when
I ride more than a few miles? Any advice for making biking suck
less (I still prefer walking).
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summer Vacation</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180531-summer-vacation/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Summer Vacation
May 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is a quick note to wish all our summer vacationers a happy
break. If you're going to be taking some time away from a screen
while the weather is nice, please enjoy your time and don't worry
about the bits and bytes. We'll all be here when you return.

Oh, and a bonus big WELCOME BACK to zelibertinegamer. You were
missed. I'm glad you've decided to return and hope you can avoid
some of that toxic stuff that led you away in the first place.
Come join us on #gopher at irc.sdf.org. It's a friendly joint.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Track</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180531-cli-tricks-track/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CLI Tricks: track
May 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is a part of a series of phlog entries where I will share
some of my command line tricks, tips, and scripts.


## track ##

Fitness trackers are all the rage. Chances are that you've got one
on you right now, weirdo. Collecting data about your own behavior
is pretty neat. It's extra cool if you can do it in a way that
doesn't also give that data away to nefarious strangers who want
to take over the world, but I digress.

I like tracking my shiz too. I've used my phone to count steps in
the past, and I have a scale in my bathroom, and a tape-measure
for my big belly. But where do I save those numbers so I can look
back on my amazing progress of awesomeness later? I don't really
want to hand that over to Google or MyFitnessPal. They don't need
to know that stuff. I could just store it in text files for myself
and parse them later.

And that's exactly what I decided to do. I keep some csv files in
dropbox, or in nextcloud, or in syncthing. But logging stuff in
CSV files isn't really fun, so I wrote a little tracker app to
help me out.

Now you can enjoy the glory of my crappy little program too!
First, grab a copy over on github [0] and install it.

[0] track
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/track

It's really easy to use. Start by checking the man page or
spitting out some help:

  $ man track

  $ track -h

See how to use it? Great! You're done!

But seriously, it is really basic. You can just add a new metric
to track by tracking something to it for the first time. It allows
only one data point per day. It doesn't care what format that data
is in.

There's probably easy ways to break it, so, um, don't do those.

Do you have something you want to add to it to make it better?
Cool! Make a pull request and gimme-gimme. I probably want that
feature too.

Oh, as a side-note, the data I used in my post "Fat" [1] all was
logged with this script. I have an example in that post of how to
generate a graph on the command line using the jp utility. Check
it out.

[1] Fat
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180407-fat

Now that track is a bit more sophisticated, I can track my weight
by typing:

  $ track -ac weight | jp -input csv -width 67 -height 25

A bit of an improvement!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tracking As Stalking</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180527-tracking-as-stalking/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Tracking as Stalking
May 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Stalking - 

"criminal activity consisting of the repeated following and
harassing of another person."

"a course of conduct directed at a specific person that involves
repeated (two or more occasions) visual or physical proximity,
nonconsensual communication, or verbal, written, or implied
threats, or a combination thereof, that would cause a reasonable
person fear."

There is an argument made by those practicing large-scale data
capture and aggregation of individuals that the data they collect
is public information, and therefore it is legal and justified.
Even if the information collected was indeed all public--and I do
not agree to that line of argument at all--then the question is
still not settled. The very act of repeated visual proximity
(which is transferrable to digital media via cyber-stalking
definitions) which could cause a "reasonable person fear" falls
clearly within the bounds of stalking. If it is a corporation
commiting these acts, then it is no less culpable than if it were
an individual. After all, corporations are people too, right? [0]

[0] Corporate personhood (Gopherpedia)
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Corporate personhood

The act of data aggregation of an individual carries with it the
inherent threat of what is being done with that data. As more
revelations are brought to light informing the public of the
deeply unsettling targeting of individuals for political
manipulation, commercial activation, or social harassment, the
fear increases. What else could be done with that information?
Even if nothing is actually put into motion, the act of
collection, of monitoring, is in itself a form of digital stalking
that explicitly undermines the argument of "public information".

Anonymous collection of data into aggregate data sets that cannot
be retargeted or focused to communicate outbound with a specific
population or person is still problematic. If that data allows you
to segment or infer the actions of a type of person or group,
especially one that routinely faces subjugation or discrimination,
then the act of collection contributes to a justifiable fear of
persecution. It is stalking.

The counter argument to all of these points is that the underlying
economic power of the internet is governed and supplied by data
collection. It is a capitalist requirement that some sort of
economic incentive be present to promote the growth and stability
of the systems. Money talks, or so the argument goes. How can we
cut out advertising and still have nice things? Will everything
need to become a paid subscription?

Here's the thing: there is no inherent, inaliable rights to
Netflix. Facebook is not a universal, precious entity that
deserves the protection and preservation of all people. The only
thing that fits that category is the people themselves. If
protecting individuals and groups of people damages these systems,
then that is the path that should be followed. If those systems
can find an alternative, legal way to continue their operations
then kudos to them. There is no argument that should value the
continued operation of a social network over the safety of even
a single individual. 

Money talks in capitalism, but capitalism cannot be allowed to run
unchecked. The morality of all people must pull on those reins and
keep careful watch. Systems of governance cannot become
subservient to the interests of economic forces over those of
moral obligation. Any systems of governance that allow this will
ultimately fail. First they will fail their people, and eventually
they will fail completely, often with dire consequences to both
those in power and those oppressed by it.

Data collection is a simple thing. It's easy to watch tracking
events fire and show up in pretty graphs. It's easy to use this to
optimize your experiences, improve them, make the user's day
a little easier. It's easy to look at the rosy garden that casual
analytics presents and see only the flowers. Just like
capitalism's promise of innovation through financial competition,
the premise is beautiful on the surface. Left unchecked it will
corrupt. That corruption will consolodate power and influence.
That power and influence will allocate more benefit to the few in
charge at the cost of the masses. The flowers are not worth it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Move Your Feet</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180522-move-your-feet/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Move your feet
May 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

It's been a while since my last phlog*. I've been wanting to get
back on gopher and do some serious plain text awesomeness, or at
least comment on the really cool happenings around the space. Cat,
love your diet, tell me more! How are you and your partner going
to handle it when you go back down under? Sparkipx, how's Felix
holding up now that you've been able to ride for a couple weeks?
Is it harder to do long distances on a folding bike than
a non-folding one? I've never tried one before. jynx, I'm totally
fascinated by single player RPGs and I need to go back through and
read up on your stuff. Tabletop role-playing is my #1 activity of
awesome, and that sounds stellar. horsemans has a cool gopher
wishlist that you guys should check out. I bet you can offer a lot
of responses there. [0]

[0] horesmans - gopher wishlist
    gopher://horsemans.online/0/2017-12-29-gopher-wishlist.md

Several of you are on vacation or soon returning. Welcome back and
all that. I hope you'll share insights and adventures. I love
travel stories so much. Hell, I love STORIES so much. tfurrows,
I'll be checking out Variations soon! Oh, and I have a Fiskers
push-mower and it's badass. I have to use it twice a week or the
grass grows too long for it to be effective. That part sucks. But
if you have a really small lawn, it's so nice to be able to handle
it quietly and "naturally".

Recently I've been absorbed in a string of poor projects at work
that have been eating up my mental energies. The work isn't hard,
but the clients have been difficult. I've been avoiding
unnecessary computer time as a way of disconnecting. Marry that up
with some unexpected (but welcome) consulting work, and my time
became even more short. Mostly, though, the thing that's kept me
away is a rededication to that principle I mentioned in recent
posts, deliberate practice.

I've been working on my shakuhachi quite a bit, and even met with
my kali instructor in the park at the side of a lake for
a fantastic jam in the rain. He built me a new shakuhachi, which
is just fantastic. It's a 1.9 (slightly deeper sound than the
standard 1.8) jin nashi flute and it's absolutely perfect. I'll be
sewing a new case for it soon, and an extra for him as well in
thanks.

I've also been walking a shit-ton. Every morning I wake at 6:35
and head outside to walk 2 to 2.5 miles on the canal towpath that
is the road I live on. Each evening, after putting my son to bed,
I head back outside and do another 2 miles. Sometimes I zip around
the neighborhood for a change of scenery. Sometimes I head into
town and walk the sidewalks. Most often I stay next to the canal
where I know the landscape features that mark my distance by
heart. I pop headphones in and binge audiobooks while I'm out
there. It's heaven.

Walking is a "keystone habit" for me, a term I learned from that
book on Habits with the yellow cover that I can't remember the
name of. When I walk, I do other good things as well. I eat well,
I sleep well, I think clearly. If I don't walk, holding on to the
other things is more difficult. So, walking rocks!

Hopefully I'll have more to share soon. In the meantime, I need to
go for a walk.

------

* I have a pet peeve about when people waste time in blogs and
phlogs talking about how they haven't posted in a long time.
That's the nature of the medium and the repetitive act of
explaining or apologizing for it serves no purpose except to make
you self-conscious. Now here I am doing it myself. Stupid.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>More Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180522-more-updates/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
More updates
May 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

That's a little depressing. After 11 days away I just wrote a long
update that is substantively the same thing I wrote 11 days ago.
I feel the need to amend this with some additional updates:

FBI File [0] - I received my FBI results. There are no records of
me in their files. I could follow up and request further research
looking for me in cross-references, but I think I'm good enough
with what I got. I'm still waiting for replies from the other
intel orgs.

[0] FBI Files
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180505-fbi-files

Poison Sumac [1] - It's finally gone. Holy shit that took a long
time.

[1] Poison Sumac
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-poison-sumac

The Hobbit [2] - The boy is loving it. We haven't gotten to read
it every night, but he's so excited about what's coming (I gave
hints). He talks about Smaug all the time despite having not met
him yet. He's excited for the giant spiders because I have
horrible arachnophobia and he thinks that's funny. We're just
leaving Rivendell and the Last Homely House. I can't wait for
Gollum!

[2] The Hobbit
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180418-the-hobbit

Finally, I've been brainstorming some ideas and getting some good
feedback from mastodon folks about a talk I want to present at
Barcamp Philly this year. I'll get it all ready to go and
hopefully it'll be something people want to attend. If not, I'll
record it and keep it ready for 1436CON/Port 70 [3].

[3] Port 70 -or- 1436CON
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180412-port-70-or-1436con
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Practice Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180511-practice-updates/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Practice updates
May 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

It's good to celebrate small victories. This week has been full of
them. I've kept up with my goal of deliberate practice regarding
writing, playing music, and even exercise. It feels great to be on
track. The next challenge will be to keep it going through the ups
and downs and boring times.

Regarding exercise, I'm well back into ketosis again (thank God)
and I've ramped up my walking. I'm walking two miles in the
morning and again in the evening. That's long been my foundation
or keystone habit to hold everything together and it seems to be
working again. I have been eating well and not snacking. The focus
has helped with my practice. All is well!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fixing Rss</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180509-fixing-rss/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fixing RSS
May 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is a quick test where I'm trying to fix the RSS lists on SDF
and tilde.town. My auto-pathing fixer regex needed some love.
Cross your fingers!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
