<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Another One Bites The Dust</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220809-another-one-bites-the-dust/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Another one bites the dust
August 09th, 2022
----------------------------------------

Lost another friend today. The number will start increasing soon,
I think, as we age more. It's hard to fathom, though. The number
has always been high. It's always too many.

I'll miss him. Less than some, more than many. He was a hell of
a human.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Small Internet Presentation At Mch2022</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220729-small-internet-presentation-at-mch2022/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Small Internet Presentation at MCH2022
July 29th, 2022
----------------------------------------

I'm back home from the Netherlands and MCH2022 (May Contain
Hackers). It was a whirlwind and quite awesome. I'm just floored
by how much stuff a bunch of volunteers can accomplish with
motivation and creative hacking.

The talks were amazing and most can now be found online on the CCC
site. There was also an epic CTF game going on the whole week (I
helped out in some lock picking challenges). The ad-hoc villages
created by visitors were endless fun too. What a wild ride. I hope
you all get the chance to attend one of these hacker camps in the
future.

I participated in one group panel discussion on social media,
disinformation, and fascism that was really interesting, but not
recorded. I also gave one of the curated stage presentations which
was recorded [0].

[0] Video of my Small Internet talk
    https://media.ccc.de/v/mch2022-83-rocking-the-web-bloat-modern-gopher-gemini-and-the-small-internet

My main talk was about the small internet, and specifically about
gopher and gemini. It covers some framing for what people mean by
the term small internet, what services and activities fall under
the umbrella, and a bit of sentiment and behavior information from
the survey I shared here earlier. Then I run through a quick
technical overview of gopher and gemini, and finish off with
a quick nod at pubnix and tildes. The questions from the audience
were wonderful and I hope it broadens awareness of our fun little
spaces. If you want to see the slides from the presentation,
they're a Nuxt app I tossed together for the purpose and can be
found here [1]:

[1] Presentation Slides
    https://small-internet-presentation.netlify.app

I hope I get to go to another camp in the near future. Perhaps
next time I'll discuss contract based dependency management [2].

[2] CBDM Blog Post
    https://labs.tomasino.org/contract-based-dependency-management/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Small Internet Survey</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220626-small-internet-survey/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Small Internet Survey
June 26th, 2022
----------------------------------------

I've put together a survey about the Small Internet (gopher,
gemini, individual webpages, small community sites) and I would
love your input. Please spend a few minutes and fill in your
thoughts. I'm especially interested in the open response
questions. This will help inform an upcoming conference talk I'll
be giving at May Contain Hackers (MCH).

Survey Link
    https://cloud.tomasino.org/apps/forms/KakFXPSpgj5WD9zq
MCH Website
    https://mch2022.org
My Talk at MCH
    https://program.mch2022.org/mch2021-2020/talk/RPVQD8/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Abortion</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220626-abortion/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Abortion
June 26th, 2022
----------------------------------------

This is a post about my thoughts on abortion. It is personal and
not intended to persuade. I'm writing it because I am, on
occasion, asked about my opinion, and thought it helpful to write
them down.

Let this brief introduction serve as a content warning.

* * * * *

Let's start with the easy bits:

There are times when an abortion is absolutely, unequivocally, and
unambiguously the moral choice. For instance, if the fetus is
non-viable or if the birth with result in the death of the fetus
and parent. There is no grey area here. By performing a medical
procedure we can help save life and reduce suffering.

With that very basic example I thereby demonstrate that there is
no right and ethical argument against abortion in all situations.
The act itself cannot be considered evil for it can in some
situations be used for good. We must look further at the situation
and recognize that there's more to this than a black & white
narrative. (Duh.)

What situations affect the ethical choice for or against birth?
There's a huge range of circumstances from family planning issues,
to health, safety, abuse, and money. This is where I feel the
opportunity is best to save lives and reduce suffering.

Lets take just a few examples here:

The teenagers who accidentally conceive -- currently face
incredibly difficult life decisions while their own bodies and
brains are still developing. The realities of modern America mean
the potential for difficulties with families, poverty, lack of
support for continued education, and lack of tooling and services
for the child. 

These things are addressable by our society. A world that embraces
and supports these young people, provides the safety nets,
childcare services, and opportunities to continue to improve
themselves and the futures of their children would create an
environment where the accidental pregnancy wouldn't come with such
a sense of shock and fear. That would lead to less people seeing
abortion as their only path.

A family that's struggling to support the kids they have may see
similar benefits if only social services are improved. The
unexpected extra child is now not a fearful burden, but an
opportunity.

But there are other situations that we must face as a reality.
Rape, incest, abusive relationships. Legislating against abortions
further punishes the victims of these crimes and causes great
suffering. It is undeniable. Forced birthing is quite literally
a war crime and crime against humanity, as defined in the 1998
Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court (ICC Statute). It
is unconscionable to force women into this situation for the sake
of a child's life: a child which after birth is given no further
thought. It is a false display of moralism made at the cost of
another.

And finally, there are people who become pregnant who just don't
want to be. There is no quandary for them. There is no situation
change which would put them in a position to want to have a child.
Here is the hardest of all situations for a third party to wrap
their head around. The life of a child vs what appears to be
nothing. But it's never nothing, is it? We are all complex
creatures with a lifetime of thoughts and feelings that led to who
we are today. These experiences are intricate, complicated, and
carry a vast depth to them. These depths are plumbed in therapy by
millions daily, and though issues may seem mundane to those in
passing they are whirlwinds of vital importance that make or break
people. Our glimpse at someone's situation is not even seeing the
iceberg above the surface, let alone below. We don't even sense
the chill in the air. We cannot understand from our vantage, and
thus, as hard as it may be, we cannot decide for that person.

I want there to be fewer abortions. I want a world that makes it
safe for children to come into being and be cared for no matter
what the situation of the parents. I want mental health services
to be available to everyone who needs to talk because maybe, just
maybe, some more people will say yes to the child.

I am pro-life. I am against abortion. And yet, I believe it is
absolutely wrong to legislate forced-births. We make abortion
diminish through compassion in our society, not through fascism.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Writing More</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220509-writing-more/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
writing more
May 09th, 2022
----------------------------------------

Last Saturday I got off my butt and joined my local NANOWRIMO
group for a coffee house meetup. I had a D&D game right after that
I needed to get to, so I only stayed for about 3 sprints, but it
was enough for me to dust off my Emergence story [0] and start
back up on it. I had a decent beginning, but I really need to
flesh out the middle and end quite a bit. 

So in those writing sprints, and again today, I added to the
fourth chapter, "Secrets", giving more depth and context. It's an
omniscient view chapter which gives it some freedom, but also
extra pressure to make everything clear. I'm also introducing some
pretty ethereal concepts around chaos, math, and consciousness
which might lose the reader. Even so, I'm going to focus on adding
to it first before I revise and streamline anything.

I hope this motivation to write continues. I really like this
story so far.

[0] Emergence
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/emergence
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Medieval Times</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220421-medieval-times/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Medieval Times
April 21st, 2022
----------------------------------------

Yesterday was my 28th trip to Medieval Times, the dinner theater
show with jousting knights, falcons, horse dancing, and
community-theater quality sword fights. It is one of my favorite
things on earth and if you haven't had the opportunity to enjoy it
before, I hope you do in the future.

Tickets are almost always available with some sort of discount if
you pop around online for a few minutes. That typically gets the
cost down to around $30-35 per person. Thus, dinner & a show for
a reasonable rate.

And the dinner is quite something! You'll have fountain drinks or
tea, coffee, tomato bisque, basically a half a chicken (massive
leg and thigh), half a baked potato, corn on the cob, and
a dessert. There's plenty of alcohol available too, and I would
highly recommend it. You want as much social lubrication as you
can get, because...

The key to medieval times is that the amount of fun you have is
directly proportional to the amount of energy you put in.

Your wait-staff will do their best to work a bit in-character,
calling themselves wenches or serfs. The more veteran servers will
even take to the arena from time to time as squires for the
knights. The other actors (knights, queen, chamberlain, etc) will
be more focused on their character portrayals and mingle with the
crowd before the show and during it as well. Just like character
actors at Disney World, these folks tend to have a lot of
experience with ad-libbing with the fans and really help to sell
the experience.

But even with that, and the show you're going to see, if you come
in and passively watch without bringing your own energy to the mix
you're missing half the fun.

So how do you make it awesome? Well first, bring a crowd. The
energy in the show comes from the crowd cheering. Be boisterous.
Be crazy. Cheer in over-the-top chants. Start a wave. Get into it!
Sure it's scripted, but so is wrestling. See how fun that can be
when the crowd goes wild?

If you bring a big group you can dominate the cheering for your
knight's section and that in turn will help them get more into
their character. You'll attract the attention of the other actors
and they may even riff with you. When your knight wins or falls,
be dramatic with them.

What else? Get the people around you into it too. This is where
alcohol helps. Put on your extrovert face and make eye contact
with the kids sitting nearby. Encourage them to get up and cheer.
They'll see you having fun and mirror it, and it'll bring a whole
other level of awesome to the show.

When a knight wins one of the skill contest in the first half of
the show they'll earn flowers they can toss to the crowd. Help
guide their choices by having your big mass of people point toward
the little kids, or the old ladies. Cheer for them too.

Yes, you'll be eating with your bare hands. Enjoy that! Make
a mess. They'll give you wet-wipes later anyway. Stomp your feet,
start a chant. Order more booze.

This is my secret sauce for a great outing and if you follow it
I can guarantee a lot of fond memories. When I went to the show as
a kid my dad was my role model for getting into it. As my friends
got married over the years, we made a point of going to a Medieval
Times show the day after the reception as a second celebration.
That experience taught me the joys of cheering for the bad guy,
and of being very drunk with friends cheering on comically bad
fight choreography. As a dad myself, I have taken my son almost
every year of his life as part of our family tradition. He's
learning to carry the torch.

If there's a castle near you, go check it out! It's great for
family reunions, birthday parties of all ages, or just a silly
saturday night. I hope you have a great time and share your
experience with us here.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Planet Of The Apes</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220320-planet-of-the-apes/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Planet of the Apes
March 20th, 2022
----------------------------------------

I just watched the new-ish Planet of the Apes trilogy with my son.
He loved them and so did I. I saw the second film a few years back
and remember thinking it was just an incredible piece of
filmmaking. The cinematography was brilliant, as was the acting,
pacing, and the classic betrayal story. Now that I've finally seen
the third I can say without reservation that it's one of the
better trilogies of the 21st century. Matt Reeves contributions on
2 and 3 are a marvel.

If you are interested in seeing it, try and find subtitles for the
ape-parts. It will help convey some of the depth of story.
I watched subtitle-free the first time and while it's possible to
follow and enjoy, there's a distance that grows between you and
the apes.

Also, there's something wonderfully cathartic about seeing these
films and unreservedly rooting for the humans to all die already
so the apes can inherit the Earth.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sensory Deprivation</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220316-sensory-deprivation/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sensory deprivation
March 16th, 2022
----------------------------------------

Today I spent an hour in a sensory deprivation tank for the first
time. My wife bought me a gift certificate to a local place that
has the tanks and some fancy chair massages, but with the COVID
situation as it was I was waiting to cash in. This week happens to
be light at work so the time finally felt right.

My appointment was at 11:30 and I managed to show up right on
time. The door was locked, oddly, so I knocked and was welcomed
inside by another American transplant. He runs the shop and said
he was just getting in and getting another visitor set up in the
next room. She was a very pregnant 20-something. I heard their
conversation and recommendations for comfort. The guy knew his
stuff. It turns out his wife is also quite far along in her
pregnancy, so they've been getting a lot of practice.

Once it was my turn I was led into a private room and given the
tour. Here is the shower for getting clean and rinsed before
entering the tank (just as is the custom at the pools in Iceland).
Here is a table with towels and a spray bottle. When you are in
the tank if you touch your face or rub your eyes, the salt water
will get all over you and it's impossible to clean off without
some help. Thus the spray bottle and the hand towel. And here are
a pair of earplugs. They're not really necessary for the sound, as
the room and tank are well insulated, but they do keep the salt
water from going deep in your ear canal. I was sure to put those
in right away.

Finally I met the tank itself. It was bigger than I expected,
which was a welcome relief. I was a little worried about feeling
claustrophobic, but this gave me room to stretch out nicely. It
was lit from within and looked clean and inviting with a little
motion to the water as the pumps did their thing. The lid opened
from the front, by the head, much like a car's trunk. You could
step in, squat down, and use the handle inside to pull the lid
closed above you. The owner of the shop recommended settling in
with the door ajar first, then closing it if comfortable. He said
leaving it open to the air might make you cold.

The lights and sound are on a timer. Everything dimmed quite low
and soothing spa sounds were barely audible in the background.
After I washed and got into the tank I quickly settled into
position and lowered the lid. The light faded first, about five
minutes in. Then the sounds faded out too, perhaps ten minutes
later. It was around this time I decided I was actually quite hot
with the lid closed, and the cool air would be welcome. I pushed
it open a foot or so, and found my happy temperature. The whole
room was blacked out at this point, so there was no functional
difference to the experience other than heat.

Now that I was alone with my thoughts it was game-on. I have,
thankfully, participated in a number of silent retreats in the
past. I think these have prepared me well for being alone and the
difficulties of quieting the mind. 

I can remember my very first three-day silent retreat: I arrived
on a Friday evening and all the participants greeted each other
normally. We had dinner with conversation, getting to know one
another a bit. Silence began when the meal ended. We were to
remain in silence until the end of Mass on Sunday, at which time
we would have a lunch together with conversation again. That first
night my mind was on fire with cool ideas and things I wanted to
remember to say when silence ended. I wrote a huge amount of notes
in my Moleskine notebook. Saturday continued that way until the
early afternoon. I was walking in the garden and I found a single
leaf dangling about 10 feet below its tree, attached only from
a single strand of a spider's web. No spider was in sight but
I was enraptured. My whole attention went on that leaf and the
spider silk strand. In those minutes I forgot about my notebook
and remembering things for later. I finally started to let go of
my rapid-paced mental dialogue and just be present. And that's
when I finally met the silence, truly. 

Once I found the silence it became an old friend. I try my best to
find it as quickly as I can on retreats now. I generally don't
take a notebook at all anymore, unless the retreat has some sort
of focused agenda to work on at specific times. Instead I try to
settle into that emptiness and just exist there.

A sensory deprivation tank is the perfect place to do that.
I dusted off an old trick I used on an 8 day retreat a few years
back: I thought about a book I want to write, and about a specific
character. I focused my attention on that character and what makes
her unique. What defines her, what part of her personality gets
her into trouble? And after just a couple minutes of that focused
thinking, not about anything that was bothering me, or about my
actual life, I felt my attention begin to wander. And so I let it
wander away from the book, and towards the silence. There it was.

The rest of the time passed quickly. The lights began to fade back
up, and there was the spa sounds again. In another minute they
were on in full and I knew it was time to get out, wash up, and
head home. Washing that much salt out of my hair took a while, but
there was no rush. I spoke some pleasantries with the owner on my
way out, but I was still carrying the silence with me. That's one
of my favorite parts of retreats as well. How long can I keep the
silence there with me, present underneath everything going on.
Sadly it seems the answer is roughly as long as I spent in silence
in the first place. One hour gets me one more. Three days get me
three more. Thirty days got me a bonus month.

I love the silence. I love the peace it brings, even when I'm back
in the thick of things.

I really enjoyed my time in the tank. I may do it again, but
probably not right away. They offer a monthly pass, but it doesn't
feel like the right fit, personally. Maybe once a quarter or twice
a year? It's a lovely ritual, though. If you have the opportunity
to try it out I would recommend it. Try to be at peace and let go.
It's surprisingly easy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Buying Books</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220306-buying-books/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Buying Books
March 06th, 2022
----------------------------------------

A fedi post from @DL6MHC@mastodon.radio I just read said:

"I've started to abuse Amazon for browsing articles, getting
inspirations, reading (hopefully non-fake) reviews and finding out
what a solid price for an article is. Then I buy my stuff
somewhere else."

For years I would go to big booksellers like Barnes & Noble or
Borders (before it shut down) to browse books and discover
interesting things only to then purchase them online from Amazon
where it was much cheaper. Sometimes I'd even purchase while I was
still there browsing. I felt so clever.

My battle then was against the big bookseller who came in and
killed so many beloved tiny bookshops. Amazon was the scrappy
alternative in my mind, and a means of revenge.

These days I will browse Amazon for things, read reviews, gather
intel, and then purchase else where, just like the fedi user
above. I wish I could say that it was an act of will power and
ethical justice at work, but it's mostly because ordering from
Amazon to Iceland is prohibitively expensive.

I take solace in the world of coffee, though. When Starbucks swept
in and killed many of my beloved local coffee shops I did not bow
down, but fought back by supporting those who remained or
abstaining completely. When the third wave of coffee brought back
the renaissance of local shops I was ready to dive right in. 

But books... sadly, my options are less stellar. For one thing
I try not to gather too many physical books. I can't move them
easily or cheaply and I end up giving them away. So I favor ebooks
or library books. Those I could still get cheaply from Amazon,
I suppose. The general mentality that "Amazon isn't affordable"
I've developed here seems to have clouded that issue in my head.
I'm more likely to seek a 3rd party site, direct-from-author
purchase, or grab from the library. For older works, out-of-print
stuff, or obscure things I dust off my tor browser and visit
z-library.

Anyway, not sure where I was going with this, but there ya go.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ukraine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20220221-ukraine/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Ukraine
February 21st, 2022
----------------------------------------

Oh no. Poor Ukraine.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
