<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Federation And Gopher</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180627-federation-and-gopher/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Federation and gopher
June 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Some of you guys were talking about a "federated gopher" on
Mastodon the other day. At first I was all into the idea and
getting ready to chime in with support. But then I started
thinking about what that would mean and I hit a wall. I think my
understanding of federation in recent context has skewed away from
the community idea. With all the work on ActivityPub and the new
clients popping up in the Fediverse I feel like I should probably
spend the time to figure out what it is everyone is talking about
when they use the word Federated.

Since we're talking definitions here, I figured I should start by
telneting to my happy dictionary [0] that I described in an old
phlog post [1]. Then I ran my query: "define english federation".
Here's what popped out:

  <security> The establishment of some or all of business
  agreements, {cryptographic} trust and user identifiers or
  attributes across security and policy domains to enable more
  seamless business interaction.

  As {web services} promise to enable integration between
  business partners through {loose coupling} at the application
  and messaging layer, federation does so at the identity
  management layer, insulating each domain from the details of
  the others' authentication and authorization.  Key to this
  loose coupling at the identity management layer are
  standardized mechanisms and formats for the communication of
  identity information between the domains.  {SAML} is one such
  standard.

From the sound of that definition, gopher is already federated in
that identity information between domains is inherent to the
protocol because it's irrelevant. There's no authorized use
mechanism here and the act of hosting content on a server is
enough to identify the source. Since I host on gopher.black, if
your use of gopher queries my server you have used standard
mechanisms and formats for the communication of that information
between the domains, right?

Maybe the reason I'm having such difficulty is because my only
exposure to federation as an idea has been via things like
Mastodon which have far more interoperable parts. Content from one
independent system is consumed and becomes content within another
one, and the source of that content, the author, server, etc, all
need to be accounted for in the communication. That requires more
than gopher for sure.

Even so, I'm not satisfied. I think there's more to federation
than that definition. The context in how people discuss it seems
to imply something else, but I can't put my finger on exactly what
that might be. Distributed systems like IPFS come up a lot in
those discussions, but I don't see a black & white relationship.

I guess my slow brainmeats can't get past the idea that federation
means I control my shiz but it can interact with everyone elses
shiz in the same way. Am I so far off? Let me know with a reply or
email or mastodon or a hand written letter.

Yes! Hand written letters are my absolute favorite. They
demonstrate all that extra effort, they're physical treasures, and
I get to silently judge your personality through bullshit
handwriting interpretation that I make up on the spot. Everyone
wins! Send me an note with a reference to a pgp key and I'll send
you back my mailing address on the down-low.

Cheers, fedi-gophers

8[0] Telnet to dict.org	dict	dict.org	2628
[1] CLI Tricks: Dictionaries
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180405-cli-tricks-dictionaries
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Modafinil And Ketosis</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180626-modafinil-and-ketosis/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Modafinil and Ketosis
June 26th, 2018
----------------------------------------

 Ketosis
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Ketosis

Ketosis is a metabolic state in which some of the body's energy
supply comes from ketone bodies in the blood, in contrast to
a state of glycolysis in which blood glucose provides energy.
Generally, ketosis occurs when the body is metabolizing fat at
a high rate and converting fatty acids into ketones.

 Modafinil
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Modafinil

Modafinil is a medication to treat sleepiness due to narcolepsy,
shift work sleep disorder, or obstructive sleep apnea (OSA). While
it has seen off-label use as a purported cognitive enhancer,
evidence for any benefit is lacking.

Common side effects include headache, anxiety, trouble sleeping,
and nausea.

   -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  - 

As mentioned previously in my phlog, I eat a ketogenic diet in
order to stay in a state of nutritional ketosis (a blood
concentration of β-hydroxybutyrate ketones in the range of 0.5-3.5
millomolar). Eating this way and staying in ketosis gives me
a number of benefits:

  - Less hunger
  - Easy avoidance of sugary foods
  - Easy intermittent fasting
  - Even energy levels throughout the day (no afternoon crash)
  - Smoother, healthier skin (eczema goes away)
  - Less inflamation in my joints
  - Lower incidence of restless leg syndrome
  - Increased mental clarity
  - Lots of sexy food-porn on my Instagram
  - Ability to talk about my diet for hours an annoy coworkers
  - Easier weight loss

In order to stay properly in ketosis and avoid the normal pitfalls
I need to eat and drink a certain way. In short:

  - Manage my macronutrients:
    - Eat less than 20 grams of net carbs per day
    - Hit my protein goal (~100 grams)
    - Eat fat only until feeling sated

  - Manage my micronutrients:
    - Eat between 3-5 grams of sodium (yes, that's a lot)
    - Eat at least 2 grams of potassium
    - Get enough magnesium to avoid sleep and heart issues
    - Otherwise make sure to hit my normal dietary needs for
      vitamins & minerals

If I do those things, ketosis happens. It's that simple. I don't
bother to log anything in a food tracker anymore because it's
become so intuitive. Huzzah!

I also occasionally take the drug modafinil as a cognative
enhancer when I need to GET SHIT DONE. Based on my current supply,
last order, and a bit of math I average 1 dose every 3 weeks. Not
too shabby, if I do say so myself. In the past I've had stretches
where I've found it helpful to take more, and I've had holidays
from it where I forget I even have it.

The effects of modafinil are interesting. If I were to boil it
down to the essence I would say it increases your ability to focus
and quickly manage task-switching. A side benefit of that focus is
that I seem to have more motivation to do the tasks in front of
me. I can juggle more projects and input at once. Writing is
smoother and more efficient, and often much longer than it would
be otherwise. If I have a pile of work that really needs my full
attention and I want to tear through it with gusto, that's when
I'll pop the pill. 

Its primary purpose was for use by the military to enable high
congnative functioning without sleep. It does that very well. If
I take a pill anytime after 9am, I will not get to sleep before
1am. It is very easy to pop one in the afternoon and coast on
through the night without noticing. I don't use it that way, but
many others do. I generally wake up early on days I plan to take
a pill and pop it around 6am, then get to work.

Since it functions in similar ways to caffiene, I've found it's
best for me to avoid coffee while "modded up". It triggers anxiety
in me which is detrimental to GETTING SHIT DONE. Modafinil also
makes it easy to forget about food and drink. It's an appetite
suppresant and your focus on work can distract you from healthy
habits like drinking water. This is a big mistake, too. Modafinil
will crush your brain with suck if you don't drink a crapload of
water. Headache central over here.

Since I need a lot of water for ketosis and also for modafinil
I made sure to focus on that today while I was doing both. So far
I'm sharp as a tack, motivated, and clear of headaches. The
effects of mental clarity from modafinil and ketosis do seem to
stack somewhat. All in all, they seem well suited to one another.

Now I'm off to drink another liter of water to keep it that way.


</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Solar Hydroponics</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180624-solar-hydroponics/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Solar Hydroponics
June 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm doing some mental planning toward a very small hydroponics
experiment. I will likely start with just one plant, an herb, in
a solo environment. I know I can do a self-contained system
without aeration at that scale, but I want to build it as if it
were a larger system, but in miniature. I want the system to be
off-grid as well. I'd like it to be as mechanical as possible, in
fact.

I found one little video oh a solar radiation powered aerator.
Basically, it was an empty air chamber that was darkly colored and
had no-return valves that forced air in one hole only and out
through the "pump". The out-bound port was covered in a bubbler
rock. When the sun hit the bottle it heated the air inside, which
forced the air forward out into the reservoir. When the bottle
cooled it would draw more air back in through the outer valve. If
the sun cycled exposure at a fairly regular interval, it seems
like it might help circulate some into the reservoir over time.

There were lots of problems with it, of course. The pressure of
the temperature change didn't create that much air flow. If the
light were fairly constant it would only expel once and then be at
rest. It needs some work to draw and billow more air. I was
thinking about having a radiometer inside the chamber, as air flow
inside would force it to work as a more continuous air pump, but
I think those barely create enough force to spin in a vacuum. I'm
close to a solve here that does not involve electronics at all,
but I'm just not quite there.

Once that's fixed, my next line of inquiry will be nutrients. What
exactly goes into those fertilizer bits and how can I generate my
own source without a store. Is that even a reasonable thing to do?

If I can solve for solar powered aeration (not using solar panels
& electronics) and nutrient creation, then I should be able to
construct a fully off-grid, automated hydroponics rig. I am just
awful at remembering to do things on a regular basis, so if this
is to succeed I absolutely must automate.

Other things to consider:

- Auto-balancing water distribution to the correct levels
- Rotation / cycling position for sun exposure
- Portability of net systems for transferring between small
  & larger rigs
- Auto-timing of nutrient injection & mixing

Do any of you have experience in hydroponics? Anything to add?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Weight Update</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180622-weight-update/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Weight update
June 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Quick note today to mark my 40lbs loss milestone. I'm feeling
great and need to stick with it forever and ever. Addicition has
never been a part of my personality, but I'm coming to accept that
I need to treat carbs the way an alcoholic treats the drink. There
is no such thing as just one taste for me. Abstinance brings me to
a better version of myself.

Disclaimer: Ketogenic diets are not a magic pill for everyone. It
works very well for me and I'm happy to talk to anyone about it,
but if you're into something else that's working for you, keep on
kicking butt. Now, back to more bacon & butter...
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moleskine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180621-moleskine/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Moleskine
June 21st, 2018
----------------------------------------

In 1997, Modo & Modo reintroduced the Moleskine notebooks to the
world, taking the design from 19th & 20th century french designs
as described in the writings of Bruce Chatwin. There's a lot of
mystique surrounding the design and use, but what they really
represent is a mass-market blank book with a solid design for
pocket use.

I started carrying Moleskine notebooks in 1998 and still carry
them today. In fact, in 2001 I bulk ordered them and have
a stockpile stored away just in case something weird happens in
Italy. They're fantastic books, not because of some magical
quality of manufacturing or design, but because they are cheap and
moderately well constructed. If they were built to last I would
have a harder time using them. That's the point I want to get at
in this phlog.

When I first started keeping a journal it was just that, a diary.
I wrote thoughts in it and dated them. They were serious and
heartfelt as only a teen can produce. They were horribly
embarrassing and trite. I wrote six pages one night on the deep
philosophy behind wanting to grow out my hair, a work of literary
genius that boiled down to the essence: "I like Highlander."

It took me a while to develop a system for using the notebooks
that really worked for me. In the end, my system boiled down to,
"turn the page and write". The key to using the notebooks
effectively was to not have a category or a use or anything.
I pick out one book at a time, turn the page, write whatever
I need, then turn the next page. There is no system beyond that.

I keep all of my Moleskines. They line a shelf in my office,
multiple rows and stacks. If you were to pick one up and thumb
through it you'd find ideas for stories, notes from D&D games,
shopping lists, phone numbers, sketches, notes from phone calls,
and any number of other random things. This is not a problem, this
is the heart of the notebook. It is a book for using, a book for
capturing the moment in the written word (or drawing) and moving
on. That's what makes it special.

Whenever I doubt myself in this, I'm reminded of Leonardo Da
Vinci's notebooks. He was possibly the greatest polymath in human
history and his greatest works are scribbled next to shopping
lists. He sketched anatomy next to questions about the volume of
water traveling in a river. The juxtaposition came from
a practical desire to not waste paper, and that's a bit of what
drives my choice as well. I don't want to spend a lot of money on
a blank book. If I do, I'll be scared to write in it for fear that
my words won't do it justice. I'll set it aside and give it
a grand purpose. I'll say to myself, "You can write only your
observations from meditation here." Or maybe, "This will be your
travel journal on your next trip to Iceland." In the end, it will
stay on my shelf, unused. Instead, the Moleskine in my pocket will
capture those notes along with everything else.

If the Moleskine design isn't for you, check out the US Army Green
Logbook. They're a standard with any quatermaster and can be found
in many places around the globe. They're cheap, plentiful, and get
the job done. You'll be hard pressed to find a military officer
that doesn't have a shelf of them at home.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Turnover</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180618-turnover/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Turnover
June 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm losing one of the developers on my team. He's decided to move
on to another job. He's a really solid programmer and a nice guy
and it's a shame to lose him.

I knew he was in a position to be looking and I tried to warn the
management team about it. Unfortunately, the types of things he
needed to stay weren't thing I could offer. It happens sometimes.
I hope to get a chance to spend a bit of exit-interview time with
him and get some feedback on my own management style. Maybe
there's something to be learned.

I'm not sure if he ever reads my gopher content (though I am sure
he knows about it). If so, I'm sad to see you go, but wish you the
best of luck at the new gig.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Pen Pals</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180617-pen-pals/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Pen Pals
June 17th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was looking into some leadership and management training stuff
recently [0] and it's been really helping me make progress as
a team leader. There's plenty you can learn on-the-job, but it's
helpful to get good advice from a trusted source.

[0] LEADx
    http://leadx.org

While looking at content on engagement I ran across a really
enlightening piece of information. People tend to value praise
based on the effort put in to giving it.

At my current company we've gone through a lot of different
systems for calling out exceptional work. We've had some official
things, some local office things, manager made-up things, and
they've had wildly different reactions. Our current system is
a corporate level point system with a rewards site where you can
log-in and pick out items you want with your accrued points. It
is, almost universally, ignored. It means nothing to individuals
getting points. There's no real public system for acknowledging
peers. It's pretty much useless.

Contrast that with our most successful system: an oversized
post-card that had some award blurb stuff up top and a big open
text area underneath where a manager would hand-write what you did
to make a difference. They were peer nominated and manager
approved. We announced them at "town hall" meetings so everyone
would hear about your awesomeness as it was read out. There was
a small financial award with it, but it was secondary. People kept
those things and put them up on their desks.

This all brought me back to an on-again-off-again conversation
thread that floats around gopherspace: comments. I love when you
guys and gals send me an email about something I wrote, or post
a reply or acknowledgement in your own phlog. It means so much to
me because you put in the effort. It wasn't a drive by "like"
button. In managerial terms you didn't just give me a nod and say,
"nice work," you took time out of your day to write me a note.
That's awesome.

It also makes my mind wander the path to hand-written letters. I'm
an infrequent letter writer, but when I write or receive one it's
always special. I have a bag in my office of every hand-written
letter I've ever gotten.

My handwriting isn't great. I don't always have brilliant things
to say in a letter. Honestly, the content isn't all that much
different from an email, except I know it will take some time to
reach the person and responding is more difficult. I try to say
things more completely. I invest more time and energy into it.
I have to buy a stamp, after all.

I'd like to write some letters again. Any of you up for it? My
contact info is in my About page [1] including encryption options
if you feel like sending me an address or PO box.

[1] About
    gopher://gopher.black/1/about
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On Magick And The Forces Of Will</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180605-on-magick-and-the-forces-of-will/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
On Magick and the forces of will
June 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

christyotwisty [0] asked a question on Mastodon tonight:
[0] christyotwisty
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/christyotwisty

  Those who use #magick to #manifest a material desire: what is it
  about the manifestation that tells you it's magick and not
  Baader-Meinhof phenomenon?

There's a lot to unpack in her request and I want to do it
justice, hence why the answer is happening here on gopher rather
than in a 500 character toot. 

I want to proceed logically. Taking to heart what Voltaire said,
"If you want to converse with me, first define your terms," I'll
attempt to do that now.


          ---------- Defining Terms ---------- 

[1] Magick
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Magick (Thelema)

The addition of the k to the end of magic has long been credited
to Aleister Crowley's Thelema to differentiate the occult practice
from stage magic and illusion. Since he coined the term I'll use
his definition here: "the Science and Art of causing Change to
occur in conformity with Will".

His definition was quite loose, and if you read his works you'll
see he uses the term interchangably to describe mundane acts, such
as like reaching out and picking up a pencil, along side ritual
magic which normally springs to mind. The idea that will can cause
any change in an object that it would be normally capable of in
nature is not surprising, then. With the right effort, anything
can be achieved. This line of thinking conflates and contrasts the
concepts of free will with destiny and leads to some... creative
conclusions.

For the purposes of this post I'm going to narrow Crowley's focus
into just his later category of occult action of will to affect
change. I suspect this is where christyotwisty was going with her
question. As we proceed I'll try to further narrow this definition
and cross-reference it with other, similar concepts.


Frequency illusion

As defined on Wikipedia's list of cognative biases: "The illusion
in which a word, a name, or other thing that has recently come to
one's attention suddenly seems to appear with improbable frequency
shortly afterwards (not to be confused with the recency illusion
or selection bias). This illusion is sometimes referred to as the
Baader-Meinhof phenomenon."

In addition to this specific illusion bias, I'll also try to
address synchronicity and confirmation bias. There's really a host
of mental phenomena which are all interrelated in the context of
the question.


       ---------- Subject-matter clarification  ----------

Before addressing the question directly I think I should say
a word or two about the subject of magick itself. There is
a strong divide between groups of people who entertain the idea of
magick as a serious phenomenon and those who dismiss it as
childish delusion. All too often, the former group is then
stigmatized and preconceived prejudices run wild, which
unfortunately make serious discussion all but impossible.

I want to disuade that behavior by stretching the concept of
magick to include similar practices that fall under more widely
acceptable terminology. Remembering our core definition of
magick--the use of will via occult (or paranormal) means to affect
change--we can find many common practices that fit the mold.

From the East:
[2] Qigong
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Qigong
[3] Tai Chi
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Tai chi

The entire system of Chinese medicine falls into this category,
manipulating unseen energies through will and the use of natural
actions, herbs, and meditation. Falun Gong, Prana, Tao Yin and so
on also fit.

From the West:
[4] Laying on of hands
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Laying on of hands
[5] Exercism
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Exercism
[6] Hypnosis
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Hypnosis

In the west there are many religious practices deeply rooted in
Christianity which clearly fit the definition of magick we're
using. Between the extremes of popular religious rites and the
ridiculed parlor ritual there is a whole range of activity. Yoga,
reiki, mindfullness medititation, and good old basic prayer all
seek to affect some sort of change through the focus of primarily
mental expressions of will.

As you can see, the question here is not limited to casting spells
in a circle under a full moon. You could reasonably reword
christyotwisty's question:

  Those who pray for change: what tells you it's working and not
  just your mind playing a trick on you?


         ---------- Efficacy of Magick ---------- 

[7] Efficacy of Prayer
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Efficacy of prayer

Using the framework we've established, we can use the more
mainstream magickal practices to explore the scientific
investigations of occult phenomena. In the link above, there is
a wealth of information about the difficulties in statistical
inference and falsifiablity, measurability in general, and
a survey of the types of studies that have been done. I'd strongly
recommend reading that page cover-to-cover with an open mind.

The most striking thing to me about the challenges of study and
the measurability of outcomes is that we must take a sacred
activity and measure it by elements that are profane (to use the
terms of Mircea Elliade). Ultimately the change that should occur
is a profane one, though. It must be concerned with the material
world or else we're using our mind to change our mind, which
doesn't seem to fit our narrow definition of magick. Perhaps using
your mind to change the mind of another could fit, but the method
would be the key deliniation (batting your eyes and winking can
certainly create new thoughts in someone else but is that
magick?).

If our outcomes are limited to the physical then they are
measurable. What comes next is to determine what action of will
can create these effects at a significant rate above a control.
This is a very rigorous way to avoid issues of the Baader-Meinhof
phenomenon or other cognative biases.

So what do studies of that have to say? From the article above,
a "systemic review of intercessory prayer reported inconclusive
results, noting that 7 of 17 studies had 'small, but significant,
effect sizes' but the review noted that the three most
methodologically rigorous studies failed to produce significant
findings". Overall, there's just not a lot of rigorous research
being done. Even if we did have reliable results, prayer
represents only a small fraction of the occult magickal practices
in the world, and prayer itself has thousands of forms and formats
to consider.

So where do we go from there? Let me start by pointing out that
after thousands of years of advancement and the advent of western
medicine, the Chinese still widely practice their traditional
medicine. That alone speaks to its efficacy. The west is bringing
over learnings from China every day.

And that brings me to my next point: occult practices are occult
because they are unknown. The paranormal describes things outside
of normal experience. Occult practices once included metalurgy.
What we don't fully understand is often ignored and denegrated
rather than explored and investigated. There is a staggering
amount of knowledge we have confirmed through science only
hundreds of years of casual practice. As an example, the entire
field of optics existed and flourished for centuries before we
understood the science of shaping glass.

Our understanding of the effects may be limited, but out
understanding of the method is almost completely absent. In one of
the prayer studies there was no significance in those prayed for
vs those not, but there was a lift in those that knew they were
being prayed for. Perhaps when it comes to immune responses we
have a greater power to manipulate the physical in ourselves than
in others through will alone. Perhaps this one of the infinite
varieties of action wasn't the specific one needed.


         ---------- Narrowing the Scope ---------- 
          
Has any of this answered christyotwisty's pertenant question? Not
quite yet. Let's reiterate in case you've forgotten where we're
aiming with all this:

  Those who use #magick to #manifest a material desire: what is it
  about the manifestation that tells you it's magick and not
  Baader-Meinhof phenomenon?

The question does not question that a manifestation has taken
place, but instead seeks to understand how you can confidently
credit it to the magickal act rather than any number of cognative
biases or coincidence. To properly answer this I have to point to
three seminal works in religious study:

The Idea of the Holy (Das Heilige) by Rudolf Otto published in the
early 20th century. It has never gone out of print and it has been
absolutely instrumental in the development of comparative religion
as a field of scholarly study. 

The Sacred and the Profane by Mircea Elliade, who I referenced
earlier. Elliade takes up the mantle that Otto laid down and takes
it to the next level. Notably, he discusses how the myths and
stories of a people lead to the creation of their symbols. Those
symbols lead to an experience of hierophany, or a breaking through
of the profane world to glimpse the Sacred and its Mysterium
Tremendum, to feel fascinated, terrified, and infinitely the
"creature" in the midst of creation. This relationship through
culture and symbols to find a common experience of the Sacred
crosses all known boundaries and shares almost identical patterns
in the Eastern Orthodox Church as it does in Aboriginal tribes of
Australia or the Lenape Indians in America.

The Varieties of Religious Experience by William James. This was
a book written from James' lectures in Scotland on the various
types of personal expressions of religious understanding. There
are many, many ways that people relate to the divine or the
Sacred, even if they consider that Sacred an unconscious power and
not a diety. Those experiences have many things in common and fit
into categories that allow for discussion of the experience
without having to dwell on the truth of that experience.

Taken together these books tell a story without a narrative. It is
the story of a people, of all people, and our relationship to
powers beyond our conceptualization that we yearn for in a million
ways and experience in glimpses between breaths. The truth of the
stories that lead to these experiences is not as important as the
fact that we all reach the same experiences once we get there. The
symbols change, but that moment of connection with the divine is
a spark of Truth that rings inside us and overwhelms doubt.

Christy, you ask how you know whether your manifestation comes
from magick. The science is still out, but the experience is
redily accessible. Choose your own pathway and look for the Truth
that resonates deep inside your spirit. Ultimately the confidence
that something comes from a magickal place will come from an
understanding that something has happened that is beyond the
normal world and has pierced that layer separatating the Sacred.
There is a feeling in it that can be communicated and shared.

Ask a priest how they heard the call and watch for that smile.
That's how you know.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Git</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180603-git/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Git
June 03rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's some panic in the air over Microsoft courting Github.
Alarmists are pulling their projects down, moving to self-hosted
Gitlab instances and so on. I'm confused by the whole thing,
though. Git isn't github. My repos aren't property of github, even
if it's one of the remotes. I have everything up there mirrored in
several remote locations. That's the beauty of git! It's
distributed. Every repo is the complete repo.

orbifx summarized it best over here [0].
[0] Decentralised Git
    gopher://notes.orbitalfox.eu/0/note/15ec76d8-a67c-4c19-abc4-103184760186

This gopher hole is a great example. It's currently located:
- on this laptop I'm writing on
- on gopher.black (raspberry pi)
- on SDF
- on Tilde.town
- on bitbucket.org
- on my macbook air at work
- on a backup tower at work
- on my PC in a VM in VirtualBox
- and probably some other places I forgot about

I think the lesson here for people shouldn't be to fear Microsoft
nabbing Github. The lesson should be, distribute your shit,
people! Use git for awesome.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mastoconflict</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180602-mastoconflict/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Mastoconflict
June 02nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Mastodon is having a little tiff right now over the introduction
of a new feature: trending hashtags. As the project maintainer
puts it, it has been the most requested feature addition for over
a year. When it rolled out, though, it was met with widespread
criticism and, in many cases, open hostility. The rebuttals back
and forth quickly escalated and became personal. Pretty much
everyone involved is greatly unhappy, regardless of their position
on the issue.

Meanwhile, I'm sitting back here thinking to myself, "democracy in
action." A collective developed and idea with their voices (the
addition of trending hashtags). When that idea was implemented,
other collectives disagreed. They weren't aware of its
development, they argue. It is unsafe and can be used for evil. It
will target groups who are often targets and make Mastodon unsafe
or unwelcoming.

There's one person in charge of the project. He must be the
problem. If it weren't for him, surely the issue would be put to
rest. It's as simple as that, because a "pure" democracy will
always work things out. This is an example of corruption of the
perfect, federated state.

Sound familiar? Yeah, I thought so. The issue isn't having
a single leader. The issue is that groups of people have different
wants and needs. This is inherent to any sized group of people
greater than one. You cannot make them all equally happy. You
cannot serve every single use case simultaneously. The utopia of
democracy does not exist, just as it does not exist for communism,
or socialism, or even monarchy.

So what do we do? We use our brains. We make decisions that help
as many as we can. We use our morals and make decisions that hurt
as few as possible. We don't cross lines that shouldn't be
crossed. We listen to the words of the suffering and try to ease
that suffering. We say to those with excess, "you have excess.
Your priorities are lower than those who need help."

This is all but impossible in systems that favor group-think. The
power in those systems comes from those who can manipulate the
system. Who can speak loudest is often the one with the most
money. The wider the spread of power, the more this systematic
influence becomes absolute. It can devolve to cult of personality
eventually. The key to the recipe is broad reach of voice.

What is the countermeasure? Strong-willed leaders who can champion
the "right" decisions. What makes those decisions right? The
things I listed above. What ensures a leader will execute those
decisions and not others? That depends on your system. In
government, there's not much, though a constitutional system can
help balance it. It's easy to slide into despotism. In social
systems like open source projects, the answer is the freedom to
move on. The system is open source and the protocol can work with
other projects. Mastodon can be forked and formed into something
else by others with a different set of principles. If the current
leader of the project does not implement policy (in the form of
software features) that reflects the needs of the people, that's
the easiest path to take. No bloodshed, just moving on and
building something new.

But back to the question of trending hashtags themselves. Are they
a good idea? Probably not, at least in the way they've been
implemented so far. There's been a lot of valid points about how
bad actors already abuse similar systems in other networks.
There's nothing currently in place to prevent that, and the
distributed nature of the network makes stopping those attacks
even harder than on Twitter. There have been very good ideas to
tweak the feature to avoid the abuse. Ultimately it should come
down to a cost/benefit analysis. Unfortunately it's more likely to
come down to the loudest screamers. But that's democracy.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
