<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Track</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180531-cli-tricks-track/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 31 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CLI Tricks: track
May 31st, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is a part of a series of phlog entries where I will share
some of my command line tricks, tips, and scripts.


## track ##

Fitness trackers are all the rage. Chances are that you've got one
on you right now, weirdo. Collecting data about your own behavior
is pretty neat. It's extra cool if you can do it in a way that
doesn't also give that data away to nefarious strangers who want
to take over the world, but I digress.

I like tracking my shiz too. I've used my phone to count steps in
the past, and I have a scale in my bathroom, and a tape-measure
for my big belly. But where do I save those numbers so I can look
back on my amazing progress of awesomeness later? I don't really
want to hand that over to Google or MyFitnessPal. They don't need
to know that stuff. I could just store it in text files for myself
and parse them later.

And that's exactly what I decided to do. I keep some csv files in
dropbox, or in nextcloud, or in syncthing. But logging stuff in
CSV files isn't really fun, so I wrote a little tracker app to
help me out.

Now you can enjoy the glory of my crappy little program too!
First, grab a copy over on github [0] and install it.

[0] track
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/track

It's really easy to use. Start by checking the man page or
spitting out some help:

  $ man track

  $ track -h

See how to use it? Great! You're done!

But seriously, it is really basic. You can just add a new metric
to track by tracking something to it for the first time. It allows
only one data point per day. It doesn't care what format that data
is in.

There's probably easy ways to break it, so, um, don't do those.

Do you have something you want to add to it to make it better?
Cool! Make a pull request and gimme-gimme. I probably want that
feature too.

Oh, as a side-note, the data I used in my post "Fat" [1] all was
logged with this script. I have an example in that post of how to
generate a graph on the command line using the jp utility. Check
it out.

[1] Fat
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180407-fat

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tracking As Stalking</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180527-tracking-as-stalking/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Tracking as Stalking
May 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Stalking - 

"criminal activity consisting of the repeated following and
harassing of another person."

"a course of conduct directed at a specific person that involves
repeated (two or more occasions) visual or physical proximity,
nonconsensual communication, or verbal, written, or implied
threats, or a combination thereof, that would cause a reasonable
person fear."

There is an argument made by those practicing large-scale data
capture and aggregation of individuals that the data they collect
is public information, and therefore it is legal and justified.
Even if the information collected was indeed all public--and I do
not agree to that line of argument at all--then the question is
still not settled. The very act of repeated visual proximity
(which is transferrable to digital media via cyber-stalking
definitions) which could cause a "reasonable person fear" falls
clearly within the bounds of stalking. If it is a corporation
commiting these acts, then it is no less culpable than if it were
an individual. After all, corporations are people too, right? [0]

[0] Corporate personhood (Gopherpedia)
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Corporate personhood

The act of data aggregation of an individual carries with it the
inherent threat of what is being done with that data. As more
revelations are brought to light informing the public of the
deeply unsettling targeting of individuals for political
manipulation, commercial activation, or social harassment, the
fear increases. What else could be done with that information?
Even if nothing is actually put into motion, the act of
collection, of monitoring, is in itself a form of digital stalking
that explicitly undermines the argument of "public information".

Anonymous collection of data into aggregate data sets that cannot
be retargeted or focused to communicate outbound with a specific
population or person is still problematic. If that data allows you
to segment or infer the actions of a type of person or group,
especially one that routinely faces subjugation or discrimination,
then the act of collection contributes to a justifiable fear of
persecution. It is stalking.

The counter argument to all of these points is that the underlying
economic power of the internet is governed and supplied by data
collection. It is a capitalist requirement that some sort of
economic incentive be present to promote the growth and stability
of the systems. Money talks, or so the argument goes. How can we
cut out advertising and still have nice things? Will everything
need to become a paid subscription?

Here's the thing: there is no inherent, inaliable rights to
Netflix. Facebook is not a universal, precious entity that
deserves the protection and preservation of all people. The only
thing that fits that category is the people themselves. If
protecting individuals and groups of people damages these systems,
then that is the path that should be followed. If those systems
can find an alternative, legal way to continue their operations
then kudos to them. There is no argument that should value the
continued operation of a social network over the safety of even
a single individual. 

Money talks in capitalism, but capitalism cannot be allowed to run
unchecked. The morality of all people must pull on those reins and
keep careful watch. Systems of governance cannot become
subservient to the interests of economic forces over those of
moral obligation. Any systems of governance that allow this will
ultimately fail. First they will fail their people, and eventually
they will fail completely, often with dire consequences to both
those in power and those oppressed by it.

Data collection is a simple thing. It's easy to watch tracking
events fire and show up in pretty graphs. It's easy to use this to
optimize your experiences, improve them, make the user's day
a little easier. It's easy to look at the rosy garden that casual
analytics presents and see only the flowers. Just like
capitalism's promise of innovation through financial competition,
the premise is beautiful on the surface. Left unchecked it will
corrupt. That corruption will consolodate power and influence.
That power and influence will allocate more benefit to the few in
charge at the cost of the masses. The flowers are not worth it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Move Your Feet</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180522-move-your-feet/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Move your feet
May 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

It's been a while since my last phlog*. I've been wanting to get
back on gopher and do some serious plain text awesomeness, or at
least comment on the really cool happenings around the space. Cat,
love your diet, tell me more! How are you and your partner going
to handle it when you go back down under? Sparkipx, how's Felix
holding up now that you've been able to ride for a couple weeks?
Is it harder to do long distances on a folding bike than
a non-folding one? I've never tried one before. jynx, I'm totally
fascinated by single player RPGs and I need to go back through and
read up on your stuff. Tabletop role-playing is my #1 activity of
awesome, and that sounds stellar. horsemans has a cool gopher
wishlist that you guys should check out. I bet you can offer a lot
of responses there. [0]

[0] horesmans - gopher wishlist
    gopher://horsemans.online/0/2017-12-29-gopher-wishlist.md

Several of you are on vacation or soon returning. Welcome back and
all that. I hope you'll share insights and adventures. I love
travel stories so much. Hell, I love STORIES so much. tfurrows,
I'll be checking out Variations soon! Oh, and I have a Fiskers
push-mower and it's badass. I have to use it twice a week or the
grass grows too long for it to be effective. That part sucks. But
if you have a really small lawn, it's so nice to be able to handle
it quietly and "naturally".

Recently I've been absorbed in a string of poor projects at work
that have been eating up my mental energies. The work isn't hard,
but the clients have been difficult. I've been avoiding
unnecessary computer time as a way of disconnecting. Marry that up
with some unexpected (but welcome) consulting work, and my time
became even more short. Mostly, though, the thing that's kept me
away is a rededication to that principle I mentioned in recent
posts, deliberate practice.

I've been working on my shakuhachi quite a bit, and even met with
my kali instructor in the park at the side of a lake for
a fantastic jam in the rain. He built me a new shakuhachi, which
is just fantastic. It's a 1.9 (slightly deeper sound than the
standard 1.8) jin nashi flute and it's absolutely perfect. I'll be
sewing a new case for it soon, and an extra for him as well in
thanks.

I've also been walking a shit-ton. Every morning I wake at 6:35
and head outside to walk 2 to 2.5 miles on the canal towpath that
is the road I live on. Each evening, after putting my son to bed,
I head back outside and do another 2 miles. Sometimes I zip around
the neighborhood for a change of scenery. Sometimes I head into
town and walk the sidewalks. Most often I stay next to the canal
where I know the landscape features that mark my distance by
heart. I pop headphones in and binge audiobooks while I'm out
there. It's heaven.

Walking is a "keystone habit" for me, a term I learned from that
book on Habits with the yellow cover that I can't remember the
name of. When I walk, I do other good things as well. I eat well,
I sleep well, I think clearly. If I don't walk, holding on to the
other things is more difficult. So, walking rocks!

Hopefully I'll have more to share soon. In the meantime, I need to
go for a walk.

------

* I have a pet peeve about when people waste time in blogs and
phlogs talking about how they haven't posted in a long time.
That's the nature of the medium and the repetitive act of
explaining or apologizing for it serves no purpose except to make
you self-conscious. Now here I am doing it myself. Stupid.

</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>More Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180522-more-updates/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 22 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
More updates
May 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

That's a little depressing. After 11 days away I just wrote a long
update that is substantively the same thing I wrote 11 days ago.
I feel the need to amend this with some additional updates:

FBI File [0] - I received my FBI results. There are no records of
me in their files. I could follow up and request further research
looking for me in cross-references, but I think I'm good enough
with what I got. I'm still waiting for replies from the other
intel orgs.

[0] FBI Files
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180505-fbi-files

Poison Sumac [1] - It's finally gone. Holy shit that took a long
time.

[1] Poison Sumac
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-poison-sumac

The Hobbit [2] - The boy is loving it. We haven't gotten to read
it every night, but he's so excited about what's coming (I gave
hints). He talks about Smaug all the time despite having not met
him yet. He's excited for the giant spiders because I have
horrible arachnophobia and he thinks that's funny. We're just
leaving Rivendell and the Last Homely House. I can't wait for
Gollum!

[2] The Hobbit
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180418-the-hobbit

Finally, I've been brainstorming some ideas and getting some good
feedback from mastodon folks about a talk I want to present at
Barcamp Philly this year. I'll get it all ready to go and
hopefully it'll be something people want to attend. If not, I'll
record it and keep it ready for 1436CON/Port 70 [3].

[3] Port 70 -or- 1436CON
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180412-port-70-or-1436con
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Practice Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180511-practice-updates/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Practice updates
May 11th, 2018
----------------------------------------

It's good to celebrate small victories. This week has been full of
them. I've kept up with my goal of deliberate practice regarding
writing, playing music, and even exercise. It feels great to be on
track. The next challenge will be to keep it going through the ups
and downs and boring times.

Regarding exercise, I'm well back into ketosis again (thank God)
and I've ramped up my walking. I'm walking two miles in the
morning and again in the evening. That's long been my foundation
or keystone habit to hold everything together and it seems to be
working again. I have been eating well and not snacking. The focus
has helped with my practice. All is well!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fixing Rss</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180509-fixing-rss/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fixing RSS
May 09th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This is a quick test where I'm trying to fix the RSS lists on SDF
and tilde.town. My auto-pathing fixer regex needed some love.
Cross your fingers!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Tfurrows Reliable Tech</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-re-tfurrows-reliable-tech/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: tfurrows - Reliable tech
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

First let me offer my condolences to tfurrows for the loss of
a long phlog post. [0] Your loss is also ours.

Second, let me suggest a slight modification to your workflow:
- Generate a tmp-file for authoring
- Process tmp-file in a secondary stage for formatting

If the formatting fails, you still have your temp file.

Alternatively, vim will save everything you type to a swap-file as
you type it, and preserve undo states. Come to the dark side.

[0] tfurrows - Reliablility of Tools
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/tfurrows/phlog/2018/ajt_reliabilityOfTools.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On The Default Of Democracy</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-on-the-default-of-democracy/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
On the default of democracy
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Richard Stallman found himself in nerd-headlines today when an
article circulated on Hacker News and Lobste.rs titled "Who
Controls glibc?" [0]

[0] Who Controls glibc?
    http://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/

In short, some of the maintainers of glibc attempted to remove
a comment that Stallman had added to the source in the 90s. This
comment was a reference to censorship in the form of hyperbole
about the function being named "abort". Sensationalized headlines
refer to it as a bad abortion joke, but that is clearly
a mischaracterization. Regardless of the content of the comment
itself, it was Stallman's response that created a minor
controversy.

The maintainers claim they had consensus in the community that the
comment (they refer to it as a joke) was unnecessary in the code
and should be removed. Stallman stated firmly that it will not be
removed. This created an abrupt conflict in the eyes of the
maintainers who believed that the project is community controlled.
Stallman stated unequivocally that he is the de facto decision
maker of the GNU Project, which trumps community.

Now I've previously mentioned that I'm a monarchist [1], and not
in favor of democracy as a general rule. You will therefore
understand why I inherently support Stallman's position. But lets
dive a bit deeper anyway.

[1] Confessions of a Monarchist
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180315-confessions-of-a-monarchist

The glibc maintainers are upset that Stallman, who in their eyes
is not contributing code to the project, has authority over it.
They feel that a majority rule (or at the very minimum,
a consensus of the vocal maintainers) should decide how the
project proceeds. We see this in a lot of open source projects
these days, and it's promoted in the form of community guidelines
more and more often. The struggles that happen within communities
as a result of actions against the community guidelines is often
public and brutal. In most cases it involves the ostracising of
individuals and occasionally forks in code bases. In some more
extreme cases it involves doxxing and personal attacks.

In all these cases the problem is pointed at the individual who
broke outside the line of acceptable behavior according to the
group. This is bread-and-butter stuff for democracy, especially in
the age of maximized sensitivity. Let me give you a real example:

Just a few weeks ago there was honest conversation and debate, in
some places heated, about whether or not a variable name within
the Mastodon source code should refer to the "dark web" by that
name. Never mind that the dark web is not something named by
Mastodon, the community at large converged on the idea that it was
inherently racist because it suggested some sort of evil, and by
including the name "dark" it was somehow also inferring that black
people are bad. I'm not exaggerating here. This was the actual
conversation and the community as a whole moved in the direction
of "yes, that's racist and we should rename the variable name."

There's so many things wrong with the specific argument, but I'm
not going to address them at all. Instead I'm going to focus on
the structure of community projects themselves. They are almost
always created by someone. Not some group, some one. Even when
a group is involved, there is almost always a leader, whether
defined or naturally as a part of that group. If the leader is the
ultimate decision maker, then these conflicts have an authority
which can address issues that arise. If there is no authority, the
issue must be raised to everyone. In many cases, the very act of
raising an issue to everyone is going to escalate that issue, and
once it is escalated, there's no bringing it back to Earth.

In a group which has an authority, the whims of the masses are
normalized. The fad of the day is quietly passed by and the
project avoids moving with tides of opinion. If given over to the
mob, the loudest will prevail or destroy.

Democracy's lie is that everyone gets an equal voice. This isn't
true because not everyone is equally aware and equally
understands, and has the equal background to make their equal
decision. Instead, the group relies on those who stand tall and
shout to the masses. "Rally around me!" they cry. "I understand
what needs to change." And so the democratic individual is
presented with a choice. It is not a choice born of her natural
inclination and understanding of the world, but a response to
a loud individual. This spark invites other loud individuals to
chime in and steer the conversation. Their voices are not equal
still. The ability to speak may be equal, but that is all.

(Small aside: I live next to a canal with a lot of wildlife. A fox
just managed to sneak up on a goose and it is being loudly
murdered outside my window. It's rather distracting.)

Where was I? Oh right.

Stallman is in charge of GNU. This is good. Without someone in
charge, GNU would float on the eddies of popular opinion. Instead,
it is a bulwark standing for freedom. Freedom as in liberty.
Liberty, which I've previously discussed, is diametrically opposed
to equality. Of course that's how he runs things. Any other way
would be as ridiculous as the idea of censoring a joke about the
overreach of censorship in a project dedicated to fighting fucking
censorship.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deliberate Practice</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-deliberate-practice/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Deliberate Practice
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's a fantastic article circulating on the typical nerd
portals today regarding "deep work" and "deliberate practice" [0].
Give it a read if you haven't already.

[0] The Importance of Deep Work
    http://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/

One of the things I enjoyed most about the post was the summary of
methods of deep work taken from a great book on the subject [1].

[1] Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World
    http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25744928-deep-work

  Monastic: 
  "This philosophy attempts to maximize deep efforts by
  eliminating or radically minimizing shallow obligations."
  — isolate yourself for long periods of time without
  distractions; no shallow work allowed. 

  Bimodal: 
  "This philosophy asks that you divide your time, dedicating some
  clearly defined stretches to deep pursuits and leaving the rest
  open to everything else." – dedicate a few consecutive days
  (like weekends, or a Sunday, for example) for deep work only, at
  least one day a week.

  Rhythmic: 
  "This philosophy argues that the easiest way to consistently
  start deep work sessions is to transform them into a simple
  regular habit." – create a daily habit of three to four hours
  every day to perform deep work on your project.

  Journalistic: 
  "in which you fit deep work wherever you can into your
  schedule." — Not recommended to try out first, since you first
  need to accustom yourself to deep work.

This put into words a struggle I've had with my own strategies.
I've tried dedicating a set amount of time, sort of like "Rythmic"
but that time hasn't been long enough to establish a deep work
flow. I've set aside days of the week for it like Bimodal, but
rarely with the isolation necessary to really dig in. Occasionally
I'm successful, but I think it's more to do with luck, or
a motivation I happened to find that day, than any deliberatet
planning.

In the past I've spoken about freezing up when an opportunity for
exploration appears [2]. I'm combatting that with organization of
lists so I can refer back to these projects I have moving and
I don't waste time spinning my wheels. All of it is a part of the
effort to get back the time that should belong to me that I give
away out of a combination of laziness and poor planning [3].

[2] Stuck
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180501-stuck
[3] Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution

Ultimately, there are skills I want to improve. The top of that
list are my writing craft and the Shakuhachi [4]. In reality the
list is quite a bit longer. Even so, I have the ability, I have
the time, and I have the necessary components to make a go of it.

[4] Shakuhachi (UTF-8)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/explorations/shakuhachi

Deliberate practice, not just sitting around fiddling with crap,
is the difference I'm missing. I've told it to my son a lot, and
I'll continue to do so in the future. You can't just go along with
things and expect to learn and grow. You need to do the hard
things [5]. When I practice with the Shakuhachi, I can't just go
sit on the porch and play improvisations for twenty minutes.
I have specific things I need to improve: timing, embouchure,
breathing dynamics. My writing is the same. I'm working on
a writing exercise and I've given myself a specific goal to focus
on brevity. This is good.

[5] Do the Hard Thing
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20171108-do-the-hard-thing

It's not just about doing things with my hobby time. It's work in
itself and I need to commit to it, at least a significant portion
of the time, if I want to improve.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fbi Files</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180505-fbi-files/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
FBI Files
May 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was sorting through some of my bookmarks tonight and I ran
across something that I pinned for myself and completely forgot
about. It's a site called "Get My FBI File". [0]

[0] Get My FBI File
    http://getmyfbifile.com/

It's a simple form that generates you a bunch of letters that you
can print off and mail in under the Freedom of Information Act to
request government agency files on you. (The FAQ states you can
send the requests even if you aren't a US citizen, with a few
modifications).

I filled out all of them and will drop them in the mail Monday
morning. I doubt there's much in those files on me, if anything,
but I just don't know for sure. That's enough reason in itself to
send the requests.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
