<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Yourtilde Com</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181118-yourtilde-com/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
yourtilde.com
November 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm adding another mirror of gopher.black to yourtilde.com,
a fantastic new addition to the tildeverse run by deepend.

gopher://yourtilde.com/1/~tomasino

Just in case, ya'll!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Perfection</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181113-perfection/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Perfection
November 13th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Very soon I'll be giving up my role as a manager and moving back
into the world of sole contributer. For the past five or six years
I've been a VP level director of a team or teams of developers. At
one point in time I had 24 direct reports across three offices.
These days I just have 3 direct reports at one office. Regardless,
my role has been primarily focused on facilitation, management,
coaching and strategy, with a heavy dollop of analytics work. It's
not that I don't get my hands dirty; I code all the time. It's
just that I'm typically jumping in to solve a single problem, or
create a framework, or rescue something gone astray. I rarely find
myself in the position of building things from scratch.

There's freelance, of course. I just completed a landing page for
a pharma company that will be launching shortly. It was an excuse
for me to learn the newest CSS features out there, CSS-Grid, and
to make sure I'm still sharp. Everything went exceptionally well,
and I should have a nice little side-money from it soon.

With the move out of the country I wanted to refocus on what
I enjoy doing and what keeps the stress level low. My dad was
a work-a-holic, and I could easily see myself falling into the
trap. I'm staring at a career crossroads: do I continue on my
present trajectory and take on C-suite positions and eventually
start my own company, or do I take a step back and focus on family
and friends at the cost of salary. It's not an easy decision.

I'm hoping Iceland can be a disconnect from a life of things.
I don't want all this stuff I've gathered. I have too many
hobbies, too many computers, too many projects. I want to take
a walk with the family and spend more time seeing my son smile.
While I don't want the stress of bills piling up, we're well past
the level of comfortable living. I don't need more if we're just
going to spend it.

So with the move to Iceland I'm giving up my VP title and my
managerial duties. I'm taking a step back into a senior developer
or lead architect role (whatever we decide to call it). I'll be
building things again and taking a pay cut to align. This feels
good and right, at least for now.

And it gives me the opportunity to think about what I enjoy about
coding. I'm a perfectionist in the work I do professionally. When
given a task I dig deep and try to solve it in ways that
anticipate things the designers never dreamed of. I anticipate the
ways testers will try to break things. I focus intensely on
pixel-perfect design execution without any compromise of speed or
accessibility. I want every piece of throw-away advertising trash
I build to be a perfect specimen.

Today I built a digital sales aid for pharmaceutical reps
detailing a drug that treats ALS. It's a tool that shows off payer
data and coverage information relevant to the doctor being
detailed. The original plan was for a national-level print piece,
but we managed to get the company to send us a feed of their raw
data. I worked on some analysis in R and generated specific
breakdowns for their list and found an elegant way to side-load
it into their presentations. The reps have extremely personalized
digital pieces now, which will give the home office interesting
analytics on the use of the tools and allow us to further segment
their targets by degree of concern about access and coverage, if
the client bothers to look at the data we collect anyway.

While the content I'm building isn't particularly interesting
I found ways to challenge myself, level it up, and focused on
perfection. That gives me a great deal of satisfaction. When I can
build something (even something dumb) perfectly in the first try,
that's a great feeling. I'm looking forward to more of that soon.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Notice</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181112-notice/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
NOTICE
November 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This gophermaster uses cookies (and milk). By reading this content
you acknowledge and accept our use of cookies for eating purposes.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moving Part 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181112-moving-part-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Moving, part 1
November 12th, 2018
----------------------------------------

The next few weeks will be hectic. On Sunday the family begins our
two week family visitation excursion. We head to Raleigh, North
Carolina first to visit my wife's best friend for a couple days.
Then we head to Charlotte to see her family, my best friend, and
have a massive Thanksgiving dinner (usually ~50 people). We have
a day or two to recover and hang out with her family then we head
to Myrtle Beach to see my parents. We'll spend a second
Thanksgiving dinner with them (and get even fatter) before moving
over to a beach condo for the rest of the week to finally relax.

The beach condo is great. It's one of my happy places, at least at
night, and this far off-season it's very quiet. Last year I got
a lot of writing done, and I'm hoping for more of the same this
time around. It's also a time to dive deep into my Icelandic
studies and really pound in some hours. It's been going well, but
I wish I could dedicate more time each day.

When we return home the house will be mostly packed and
disassembled. We'll crash one night all together in the master
bedroom, and then the movers arrive. Half of our stuff has been
trimmed, sold, given away or donated. Of the remaining things,
some will move to our new apartment and the rest goes into
storage. That storage will eventually go to Iceland in July or
into long-term storage down in Charlotte. Hopefully we'll be able
to trim a bit before then, though.

Once we spend a few days moving in and getting settled, we settle
on the sale of the house. With that clear I'll have about a week
before the Christmas holiday hits. Flash, bang, New Years!

I did say things are hectic, right?

Once we're clear of the new year the hard-core planning for the
Iceland move begins in earnest. I forsee a binder.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Little Reminder</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181107-a-little-reminder/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A little reminder
November 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Whether you're thrilled or devestated with the events of the past
few days, I just wanted to remind everyone that representative
government is terrible all around! :D
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dad</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181106-dad/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Dad
November 06th, 2018
----------------------------------------

My dad can't feed himself anymore. I want to scream about that or
cry about it depending on the moment. Instead I sit quietly and
think about him through my life. The good moments come to me. I'm
not sure where the bad ones went, with time.

I remember throwing a ball, playing with a tape recorder, being
chased on a field. I hold strong.

His voice calls my name and I answer, "daddy" and I am six years
old. I am my own son, and I see all our eyes. Then I cry.

I'm not ready for him to go.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Knives</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181027-knives/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Knives
October 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm on my way out the door to a Halloween party, so I'll make this
quick. Knives are awesome. They are tools first, weapons second,
and infinitely useful. I'm a Mora Classic #1 and #2 kind of guy.
I have some Baretta tactical knives thate are pure beauty and
a karambit that is sex in sickle form, but the work horse knife
for me is the Mora. It runs about $12 retail in the US, and if
well cared for it's multi-generational. The steel is excellent,
the handle is sturdy. Great stuff.

I'm disappointed in knife limiting laws. I don't see much of
a parallel with gun control there. Gun's are instruments of death.
Knives CAN be, but it is not a primary purpose. It's the same with
an axe, or a hammer, for that matter. I like useful things, and
sometimes those useful things are also beautiful. Knives... mmm.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Seasoning</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181019-seasoning/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
seasoning
October 19th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I recently acquired a pair of beautiful pans. You may already be
aware that I have a distinct preference for cast iron cookware,
and so it may surprise you to learn that these pans are different.
Instead of cast iron, these pans are wrought iron!

US-ION ran a kickstarter [0] for what they call "Solidteknics Iron
Skillets". They've developed a machining process allowing them to
mass produce wrought iron instead of cast iron. The result is
theoretically both lighter and more durable. Quite a claim!

[0] Solidteknics Iron Skillets
    http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/495892923/solidteknics-pans-1pc-wrought-iron-not-cast-lighte

Cast iron (and now wrought iron) cookware is an heirloom item.
Rather than buy-it-for-life, it's buy-it-for-generations. That's
value I can get behind! This lifespan doesn't come without some
effort, though. You must care for your stuff if you want it to
last. This is true of pretty much everything, but it bears
repeating. My lovely leather shoes need polish. My knives need
sharpening and oil. Iron needs seasoning.

What is seasoning? In layman's terms, it's a coating of oil that
goes through a chemical bonding to the surface of your pan. It
protects the iron and makes it non-stick. It's safe! It won't
break down and poison you like other **coughTEFLONcough**
coatings.

Is it a lot of work? I don't think so, but others disagree.
There's also about 7,000 different opinions on how best to keep
a pan clean over time, "properly" season it, etc. Here's my
method; you can decide for yourself if it's too much work.

  -  -  -  -  -  -    Initial Seasoning    -  -  -  -  -  -  

Brand new iron is naked and fragile. If you buy an unseasoned pan
it may look like steel or it may be black already. Regardless, it
needs some extra special care right in the beginning to get things
off to the best start. Putting on the initial layers of oil is the
slowest part and requires the most effort. After this, upkeep is
extremely simple.

To season a cast iron (or wrought iron) you'll need the following:

  - sandpaper, fine grit
  - a clean cotton rag or old t-shirt
  - a can/tub of vegetable shortening
  - the pan/skillet/dutch oven/whatever
  - an oven that can reach 480°F

1. Begin by thoroughly scouring the pan clean. It may have shipped
   with beeswax coating to protect it in transit, or there may be
   old layers of seasoning to work off. Hot water, scrub with
   soap, do it to it.

2. Dry the pan by hand, and then in the oven under low heat until
   you're sure there's no moisture on it at all.

3. Lightly scratch up everything with the sandpaper. Roughing the
   surface will help the first layer of oil bonding.

4. Heat your oven to 480°F or there-abouts.

5. Dab your cloth into the shortening, then rub it over the whole
   pan, inside and out. Make sure you get the handle too. Don't
   leave anything untouched. You don't need a lot of shortening or
   a thick coat. In fact, the thinner the better. Wipe it on and
   then use a clean part of the rag to wipe it off again.

6. Place the pan upside down into the oven. Cook it for 90
   minutes.

7. Turn off the heat and allow the pan to cool completely.

8. This is the sucky part. Now that you've put a single coat on
   your pan, it probably doesn't look too different. It may have
   darkened slightly or maybe not. This initial process needs to
   be done at least twice more. If you have the time over the next
   couple days you should do it as much as you can. I usually do
   five or six iterations. Go back and repeat steps 4-7. You don't
   need the sandpaper on every round. You can use it a second time
   after that first seasoning if you want, but I don't bother
   after that.

9. Your pan is now mostly seasoned, but it can use a little extra
   love in the cooking area still. For this secondary seasoning,
   we'll use your stove top! Crank the heat on a burner to high
   and get ready.

10. Add a thin layer of shortening to the inside of your pan and
    also a bit to the base, but don't bother with the handle this
    time. We're focused on the cooking area.

11. Place the pan on the burner, but get ready with your cotton
    rag. Wrap it around a wooden spoon or grab it in some tongs so
    you can use it on the pan while it's on the heat.

12. For the next minute or two, continuously wipe the cotton on
    the pan while it heats up. This will cause it to smoke A LOT.
    Open some windows, turn on a fan, etc. Let it smoke like this
    for up to 30 seconds, then cut the heat.

13. Allow the pan to cool for 10 minutes, then repeat steps 9-13
    a few more times.


Your pan should be uniformly black. It should not feel sticky or
tacky to the touch. If it does, you have too much oil on it still
and it didn't fully bake in. Wipe it down with a clean cloth and
toss it in the oven at 480°F again for another 30 min to get
everything fully baked in.

You can use this thing to cook now! But cook on what? That's the
best part. You can cook on anything from an induction stove to an
open fire. It's so versitile!

You might notice a little sticking of delicate foods like eggs
& fish when you first start using it. That's because your
seasoning is just at its beginning. That effort may have seemed
like a little or a lot, but it's the start of the long road of
maintenance that will make your pan better and better with every
use.

 -  -  -  -  -  -    Maintenance Seasoning    -  -  -  -  -  -  

Every time you use the pan you need to clean it. This should also
go without saying, but people get really weird about cast iron and
logic seems to go out the window. Much conventional wisdom says
that you don't need soap, or SHOULD NEVER USE SOAP, with your pan.
I'm here to tell you that's a bunch of crap. Please use soap.
Clean your pan well. Stay healthy. Don't be gross. But how...

1. Clean of the physical bits from your pan with a hard plastic
   scraper or metal that won't gouge the seasoning. I have a 6"
   square of chainmail that I use. Don't press super hard, just
   get all the stuff off the surface.

2. Soap and water and clean the thing like you would any other
   pan. Seriously. It's fine. If you want to be extra cautious,
   don't use a lemon based cleaner. Acids wear down seasoning (not
   that fast).

3. THE MOST IMPORTANT STEP!!!! Dry the everliving shit out of that
   pan. I hand dry mine and then immediately place them back on
   a burner and crank it to medium heat to cook off any lingering
   water. Soap doesn't harm anything, but it will if little bits
   of it remain on the surface. Water will do much, much worse.
   Rust sucks (though even that can be fixed).

4. While the pan is still warm from the drying heat, dab a bit of
   vegetable shortening on a rag and do a quick surface rub on the
   inside and base (don't do the handle unless you plan on putting
   it back in the oven to bake).

5. Crank a burner to high heat and cook & smoke that shortening
   for a minute or two. Then congratulate yourself on adding yet
   another layer of seasoning to your awesome pan of awesome. This
   is what will build up more and more over time and turn it into
   the only pan you ever want to use for cooking anything ever.
   Ever.

6. Let it cool, and put it away for 20 minutes until you can't
   wait to use it again!


That's it. That's my routine with all my iron. The new wrought
iron pans are on seasoning #4 in the oven cooling. They'll get two
more rounds today before I start the stove top. Does that seem
like a lot of work to you? I bet my grand children will appreciate
it when they inherit the super skillets.

One final note: if you have cast iron that has rusted, it is
probably still fine as long as it hasn't created a pit or hole.
You can sand off the rust, or in extreme cases you can use some
home chemistry to remove all the rust through electrolysis [1].
Once the rust is gone, go to the start of my initial seasoning
instructions and act like it's a new pan. A day or two later and
it's back to working order. If you're a thrifty person you can
pick up old cast iron from yard sales or flea markets for
a dollar, put in some elbow grease with your shortening, and have
a brilliant cookware set!

[1] Cleaning cast iron with electrolysis
    http://www.castironcollector.com/electrolysis.php
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sprezzatura</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181018-sprezzatura/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
sprezzatura
October 18th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Castiglione wrote The Book of the Courtier between 1508 and 1528.
It's a fantastic read, if you've never tried it before. In the
book he introduces a newly created word: sprezzatura, defined as -

  "I have found quite a universal rule which in this matter seems
  to me valid above all other, and in all human affairs whether in
  word or deed: and that is to avoid affectation in every way
  possible as though it were some rough and dangerous reef; and
  (to pronounce a new word perhaps) to practice in all things
  a certain sprezzatura [nonchalance], so as to conceal all art
  and make whatever is done or said appear to be without effort
  and almost without any thought about it."

It defined the ultimate goal of the courtiers at the court of
Urbino. Look amazing at everything without trying.

Ever since reading the book in high school that has been my
personal motto. Even mentioning it "out loud" here in gopher
undermines the effort somewhat. Talking about trying to be awesome
at everything and seem effortless ... you get where I'm going with
this.

Anyway, I wanted to mention it for two reasons:

1) When I was thinking of a show for anonradio, my first idea
   centered around sprezzatura, but I couldn't come up with a way
   to make it a thing without also completely destroying that
   thing. It's tricky! Try it in your head.

2) Some people these days are all too eager to "own" their
   failings. There's a pride in being bad at stuff. It's probably
   a generational thing. Showing vulnerability is cool as shit, or
   something. I'm drunk and an old man when it comes to this
   stuff. I'm of the opinion that if you can be a total badass at
   every fucking thing, then you should be a badass at every
   fucking thing. If you're a badass at 90% of the things, then
   focus and fix that last 10% in the quiet of your bedroom until
   you can be a rockstar there too.

That's it. The whole point of this was to tell you all to go be
badass at everything. Not good at something? Don't tell me about
it. Go fix it. No.. don't fix it, master it. Master the heck out
of that thing and then do it routinely as if it's no big deal.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading Plain Text</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-reading-plain-text/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reading plain text
October 14th, 2018
----------------------------------------

While reading moji's phlog [0] I started considering how I read on
gopher, or in plain text in general versus my methods on the web.
Certainly I do more scanning in a web browser, which I attribute
at least partially to the various font and style treatments that
both allow for and promote the bite-sized ingestion of content.
There is also an element of reading fatigue that plays out
differently here in plain text, and thats where my mind went (not
to say that moji was in any way tiring).

When I'm tired of reading on gopher it is instantly apparent.
I skim over blocks of text looking for something to jump out at
me, but that isnt how it works. Warning claxxons blare in my brain
and I shut down figuratively and literally. It's clear I need to
do something else and come back later. I get no such signal on the
web. I peruse long past the point of usefulness. I trade reading
for browsing. Surfing becomes skimming. Infinite scroll is
infinitely useless.

My time in text is short and productive in the sense that I get
something from it, whether information or entertainment. My time
on the web offers sone of that, but the trappings are extreme and
it is all too easy to give more time than necessary or helpful.

This is intentional. Capitalism demands attention, and it is that
monstrosity which guides the design patterns on port 80. Even
informational sites follow the patterns because that is what
drives engagement. Look at the analytics, measure your performance
goals. How do we keep them longer? How do we show them more ads?
How do we get them to spend a little more?

I'm sick of environmental leeches. I want my landscapes clear and
clean. Mow down the billboards and flashing neon and let me get
where I'm going on my own terms, please.

There is no way out on the web. The experience is condemned to
these patterns. People scream when you try to pull that bandage
off. They demand more convenience despite the cost. The masses
want to live like this. We're the weirdos for questioning it.

[0] moji - unlearning
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~moji/phlog/20180928-unlearning.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
