<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>A Bottomless Pit</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200516-a-bottomless-pit/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
a bottomless pit
May 16th, 2020
----------------------------------------

That's what it feels like right now, even with all the
preparation. I lost my dad tonight. About an hour ago, in fact.
I didn't get to say goodbye, but my sister did. I'm glad for that.
He's not suffering anymore, and neither is my mom. I'm glad for
that too. I'm glad I had time to prepare for it, to think on it
and test my emotions in the years leading up to this. I'm also
really glad for all the time I had with him.

It's just that after all of that gratitude and reason I eventually
hit a memory where he isn't my dad, but he is daddy and I'm eight
years old again and it is an unfathomable pit of despair that
opens around me knowing that he's gone and I can't ever hold him
or talk to him again. I'll carry that part until my own days are
up.

I won't want my son to feel this way. I'll want him to be happy
with his life and live it brilliantly. My dad surely wants the
same. I'm glad for that knowledge too. I just miss my daddy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Few Years Of Gophering</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200513-a-few-years-of-gophering/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
a few years of gophering
May 13th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Our good gopher citizen, solderpunk, recently shared his past
three years of gophering [0]. What an awesome view, seeing how
many posts we make on gopher month by month.

[0] solderpunk - three years of gopher
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~solderpunk/phlog/three-years-of-gopher.txt

I wanted to see the same thing on my own gopher history and he was
kind enough to share his code. With very little tweaking, I found
this:

Aug 2017: 13 posts |**************************
Sep 2017: 15 posts |******************************
Oct 2017: 09 posts |******************
Nov 2017: 10 posts |********************
Dec 2017: 08 posts |****************
Jan 2018: 19 posts |**************************************
Feb 2018: 11 posts |**********************
Mar 2018: 34 posts |************************************************
                  +|********************
Apr 2018: 23 posts |**********************************************
May 2018: 14 posts |****************************
Jun 2018: 12 posts |************************
Jul 2018: 17 posts |**********************************
Aug 2018: 07 posts |**************
Sep 2018: 07 posts |**************
Oct 2018: 10 posts |********************
Nov 2018: 11 posts |**********************
Dec 2018: 05 posts |**********
Jan 2019: 09 posts |******************
Feb 2019: 02 posts |****
Mar 2019: 04 posts |********
Apr 2019: 11 posts |**********************
May 2019: 06 posts |************
Jun 2019: 04 posts |********
Jul 2019: 03 posts |******
Aug 2019: 03 posts |******
Sep 2019: 08 posts |****************
Oct 2019: 01 posts |**
Nov 2019: 02 posts |****
Dec 2019: 04 posts |********
Jan 2020: 02 posts |****
Feb 2020: 04 posts |********
Mar 2020: 06 posts |************
Apr 2020: 02 posts |****
May 2020: 01 posts |**

March of 2018 was CRAZY! 34 posts in 31 days. I guess I had a lot
to say. We'll see how this goes in the future. :D Thx solderpunk!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Plaintext Passwords</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200512-plaintext-passwords/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Plaintext passwords
May 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

A recent set of exchanges on the fediverse reminded me that
there's still plenty of poorly run websites and institutions who
are still storing user credentials in plain text. Yes, unencrypted
plain text.

I remember the horror in my heart back in 2008 when I was trying
to learn about virtual credit cards from my bank (a cool idea
which went away for no good reason). I was on the phone and the
customer service representative asked me for the 3rd and 5th
letter in my password to verify my identity.

Did it hit you too? Did that little pit in your stomach open up
like it did for me? How could this person know a specific
character in my password?

Needless to say, the conversation I had with the bank that day
quickly changed. I wish that was the only time I had the
experience, but it happened a second time in the same year in
a conversation with Fidelity, who ran my 401k at my job at the
time. In that case I was stuck. I couldn't choose to move my 401k
to another provider. Thanks America.

Anyway, there's a ton of these places including a downright scary
number of banks (looking at you Tesco). I figured gopher needed
some place to reference the list of shame, so I made one [0] over
in my Experiments section. There's a link over there to the master
list managed in github as well. If you have others to add, make
a PR and help shame them.

[0] List of sites storing passwords in plain text
    gopher://gopher.black/0/explorations/plaintext/list-of-plaintext-passwords.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Out Of The Past</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200430-out-of-the-past/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Out of the past
April 30th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I adored this band when I was a teen. They were local and played
mostly in bookstores and small venues or the occasional folk
festival. I would see them as much as possible, listened to their
music around the clock... you get it.

Well, 20+ years later, the keyboardist and main songwriter was
stuck at home due to covid-19. He sat at his piano and started
playing a song that he'd forgotten all about. It was from the time
leading up to their second indy album but the feel wasn't right
for that collection. Much later on he thought he'd lost all traces
of it: gone from memory and never recorded. Here we was, just
barely remembering the tune.

Then serendipity struck. Today he dusted off an old, ancient iPod
and plugged it in. Amazingly it still worked. He put it on shuffle
with his collection of thousands of songs when what should start
coming through his speakers but the very mystery song he'd lost.

Sometime in the mid-nineties he had put together a demo track with
just him and the lead singer. One take, no practice. It had been
mis-labeled as a different track ("More to This") and tossed into
a collection and forgotten.

Today it speaks across time not just to him, but to all of us who
loved that music and the band, and to everyone who spends the time
to listen. I can't even put into words how much it means to me.

Story to Tell (Soundcloud)
    https://soundcloud.com/dwayne-keith-kessel/itunesexport-m4a/s-Zq9n0kPcDms
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Renting A Video Game</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200429-renting-a-video-game/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Renting a video game
April 29th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Nostalgia struck. I'm back in a childhood home giddy with
excitement over the Nintendo Entertainment System which stealthily
arrived as the last present opened at Christmas. My parents sprung
for the unit that came with two game cartridges, not just one:
Super Mario Bros. & Duck Hunt on one cartridge, and Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles on the other. It's visceral. I can smell the box.
Feel the plastic.

Games then were expensive. I suppose they're still expensive, but
I don't buy so many. A game like Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles cost
about $50 in the late 80s. With some napkin math, that's around
$80-85 today. Pricey, as I said. We didn't get new ones often.
Years--and many garage sales--later, I have 57 games in my
collection. As a kid, I had around 20 at the most.

Don't get me wrong. I'm not suggesting games were worth this much
back then, but it's what we had. There's games I've got that
aren't worth a dime. The Adventures of Dino Rikki comes to mind.
What a piece of trash! Still, it cost a fortune and I had no way
of knowing if it was going to be terrible. Maybe a friend had it
and could warn me. Maybe it would get a mention in Nintendo Power
magazine. Otherwise, you're shopping by box art.

That was until the video rental stores got in on the action. It
was a brilliant outgrowth from home video. For a dollar or two you
could take home a game for a few days. Sure, you weren't likely to
master it or beat it, and your save game was gone when it was
returned. Even so, what an incredible tool to avoid wasting big
money on flops.

I vividly remember renting Life Force [0] from the Video Stop.
What a brilliant game that was. I loved the gameplay and the
sprites. There was one that looked like an uncooked chicken
crawling on the ground. Awesome. I believe that eventually many of
those sprites, sound effects, and much of the gameplay code would
get revisited in The Guardian Legend, my favorite NES game of all
time.

[0] Life Force
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dt-pMJiQTTk

That rental was awesome and eventually I'd get my own copy of the
game. Others... well [1], I own some of those anyway.

[1] Not so awesome NES games
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2KgwO0N6e8U

I don't really have a big reason for sharing this. It just came to
my mind and was worth a smile. Hope it gave you one too.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>All Summer In A Day</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200324-all-summer-in-a-day/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
All Summer in a Day
March 24th, 2020
----------------------------------------

When I was a child my dad recorded an eclectic collection of TV
movies for me onto a very low quality VHS. I'm fairly convinced he
had no idea what the stories were about but they probably said
they were for kids and that was good enough for him. For me, it
was a warm blanket of comfort. I adored every single thing on that
tape and watched them over and over. My sister, three years older
than me, couldn't stand any of them and would leave me alone.

Years later the VHS tape surfaced when I was in college. My friend
and roomate at the time looked at this odd assortment of titles
written on masking tape and asked about it. "Hold onto your butt!"
I probably yelled and looked all over creation for a VCR.

We sat there, two guys in their twenties, watching this mad
collection of cinematic excellence and I'll never forget his
reaction.

"This tape explains ALL of you."

So what was on it? Allow me to give you the highlights:

It opened with a powerhouse. One of the most beautiful and
heart-wrenching stories ever. Ray Bradbury's "All Summer in
a Day".

All Summer in a Day (Video)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iz05RhA9Cyw
All Summer in a Day (Short story)
    http://staff.esuhsd.org/danielle/english%20department%20lvillage/rt/short%20stories/all%20summer%20in%20a%20day.pdf

If you've never seen or read the story, I can't tell you honestly
which to look at first. The short story is powerful, but the video
really nails the drama. The only downside, which I did not
remember from childhood, is the absolutely horrible score.

As an interesting side-note, I ended up ripping the video of my
VHS tape and creating a chapterized DVD from it. I made fake
artwork for the case and printed 5 copies. A friend working at the
Franklin Indiana Public Library tagged them and snuck them onto
the shelves there. If anyone is in the Franklin Indiana area, have
a look and see if you can find a copy!

**** SPOILERS ****

This story profoundly affected my own appreciation for sorrow and
tragedy. This was just strong enough for the child I was to feel
it deeply and empathise with Margot. I was in the closet with her
in darkness. It's hard to put into words what that did to me.

**** END SPOILERS ****

The next video on the tap was a TV adaptation of the 1977
children's book by Daniel and Jill Pinkwater: The Hoboken Chicken
Emergency. The plot as described on Wikipedia:

    The main character, Arthur, is asked to pick up a reserved
    turkey for Thanksgiving dinner, but the market has lost the
    reservation, and no store in the area has any turkeys or other
    birds available for purchase. So Arthur finds and brings home
    a 266-pound chicken named Henrietta. The family welcomes her
    with open arms, but the neighbors are not so sure. Everyone in
    town is horrified after Henrietta escapes.

As you can imagine, it's pure ridiculousness. The video format,
made in the early 80s, is really bad. The giant chicken costume,
the acting, all of it. 

The Hoboken Chicken Emergency (Video)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hGe3Eh6zKTQ


Following that was a harrowing tale of kidnapping and escape.
That's right, I'm talking about that oh-so-famous TV movie, 
Run Rebecca Run! Synopsis:

    Simone Buchanan plays a young camera fanatic who is marooned
    on a desert island. Here she is threatened by a refugee from
    South America (Henri Szeps) who isn't keen on having his
    whereabouts known. Hostility melts into friendship before the
    rescue boats arrive.

That's kind of a lame way of putting it. The dude is a fugitive
and he decides to hold her captive so she can't give away his
location. She tries to escape, and there's a bird, and stuff.
I really wish I could explain it more, or link you to the actual
video, but this one doesn't seem to be online at present. The best
I can do is this trailer.

Run Rebecca Run (Trailer)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vW8sljNvZxI

I guess I could point to this one for some of my outdoors-y stuff,
or maybe for my penchant for being a recluse and doing crimes. I
dunno.

And that brings us to the clean-up position on the tape. The #1
biggest hit for me was The Boy Who Loved Trolls, with its all-star
cast including Sam Waterston and William H. Macy, and the dad from
Alf! This one is on Youtube in Parts and it's so worth your time:

The Boy Who Loved Trolls
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hwJoKVDtA0Q

When the parents go away the secret magic of the world is revealed
to a dreamy-eyed kid. He journeys on adventures, meets some crazy
cool characters (including a mermaid and a turtle!) and saves time
itself. My fastination with the fantasy genre definitely comes
from this thing, in all its flaws.

There were more things on the tape, but you get the idea. It was
really substantial to my emerging identity and I'm appreciative.

Do you have anything like that? Books, movies? A horrible drive
you took with the family every year that scarred you for life?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Floor Of Mecca Is White</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200319-the-floor-of-mecca-is-white/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Floor of Mecca is White
March 19th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I saw a picture of Mecca today, and specifically the space
surrounding the Ka'bah at the center. It was empty. Not a single
soul praying, doing their seven circles or otherwise fulfilling
the hajj. It was eerie. It was also white.

The floor, specifically, is a bright white. I guess I've never
noticed, or never seen it clearly. It's always covered in people.
Perhaps it was obvious to others. It has lingered with me.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tls On Gopher Update</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200314-tls-on-gopher-update/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
TLS on gopher update
March 14th, 2020
----------------------------------------

jan [0] is working on adding TLS support to his gopher client,
ncgopher [1]. I am running gopher over tls on cosmic.voyage via
port 7070 [2]. I went to check on it this morning and saw it was
giving me a cert error.

I'm using stunnel4 to handle the TLS stuff, and then configuring
a second copy of gophernicus to serve up the goods. The whole
process is outlined in an old phlog here [3]. 

What I failed to take into account is that letsencrypt updates my
keys routinely, but stunnel doesn't reload them. It's as easy to
fix as: 

  $ sudo /etc/init.d/stunnel4 restart 

Now I need to think about how to automate that when letsencrypt
does its business. Hmmm... ahha!

/lib/systemd/system/certbot.service:

  ExecStart=/usr/bin/certbot -q renew \
    --post-hook "/etc/init.d/stunnel4 restart"

[0] jan
    gopher://jan.bio/1
[1] ncgopher user guide
    gopher://jan.bio/1ncgopher
[2] cosmic on tls
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/
[3] gophernicus TLS howto
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-gophernicus-tls-howto
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fables</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200313-fables/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fables
March 13th, 2020
----------------------------------------

This week I finally got off my bum and contributed something to
the excellent project over at tilde.tel [0]. This is a small
community run by cat [1] which is all about internet phone stuff.
I'm sure many of you gopherites know all about SIP and all that,
so if you want to join and play, he's the man to talk to.

[0] https://tilde.tel/
    https://tilde.tel/
[1] cat
    gopher://baud.baby/1/

So what did I contribute? I made a special phone extension (1969)
called Tilde.Tel Story Time. If you call it you'll get to listen
to me telling you a story. What sorts of stories you might ask?
Well, I'm starting off with Aesop's Fables. So far I've recorded
25 of them, all from the text on project gutenberg.

  Side note: the gopher front-end to project gutenberg seems to
  have exploded into little bits. I forget who was running that.
  Was it you jynx? Anyway, I'd love to link to it again, if that
  gets patched up.

Since some of you aren't internet phone people, and because I'd
hate to lose all the work, I've also archived the stories here on
gopher.black. You can find them over at Story Time [2].

[2] Story Time
    gopher://gopher.black/1/storytime

If you listened to Choose Your Own Adventure [3] on anonradio,
then you know I'm far, far removed from a professional voice guy.
(I have a lisp and stuff) I did clean up the audio a tiny bit, but
I figured it was meant to be heard over phone lines so it is what
it is. I hope you enjoy the recordings. I'll continue to add to
the collection over time.

[3] Choose Your Own Adventure (anonradio)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/cyoa
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Effects Of Deleting A Social Medium</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200306-the-effects-of-deleting-a-social-medium/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The effects of deleting a social medium
March 06th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I recently removed the Instagram app from my phone. (pause for
applause).

This is not a statement about the evils of social media, or the
objectification of ketogenic foods, or whatever else you might be
guessing. It's about time.

I removed the app because of the little magnifying-glass button
next to the home feed. There was a tendency for me to fill my time
by looking at random pictures Instagram thought relevant to me.
This was really easy for their algorithm to game and optimize.
Very quickly I had an endless scroll of "neat" stuff, and that was
sucking up way too much of my time without any tangible reward.

I like my own instagram feed. Seeing photos from friends and
places that interest me is cool and relatively quick to consume.
I don't need to read much and I can "catch up" quickly in a linear
timeline. If there were a way to disable that little magnifier
icon the app would still be on my phone.

I've since started posting pictures on pixelfed [0]. There's not
much to that app except the posting of pictures, so the temptation
to check it at other times is gone. When I post something I give
the feed a quick scroll to see if anything new is there, and then
I'm done. Easy!

[0] pixelfed
    https://pixfed.com/jamestomasino

Even so, in the days following the Instagram change I went through
the usual withdrawl. I ended up closing and opening mastodon again
several times in a row as my hands tried to fill the habit with
the available tools. Now several days in I'm no longer in that
habitual loop and I've begun reclaiming my time [1].

[1] Reclaiming my time
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqCZzs7UXIo

The first effect is my improved patience with long-form content.
I've been catching up on phlogs & blogs (RSS) more readily. That
was unexpected but appreciated. It makes me wonder about the
implications too. If cutting out one small habit that involved
short attention-span cycling has such a major effect on my overall
patience, how crippled is my current state? If I cut out Mastodon
and even IRC, would that attention continue to grow? How fast?
This might warrant some experimentation.

Another effect is a diminishing of the value of my phone.
I haven't ceased using it and there are plenty of other apps that
hold my attention for lengthy periods. Still, the change has been
tangible. Again, further experimentation is needed.

I know this community is filled with folks who have gone through
similar changes. What's your experience with cutting out a social
platform? Has it remained cut out? Do you still see the tangibles
in your life, or did those fade to some sort of "rest state"? Were
there notable negatives?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
