<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Out Of The Past</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200430-out-of-the-past/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Out of the past
April 30th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I adored this band when I was a teen. They were local and played
mostly in bookstores and small venues or the occasional folk
festival. I would see them as much as possible, listened to their
music around the clock... you get it.

Well, 20+ years later, the keyboardist and main songwriter was
stuck at home due to covid-19. He sat at his piano and started
playing a song that he'd forgotten all about. It was from the time
leading up to their second indy album but the feel wasn't right
for that collection. Much later on he thought he'd lost all traces
of it: gone from memory and never recorded. Here we was, just
barely remembering the tune.

Then serendipity struck. Today he dusted off an old, ancient iPod
and plugged it in. Amazingly it still worked. He put it on shuffle
with his collection of thousands of songs when what should start
coming through his speakers but the very mystery song he'd lost.

Sometime in the mid-nineties he had put together a demo track with
just him and the lead singer. One take, no practice. It had been
mis-labeled as a different track ("More to This") and tossed into
a collection and forgotten.

Today it speaks across time not just to him, but to all of us who
loved that music and the band, and to everyone who spends the time
to listen. I can't even put into words how much it means to me.

Story to Tell (Soundcloud)
    https://soundcloud.com/dwayne-keith-kessel/itunesexport-m4a/s-Zq9n0kPcDms
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Renting A Video Game</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200429-renting-a-video-game/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Renting a video game
April 29th, 2020
----------------------------------------

Nostalgia struck. I'm back in a childhood home giddy with
excitement over the Nintendo Entertainment System which stealthily
arrived as the last present opened at Christmas. My parents sprung
for the unit that came with two game cartridges, not just one:
Super Mario Bros. & Duck Hunt on one cartridge, and Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles on the other. It's visceral. I can smell the box.
Feel the plastic.

Games then were expensive. I suppose they're still expensive, but
I don't buy so many. A game like Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles cost
about $50 in the late 80s. With some napkin math, that's around
$80-85 today. Pricey, as I said. We didn't get new ones often.
Years--and many garage sales--later, I have 57 games in my
collection. As a kid, I had around 20 at the most.

Don't get me wrong. I'm not suggesting games were worth this much
back then, but it's what we had. There's games I've got that
aren't worth a dime. The Adventures of Dino Rikki comes to mind.
What a piece of trash! Still, it cost a fortune and I had no way
of knowing if it was going to be terrible. Maybe a friend had it
and could warn me. Maybe it would get a mention in Nintendo Power
magazine. Otherwise, you're shopping by box art.

That was until the video rental stores got in on the action. It
was a brilliant outgrowth from home video. For a dollar or two you
could take home a game for a few days. Sure, you weren't likely to
master it or beat it, and your save game was gone when it was
returned. Even so, what an incredible tool to avoid wasting big
money on flops.

I vividly remember renting Life Force [0] from the Video Stop.
What a brilliant game that was. I loved the gameplay and the
sprites. There was one that looked like an uncooked chicken
crawling on the ground. Awesome. I believe that eventually many of
those sprites, sound effects, and much of the gameplay code would
get revisited in The Guardian Legend, my favorite NES game of all
time.

[0] Life Force
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dt-pMJiQTTk

That rental was awesome and eventually I'd get my own copy of the
game. Others... well [1], I own some of those anyway.

[1] Not so awesome NES games
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2KgwO0N6e8U

I don't really have a big reason for sharing this. It just came to
my mind and was worth a smile. Hope it gave you one too.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>All Summer In A Day</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200324-all-summer-in-a-day/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
All Summer in a Day
March 24th, 2020
----------------------------------------

When I was a child my dad recorded an eclectic collection of TV
movies for me onto a very low quality VHS. I'm fairly convinced he
had no idea what the stories were about but they probably said
they were for kids and that was good enough for him. For me, it
was a warm blanket of comfort. I adored every single thing on that
tape and watched them over and over. My sister, three years older
than me, couldn't stand any of them and would leave me alone.

Years later the VHS tape surfaced when I was in college. My friend
and roomate at the time looked at this odd assortment of titles
written on masking tape and asked about it. "Hold onto your butt!"
I probably yelled and looked all over creation for a VCR.

We sat there, two guys in their twenties, watching this mad
collection of cinematic excellence and I'll never forget his
reaction.

"This tape explains ALL of you."

So what was on it? Allow me to give you the highlights:

It opened with a powerhouse. One of the most beautiful and
heart-wrenching stories ever. Ray Bradbury's "All Summer in
a Day".

All Summer in a Day (Video)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iz05RhA9Cyw
All Summer in a Day (Short story)
    http://staff.esuhsd.org/danielle/english%20department%20lvillage/rt/short%20stories/all%20summer%20in%20a%20day.pdf

If you've never seen or read the story, I can't tell you honestly
which to look at first. The short story is powerful, but the video
really nails the drama. The only downside, which I did not
remember from childhood, is the absolutely horrible score.

As an interesting side-note, I ended up ripping the video of my
VHS tape and creating a chapterized DVD from it. I made fake
artwork for the case and printed 5 copies. A friend working at the
Franklin Indiana Public Library tagged them and snuck them onto
the shelves there. If anyone is in the Franklin Indiana area, have
a look and see if you can find a copy!

**** SPOILERS ****

This story profoundly affected my own appreciation for sorrow and
tragedy. This was just strong enough for the child I was to feel
it deeply and empathise with Margot. I was in the closet with her
in darkness. It's hard to put into words what that did to me.

**** END SPOILERS ****

The next video on the tap was a TV adaptation of the 1977
children's book by Daniel and Jill Pinkwater: The Hoboken Chicken
Emergency. The plot as described on Wikipedia:

    The main character, Arthur, is asked to pick up a reserved
    turkey for Thanksgiving dinner, but the market has lost the
    reservation, and no store in the area has any turkeys or other
    birds available for purchase. So Arthur finds and brings home
    a 266-pound chicken named Henrietta. The family welcomes her
    with open arms, but the neighbors are not so sure. Everyone in
    town is horrified after Henrietta escapes.

As you can imagine, it's pure ridiculousness. The video format,
made in the early 80s, is really bad. The giant chicken costume,
the acting, all of it. 

The Hoboken Chicken Emergency (Video)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hGe3Eh6zKTQ


Following that was a harrowing tale of kidnapping and escape.
That's right, I'm talking about that oh-so-famous TV movie, 
Run Rebecca Run! Synopsis:

    Simone Buchanan plays a young camera fanatic who is marooned
    on a desert island. Here she is threatened by a refugee from
    South America (Henri Szeps) who isn't keen on having his
    whereabouts known. Hostility melts into friendship before the
    rescue boats arrive.

That's kind of a lame way of putting it. The dude is a fugitive
and he decides to hold her captive so she can't give away his
location. She tries to escape, and there's a bird, and stuff.
I really wish I could explain it more, or link you to the actual
video, but this one doesn't seem to be online at present. The best
I can do is this trailer.

Run Rebecca Run (Trailer)
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vW8sljNvZxI

I guess I could point to this one for some of my outdoors-y stuff,
or maybe for my penchant for being a recluse and doing crimes. I
dunno.

And that brings us to the clean-up position on the tape. The #1
biggest hit for me was The Boy Who Loved Trolls, with its all-star
cast including Sam Waterston and William H. Macy, and the dad from
Alf! This one is on Youtube in Parts and it's so worth your time:

The Boy Who Loved Trolls
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hwJoKVDtA0Q

When the parents go away the secret magic of the world is revealed
to a dreamy-eyed kid. He journeys on adventures, meets some crazy
cool characters (including a mermaid and a turtle!) and saves time
itself. My fastination with the fantasy genre definitely comes
from this thing, in all its flaws.

There were more things on the tape, but you get the idea. It was
really substantial to my emerging identity and I'm appreciative.

Do you have anything like that? Books, movies? A horrible drive
you took with the family every year that scarred you for life?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Floor Of Mecca Is White</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200319-the-floor-of-mecca-is-white/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The Floor of Mecca is White
March 19th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I saw a picture of Mecca today, and specifically the space
surrounding the Ka'bah at the center. It was empty. Not a single
soul praying, doing their seven circles or otherwise fulfilling
the hajj. It was eerie. It was also white.

The floor, specifically, is a bright white. I guess I've never
noticed, or never seen it clearly. It's always covered in people.
Perhaps it was obvious to others. It has lingered with me.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Tls On Gopher Update</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200314-tls-on-gopher-update/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
TLS on gopher update
March 14th, 2020
----------------------------------------

jan [0] is working on adding TLS support to his gopher client,
ncgopher [1]. I am running gopher over tls on cosmic.voyage via
port 7070 [2]. I went to check on it this morning and saw it was
giving me a cert error.

I'm using stunnel4 to handle the TLS stuff, and then configuring
a second copy of gophernicus to serve up the goods. The whole
process is outlined in an old phlog here [3]. 

What I failed to take into account is that letsencrypt updates my
keys routinely, but stunnel doesn't reload them. It's as easy to
fix as: 

  $ sudo /etc/init.d/stunnel4 restart 

Now I need to think about how to automate that when letsencrypt
does its business. Hmmm... ahha!

/lib/systemd/system/certbot.service:

  ExecStart=/usr/bin/certbot -q renew \
    --post-hook "/etc/init.d/stunnel4 restart"

[0] jan
    gopher://jan.bio/1
[1] ncgopher user guide
    gopher://jan.bio/1ncgopher
[2] cosmic on tls
    gopher://cosmic.voyage/1/
[3] gophernicus TLS howto
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-gophernicus-tls-howto
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fables</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200313-fables/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Fables
March 13th, 2020
----------------------------------------

This week I finally got off my bum and contributed something to
the excellent project over at tilde.tel [0]. This is a small
community run by cat [1] which is all about internet phone stuff.
I'm sure many of you gopherites know all about SIP and all that,
so if you want to join and play, he's the man to talk to.

[0] https://tilde.tel/
    https://tilde.tel/
[1] cat
    gopher://baud.baby/1/

So what did I contribute? I made a special phone extension (1969)
called Tilde.Tel Story Time. If you call it you'll get to listen
to me telling you a story. What sorts of stories you might ask?
Well, I'm starting off with Aesop's Fables. So far I've recorded
25 of them, all from the text on project gutenberg.

  Side note: the gopher front-end to project gutenberg seems to
  have exploded into little bits. I forget who was running that.
  Was it you jynx? Anyway, I'd love to link to it again, if that
  gets patched up.

Since some of you aren't internet phone people, and because I'd
hate to lose all the work, I've also archived the stories here on
gopher.black. You can find them over at Story Time [2].

[2] Story Time
    gopher://gopher.black/1/storytime

If you listened to Choose Your Own Adventure [3] on anonradio,
then you know I'm far, far removed from a professional voice guy.
(I have a lisp and stuff) I did clean up the audio a tiny bit, but
I figured it was meant to be heard over phone lines so it is what
it is. I hope you enjoy the recordings. I'll continue to add to
the collection over time.

[3] Choose Your Own Adventure (anonradio)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/cyoa
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Effects Of Deleting A Social Medium</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200306-the-effects-of-deleting-a-social-medium/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The effects of deleting a social medium
March 06th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I recently removed the Instagram app from my phone. (pause for
applause).

This is not a statement about the evils of social media, or the
objectification of ketogenic foods, or whatever else you might be
guessing. It's about time.

I removed the app because of the little magnifying-glass button
next to the home feed. There was a tendency for me to fill my time
by looking at random pictures Instagram thought relevant to me.
This was really easy for their algorithm to game and optimize.
Very quickly I had an endless scroll of "neat" stuff, and that was
sucking up way too much of my time without any tangible reward.

I like my own instagram feed. Seeing photos from friends and
places that interest me is cool and relatively quick to consume.
I don't need to read much and I can "catch up" quickly in a linear
timeline. If there were a way to disable that little magnifier
icon the app would still be on my phone.

I've since started posting pictures on pixelfed [0]. There's not
much to that app except the posting of pictures, so the temptation
to check it at other times is gone. When I post something I give
the feed a quick scroll to see if anything new is there, and then
I'm done. Easy!

[0] pixelfed
    https://pixfed.com/jamestomasino

Even so, in the days following the Instagram change I went through
the usual withdrawl. I ended up closing and opening mastodon again
several times in a row as my hands tried to fill the habit with
the available tools. Now several days in I'm no longer in that
habitual loop and I've begun reclaiming my time [1].

[1] Reclaiming my time
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqCZzs7UXIo

The first effect is my improved patience with long-form content.
I've been catching up on phlogs & blogs (RSS) more readily. That
was unexpected but appreciated. It makes me wonder about the
implications too. If cutting out one small habit that involved
short attention-span cycling has such a major effect on my overall
patience, how crippled is my current state? If I cut out Mastodon
and even IRC, would that attention continue to grow? How fast?
This might warrant some experimentation.

Another effect is a diminishing of the value of my phone.
I haven't ceased using it and there are plenty of other apps that
hold my attention for lengthy periods. Still, the change has been
tangible. Again, further experimentation is needed.

I know this community is filled with folks who have gone through
similar changes. What's your experience with cutting out a social
platform? Has it remained cut out? Do you still see the tangibles
in your life, or did those fade to some sort of "rest state"? Were
there notable negatives?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Smolderingwizard Roll Vs Roleplaying</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200306-re-smolderingwizard-roll-vs-roleplaying/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: smolderingwizard - roll vs roleplaying
March 06th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I just read a really interesting observational phlog post from
smolderingwizard [0] on his experiences in a 5th edition D&D game.
He describes everything in 5th edition coming down to a mechanic
role and that those rolls are happening constantly and distracting
from the game.

[0] smolderingwizard - roll vs role-playing
    gopher://gopher.smolderingwizard.com/0/phlog/2020-03-05-roll-vs-role-5e-vs-old-school.md

I've run into this in some games as well and feel it's ultimately
the fault of the DM/GM, though I can't judge them harshly for it.
Running a game is hard work and it's not a skill that's usually
taught. People learn in their own way, from playing with others
and emulating good GMs, or watching games online, or just doing
their best to guess their way through. 

One big influence these days is computer gaming. It's had immense
impact on tabletop RPGs over the years, going so far as to
completely screw up D&D into the mess that was 4th edition AKA
World of Warcraft on paper. But even in the early days of say, 2nd
edition, there were books and books describing mechanics that you
could turn into rolls. I remember one guidebook describing the
fall-off rate of light from various sized campfires and the impact
for low-light vision at each distance in a grid. It got silly.

But those books didn't come from a vacuum. People wanted that in
their games. There's always been a subset of gamers who want the
mechanics to rule the action. Sometimes these are reflected in
power-gaming, or just optimized buildes. Sometimes it's just
a style of play that the group enjoys.

I cannot put myself in that camp, personally. My most formative
long-term RPG was played 1-on-1 with my DM in high school. It was
a solo game and we rolled almost never. The entire game was
role-play and that has had enormous impact on my own style.

In the Fate Core System book, the game designers have this to say:

  When to Roll Dice

  Roll the dice when succeeding or failing at the action could
  each contribute something interesting to the game...

  The worst, WORST thing you can do is have a failed roll that
  means NOTHING HAPPENS--no new knowledge, no new course of action
  to take, and no change in the situation. This is totally
  boring...

  If you can't imagine an interesting outcome from both results,
  then don't call for that roll. If failure is the uninteresting
  option, just give the PCs what thy want and call for a roll
  later, when you CAN think of an interesting failure. If success
  is the boring option, then see if you can turn your idea for
  failure into [a motivation for the PC to role play their
  character that way]. 

In combat things are simple. You failed a roll or you succeed at
it have immediate consequences. If you're rolling as you walk down
a hallway, what happens if you fail? You triggered a trap? But
what if you succeed? Did you just notice the trap? That's boring
because it doesn't change anything. What if the success meant you
spotted a trap that was about to affect the party behind you. Your
quick action let you spring up and grab a counterweight. Now you
have to hold it in place so the others can get across. The
challenge has changed the dynamic of the action and given the
party a reason to interact with one another. Is your character
strong enough to hold it for the whole party? What if you this
splits you up? What if you have to choose who to drop it on before
you're pulled inside the mechanism?

Anyway, I digress. Chat with your DM and talk about the rolls. Or
talk about it with the whole group. Are they into it? Maybe so.
Maybe they're just waiting for the topic to come up.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mike Tyson S Punch Out</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200223-mike-tyson-s-punch-out/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Mike Tyson's Punch-Out
February 23rd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Years ago there was a series of videos on youtube that outlined
the deep, deep secrets and strategies of Mike Tyson's Punch-Out in
exquisite detail. The series was quite long, if memory serves.
Perhaps 10 or 12 videos in all. I remember it from the late 2000s
but it seems to have vanished from the internet completely.

In the first of the videos the author explained some of the
fundamentals. These are things we take for granted about the game
that are so basic they set up the mind for later revelations. The
first can be demonstrated by a very basic question: which punch
does more damage, left or right? Do you know? Do you think you
have an answer? Or did you, like most people, just punch whichever
was convenient and then alternate away? Would you be surprised to
learn that there is an actual benefit for choosing one over the
other. There is indeed, and it depends upon which direction your
opponent attacked from last.

The sequence of punching, whether to stay on left or right for
a series or to alternate, also changes depending on a number of
cues that are all right there in the game. There's so much at
work, such rich programming and strategy, that it's unfathomable
that it's escaped notice for so long.

What else can I tell you about? The various techniques to gain
stars, the methods of using those stars that results in opponent
reactions you've never even seen. Seriously, there's like 10
videos worth of gold that was out there!

But now it's gone. Poof. I've looked a bunch of times without any
luck. The author pulled the videos down and vanished long ago and
no manner of sleuthing has uncovered a crumb.

It's contrary to the idea we're normally presented with that once
something is on the internet it's there forever. We gopher
dwellers know the truth, though. This is all vapour and fleeting.
How much of the web was purely in Flash and completely
inaccessible now? How much was never archived in the wayback, or
was behind a login? My own earliest websites are gone. And that's
just the web! How much of gopherspace is lost to us? These
protocols, around in force since the mid 90s only, 25-30 years of
content that seems at once like everything that has ever been, and
also a flash in the pan. How long until the next technological
upheaval closes another door to our past? How long until all of
this is fleeting memory?

We are better at archiving than many here in our burrows. It's
mostly plain text, after all, and easily stored. But it's also
difficult to index, and links vanish without a clue as to where
those backup treasure troves might be. If we lose a few
cornerstones like Cameron's Floodgap, or SDF, how much goes with
it?

Anyway, I guess what I'm saying is... have any of you seen the
Punch-Out videos? I really want to watch them again.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Green Energy In Iceland</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200218-green-energy-in-iceland/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Green Energy in Iceland
February 18th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I don't complain about many things in Iceland because, frankly,
there aren't a whole lot of things to complain about. By almost
every measure, life here is superior to the United States. In
fact, the thing I'm about to complain about in this phlog is
nitpicking. The situation in the United States is worse, frankly.

What I'm talking about in green power, or carbon neutral power, or
sustainable energy, or whatever else you want to call it. You may
be aware that Iceland's grid is pretty much 100% renewable energy.
Put a period there at the end of that sentence and things feel
pretty damn good. The island has rich resources in terms of
hydroelectric power, geothermal power, and wind. You can read all
about it on this site [0].

Why Iceland - Competitively Priced Green Energy
    https://www.invest.is/why-iceland/competitively-priced-green-energy

So what's the problem then? Two things. I'll call one the lesser
evil and the other one the great lie.


The Lesser Evil

Power distribution in Iceland is not balanced between individuals
and corporations. The rates are different, their power channels
are different, and their use and the care with which is is taken
is different. In short, companies can get away with some shady
stuff. 

Is it as bad as the US? Oh hell no. After all, we're not dumping
toxic coal ash into major waterways or anything [1] here. 

Duke Energy Coal Ash in North Carolina
    https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article238898708.html

Even so, there's some ecological impact at stake, and a misuse or
unbalanced use of public resources that favors large capitalist
enterprise without paying back into the local economy. I could go
into more detail here, but I'm just gonna leave it vague because
I really want to focus on...


The Great Lie

Iceland sells its green resources as credits that companies can
pay for to offset their own polluting behavior. If a shitty
polluter like Duke Energy wants to seem cleaner, they can pay
Iceland and claim the renewable energy as their own despite not
using it. This lowers Iceland's real contribution to the Earth in
a major way, all but removing it as a good from the world because
it allows these other companies to continue their damage while
claiming to be better.

It's a short term gain for a country that was recently in
a financial crisis. What a great way to bring in extra funds for
doing nothing, right? Except it does have a major cost to the
world as a whole.

Is this worse than what the US is doing? Well, no. The US is
actively polluting and subsidising fossil fuel industries. But
that doesn't give Iceland a pass. This country has pinned its
reputation in the world as a Green Nation while it makes back-room
deals to sell off the fruits of that labor at the cost of our
future. There are many MPs here who are working on this and
a number of other issues. Fundamental to all of these efforts is
the new constitution that was passed by public referendum years
ago but has not been ratified by the alþingi, our parliament. It's
a powerful document that returns natural resources to the public
and out of the hands of a small number of oligarchs. You can see
why it hasn't happened yet right there.

The people all want it. Many MPs want it. It will happen. These
petty corruptions that take advantage of the fisheries, of the
power systems, of plundering the Namibian fishing quotas [2], they
will all be outed. We'll get there.

Icelandic Fishing Company Engaged In Bribery, Tax Evasion, Plundering African Resources
    https://grapevine.is/news/2019/11/13/icelandic-fishing-company-engaged-in-bribery-tax-evasion-plundering-african-resources/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
