<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Lxd</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190128-lxd/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
lxd
January 28th, 2019
----------------------------------------

lxd and lxc are amazing. If you know what they are, skip this
paragraph. If not, they're sort of like Docker, but instead of
encapsulating your application, they encapsulate a system. They're
not as broad as a whole VM, and in reality they're not really
a "thing" at all. They're a collection of isolation tools built
into Linux that makes it seem like you're running on a whole new
vm while sharing kernels and junk. Um, go read about it somewhere
else. There's some great material out there that will explain it
better than me.

The purpose if this phlog is to document my basic LXD setup. My
host system is Ubuntu 18.04 as of this article being written, but
it really doesn't matter. Most of my containers are built using
the latest stable Ubuntu, but that also doesn't really matter. My
goals are as follows:

- Be able to create and dispose of containers easily
- All containers, by default, allow me to ssh in using my keys
- I can ssh to the containers by their container name, not IP
- I can apply a 'gui' profile and make a container work with my
  native display
- I can apply a 'user' profile and make my container start with my
  dotfiles installed

Step 1: Install LXD

If it's not already installed, you can grab the snap package.


Step 2: Install ZFS

It's not necessary, but it performs better at start/stop
operations. If you install it, LXD will use it as the default.

Step 3: Configure LXD

$ sudo lxd init

Just say yes to the defaults.

Step 4: Edit the default profile

$ lxc profile edit default

  config:
    user.vendor-data: |
      #cloud-config
      package_upgrade: true
      packages:
        - build-essential
        - software-properties-common
      users:
        - name: ubuntu
          ssh-import-id: gh:jamestomasino
          shell: /bin/bash
  description: Default LXD profile
  devices:
    eth0:
      name: eth0
      nictype: bridged
      parent: lxdbr0
      type: nic
    root:
      path: /
      pool: zfs
      type: disk
  name: default
  used_by: []

The key here is the ssh-import-id to pull my keys down from
github. With that I can ssh in immediately instead of using the
lxc exec method to sudo in.

Step 5: Edit the gui profile

If you didn't install lxd via snap, you'll need to run this one liner:

$ echo "root:$UID:1" | sudo tee -a /etc/subuid /etc/subgid

  config:
    environment.DISPLAY: :0
    raw.idmap: both 1000 1000
    user.user-data: |
      #cloud-config
      runcmd:
        - 'sed -i "s/; enable-shm = yes/enable-shm = no/g" /etc/pulse/client.conf'
        - 'echo export PULSE_SERVER=unix:/tmp/.pulse-native | tee --append /home/ubuntu/.profile'
      packages:
        - x11-apps
        - mesa-utils
        - pulseaudio
  description: GUI LXD profile
  devices:
    PASocket:
      path: /tmp/.pulse-native
      source: /run/user/1000/pulse/native
      type: disk
    X0:
      path: /tmp/.X11-unix/X0
      source: /tmp/.X11-unix/X0
      type: disk
    mygpu:
      type: gpu
  name: gui
  used_by: []

This magic sauce will set up all the dependencies needed to
connect to my display when a gui app is run. I then SSH in with
export x11 enabled and all is well.

Step 6: Edit a user profile

This one involves a lot of runcmd: stuff in a row that points to
my dotfiles, installs other apt packages, does a little dance, and
ends up with a working environment for me to do some damage. I'll
spare you all.

Step 7: SSH

I want to be able to connect to lxd containers by name, not just
IP address. I'm going to set that bit up in a minute using dnsmasq
and systemd, but first lets look at my ~/.ssh/config to see what
goodness lies within:

Host *.lxd
StrictHostKeyChecking no
UserKnownHostsFile /dev/null
LogLevel QUIET
ForwardX11 yes
ForwardX11Trusted yes
User ubuntu
IdentityFile ~/some/really/cool/path/to/SECRETS

The host checking and host file bit, along with LogLevel mean you
won't get man-in-the-middle warnings if your container IP changes
one day from starting and stoping repeatedly. X11 forwarding there
for display. I use ubuntu containers, so I've attached the
username there as well.

Step 8: DNS

$ sudo vim /usr/local/bin/lxdhostdns_start.sh

  #!/bin/sh

  LXDINTERFACE=lxdbr0
  LXDDOMAIN=lxd
  LXDDNSIP=$(ip addr show lxdbr0 | grep -Po 'inet \K[\d.]+')

  /usr/bin/systemd-resolve --interface ${LXDINTERFACE} \
                           --set-dns "${LXDDNSIP}" \
                           --set-domain ${LXDDOMAIN}


$ sudo vim /usr/local/bin/lxdhostdns_stop.sh

  #!/bin/sh

  LXDINTERFACE=lxdbr0

  /usr/bin/systemd-resolve --interface ${LXDINTERFACE} --revert


$ sudo vim /lib/systemd/system/lxd-host-dns.service

  [Unit]
  Description=LXD host DNS service
  After=multi-user.target

  [Service]
  Type=simple
  ExecStart=/usr/local/bin/lxdhostdns_start.sh
  RemainAfterExit=true
  ExecStop=/usr/local/bin/lxdhostdns_stop.sh
  StandardOutput=journal

  [Install]
  WantedBy=multi-user.target

$ sudo systemctl daemon-reload
$ sudo systemctl enable lxd-host-dns.service
$ sudo systemctl start lxd-host-dns.service

Boom. If you didn't answer defaults on lxd init, then your
interface might not be lxdbr0 and you'll need to change stuff.

Step 9: Test it out

$ lxc launch ubuntu: test
$ lxc list # wait until you can see the IP to know it's ready
$ ssh test.lxd

If everything blew up it's because you're with me and that DNS
hackery works great to be able to ssh in, but it also breaks the
ability for your container to connect to anything else. For now
I'm disabling the DNS bit and sshing in via IP, or using the lxc
exec sudo stuff to connect. I'm watching this post [0] for
a comment response that will hopefully clarify that last bit.

[0] How to use lxd container hostnames on the host in Ubuntu 18.04
    http://blog.simos.info/how-to-use-lxd-container-hostnames-on-the-host-in-ubuntu-18-04/

!
-
*  Testing
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Free Speech</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190121-free-speech/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
free speech
January 21st, 2019
----------------------------------------

solderpunk, visiblink and yargo have a great thread going on the
topic of discrimination. Here's the most recent link to it, but
there's a history you can dig through [0].

[0] visiblink - Of nature, nurture, and dinosaurs
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~visiblink/phlog/20190120

In visiblink's first post on the topic the discussion began with
a comedian who repeatedly ridiculed a disabled child and a human
rights tribunal that then fined him for it. That's where I'd like
to focus my very narrow band of thought on the topic.

While the discussion that spawned has been interesting it has been
focused on what constitutes an appropriate topic of criticism. Is
it based on whether that factor is in full control of the
individual, is it related to their culture or wealth, and does
that play a factor in what is appropriate. Great stuff... go read.

The part that stuck out to me was the concept of free speech and
protected speech, their terminology, and the psychology involved
in each. Yargo, in a simplistic and unfair summary to him, stated
that he'd prefer to say whatever he likes without fear of legal
consequences. That's a great place to start.

There is some psychological system at play which places the idea
of protection on the individuals who are criticized, or who are
the subject of hate speech. Media discussions surround the idea of
sensitivity and others refer to "snowflakes". Protection is
demanded by the sensitive, or so it seems.

We know in reality that it is the speech which is the subject to
protection instead. It is not the targets of the speech, but the
speaker who needs focus here, right?

The distinction is minor because the relationship between the
speaker and target haven't changed. But that's not the whole
story, is it? If we use terms like "free speech" it hides part of
the story. When we say "protected speech" now we get at the crux.
Protected by whom, and from whom?

There are other parties involved: the speaker, the subject, and
the protective entity and the persecutive entity. So when we look
back at the discussion of protected speech now we can fit everyone
into context:

A speaker's (subject) speech toward someone (object) is
potentially protected (protector) from persecution (persecutor).

Who is the persecutor? In the case of the United States and the
1st amendment from which most of this discussion flows for
Americans it is the US government itself.

Who is the protector? Well, again in this case, the US government.

  Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of
  religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging
  the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the
  people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for
  a redress of grievances.

Congress is limited in their powers by the Constitution from
abridging the freedom of speech.

Done, right? libertarians have at it. Except, no. Oliver Wendell
Holmes comes knocking next...

In the landmark case of Schenck v. United States, Holmes stated, 

  The most stringent protection of free speech would not protect a
  man in falsely shouting fire in a theater and causing a panic

Okay, so all speech is does not warrant protection under the first
amendment. Where do we draw the line? Here we get into Public
Forum Regulation, Prior Restraint, Expressive Conduct, Defamation,
and so on. Most appropriate to our discussion is the topic of
defamation, and inciting, provocative, or offensive speech. 

Here we go to the courts to decide where the line should be. Did
that speech represent an individual freedom, or did it put at risk
the lives and liberty of others, such as by listing the home
addresses of families of abortion doctors? The line gets blurry,
right? We're not talking about feelings being hurt anymore. Our 
objects of discussion potentially got much more serious.

Back to my focus: the protector and persecutor are the same
entity, though perhaps different departments of it. That entity
is given the power to determine what it protects from itself.
That's pretty weird when you word it like that, but so be it.
What stands out though is that the justification for NOT
protecting speech is required based on the wording of the
constitution. The US government, at least, needs to justify a
decision to step in and persecute a speaker (at least to itself).

Where was I going with this? I don't remember. I tried writing
this at work and got interrupted every five minutes. I think I was
getting to something about the psychology of speech protection,
asking an outside entity to come in and protect you from itself in
some cases and not others. There was going to be a really cool
reference to 80s sitcoms in there too.

Meh, now I'm hungry and totally forgot where I was going. So, um,
thanks for sticking with me through the first half of a well
thought-out argument. Marsha will validate your parking on your
way out.

Cheers!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gophernicus Tls Howto</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-gophernicus-tls-howto/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gophernicus TLS howto
January 20th, 2019
----------------------------------------

A few people on mastodon requested a little guide on how to set up
stunnel4 with gophernicus to offer TLS. As you might know from my
earlier posts on gopher.black, I prefer to run this gopher server
as a tor service instead of using the TLS approach alone since it
does all the same things plus some extra goodies and doesn't
require modification to your gopher clients. Regardless, gopher
over TLS is cool in its own right (and I use it on cosmic.voyage).

Here's how:

1) Make sure you're using gophernicus and it's Kim's Prison
   Edition, not one of the ancient ones that shows up when you
   google gophernicus, like prologic's

2) Have an SSL cert. I use letsencrypt because why pay for
   something that's free?

3) Have stunnel4. I think it was an apt install for me.

Actually configuring everything is just a matter of tweaking
2 files:

1) /etc/default/gophernicus

OPTIONS="-o UTF-8 -nt -nh -nf -T 7070"

The important part for TLS is the last bit (-T PORT). The other
switches hide the /stats page which is a security issue, and get
rid of titles and footer and stuff, which make for a cleaner
rendered gophermap. They're cool settings, but not necessary for
TLS.

2) /etc/stunnel/gophernicus.conf

;
; Gophernicus behind Stunnel4 for gopher over TLS
;

; User/group for stunnel daemon
setuid = stunnel4
setgid = stunnel4

; PID file location
pid = /var/run/stunnel4/gophernicus.pid

; Log to file, not syslog
output = /var/log/stunnel4/gophernicus.log
syslog = no

; Certificate in pem format is needed for TLS
cert = /etc/letsencrypt/live/cosmic.voyage/fullchain.pem
key = /etc/letsencrypt/live/cosmic.voyage/privkey.pem

; Enable TCP wrappers
libwrap = yes
service = in.gophernicus-tls

; Gopher over TLS service
[gophernicus]
accept  = :::7070
connect = 127.0.0.1:70
protocol = proxy


So I'm pointing at my letsencrypt cert for cosmic in this file,
and I've chosen to use port 7070 for TLS. Kensanata says there's
an argument for port 7443 that was given on the gopher mailing
list, but I never read it. Use what makes sense to you, but make
sure it matches what you have in /etc/default/gophernicus.

And that's it. Oh, I guess you'll need to open up your port with
your firewall, but everything else should just work(TM).

Good luck!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cosmic Voyage Part 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190120-cosmic-voyage-part-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Cosmic Voyage - Part 1
January 20th, 2019
----------------------------------------

slackz [0] asked me to do some write-ups on cosmic.voyage from the
architect POV. Here's part 1 of who knows how many.
[0] slackz
    gopher://gopher.orghub.co/1/

If you don't know what cosmic.voyage is read this first [1]
[1] Cosmic Voyage
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181124-cosmic-voyage

Being a text-based writing adventure, and me being me,
I immediately set out to make Cosmic sit primarily on gopher
rather than web. At first I didn't plan to have a web presence for
it at all, but that changed as things went along. Really, my goals
and understanding of the system are ever-evolving and greatly
informed by the active users.

Regardless, things started with gopher. I knew I wanted a few
things right away:

- A single gopher structure, not individual user folders.
- Users to be able to fully control their ships and stories, but
  not mess with other users' things
- An ongoing log that linked everything together.

I use motsognir [2] on gopher.black, but I thought it might be
easier to write scripts as gophermaps for cosmic if I stuck with
gophernicus. I could have made things in cgi scripts, but I like
the transparent heirarchical structure I get to this way instead.
[2] motsognir
    gopher://gopher.viste.fr/1/projects/motsognir

The structure of cosmic's gopher hole looks like this:
  ├── gophermap
  ├── intro.gophermap
  ├── listing.gophermap
  ├── log
  │   ├── gophermap
  │   └── intro.gophermap
  ├── Melchizedek (or any old ship)
  │   ├── 001.txt
  │   ├── 002.txt
  │   ├── 003.txt
  ├── Melvin P Feltersnatch (another example ship)
  │   ├── 001.txt
  │   ├── 002.txt
  │   └── 003.txt
  ├── rss.xml
  └── ships
      ├── gophermap
      ├── Melchizedek (example ship page directory)
      │   └── gophermap -> /var/gopher/ships/ship/gophermap
      ├── Melvin P Feltersnatch (another example ship page dir)
      │   └── gophermap -> /var/gopher/ships/ship/gophermap
      ├── ship
      │   └── gophermap
      └── ships.gophermap

At the root level I have a gophermap that pulls in and processes
other gophermaps, does a little shell scripting, and displays the
basic content. Let's start by having a look at that code:

  =intro.gophermap
  1Complete Transmission Log /log
  1Ships, Colonies, Outposts /ships
  0RSS Feed /rss.xml

  Most recent (20) log entries: 
  =head -n 20 listing.gophermap | sed 's|^0||' | awk -v tot="$(wc -l listing.gophermap)" '{print 0 int(tot)-NR+1 " >> " $0}'

Gophernicus allows us to source in other gophermaps by using
saying =gophermapname. In this way I can keep my intro text for
cosmic in a separate file (which becomes helpful later when we
look at web generation). Following that I have a few regular
gophermap links using gophernicus' friendly shorthand syntax (no
servername or port required). Finally I list the most recent log
entries.

In this, I grab the top 20 lines from listing.gophermap and number
them properly.

listing.gophermap is the heart of the cosmic log system. Each time
a user adds a log to the site, it gets prepended to that file.
That file in turn generates the log page, the short listings here,
and content for the individual ship pages. It's a sensitive file
because it needs to be writable by all users on the system. I've
kicked around better ways to do that, but for now it seems to
work. At least I back it up regularly.

The /log/ page works very much like the root gophermap, but with
a simpler rendering.

  =intro.gophermap
  =sed 's|^0||' /var/gopher/listing.gophermap | awk -v tot="$(wc -l /var/gopher/listing.gophermap)" '{print 0 int(tot)-NR+1 " >> " $0'}  

Simple, right? awk is the best.

So what about the ship pages? Those are a little funkier. On the
one hand, they pretty much just sed/awk their way through the
listing.gophermap file as well, but there's also the matter of
a navigable directory.

From the list above you can see that there's a ships directory.
Lets look more closely at an example:
  └── ships
      ├── gophermap
      ├── Enterprise NCC-1701
      │   └── gophermap -> /var/gopher/ships/ship/gophermap
      ├── ship
      │   └── gophermap
      └── ships.gophermap

The root gophermap of the ships page does a little more hard work.
This has a few long lines that might not render well on your
screen. I apologize!:

  #!/bin/sh
  cat "ships.gophermap"
  find "/var/gopher/" -maxdepth 1 ! -path "/var/gopher/" ! -path "/var/gopher/ships" ! -path "/var/gopher/log" -type d -print | sed 's|/var/gopher/||' | sort | while read -r ship
  do
    entry_num=$(grep -c "^0${ship}" "/var/gopher/listing.gophermap")
    if [ "$entry_num" != "0" ]; then
      printf "1%s (%s)\\t/ships/%s\\n" "$ship" "$entry_num" "$ship"
    fi
  done

We start by catting out the intro for the ships page from
ships.gophermap, then we loop through all the ship directories on
the system. Using each of those ships, we then check against
listing.gophermap to see how many entries they have. If they don't
have any entries, we leave them out of the listings. That was
a nice idea from one of the cosmic users to avoid cluttering up
the ship page with empty ships. If there ARE entries, we print
a link to the ship page.

The ship pages themselves are a bit of trickery. There's really
only one ship page /ships/ship/gophermap. All the rest are just
symlinks to it. But how!!?? What manner of sorcery is this?

  #!/bin/sh

  ship="$(/bin/pwd -L | sed 's|.*/||')"
  desc="/var/gopher/${ship}/.description"
  if [ -f "$desc" ]; then
    cat "$desc"
    printf "\\n"
  fi

  printf "%s - Ship Log\\n" "$ship"
  tac "/var/gopher/listing.gophermap" | sed "s|^0||" | awk '{print 0 NR " >> " $0}' | grep "^.*>>\\ ${ship}" 

pwd -L gets the path of the current symlink, which reveals the
ship name! Then we look to see if there's a ship description and
finally we grab all the relevant logs from listings and number
everything.

Huzzah!

That's it. That's the whole gopher structure that drives Cosmic
Voyage. Next time I'll talk about the web generation and RSS
feeds.

If this inspired you to join the system, instructions can be found
on cosmic's home page. See you in the stars!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Little Free Library Part 3</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190115-little-free-library-part-3/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Little Free Library, part 3
January 15th, 2019
----------------------------------------

The batter test is complete. I picked up a solar powered battery
pack off Amazon and plugged in the pi, then left it in the dark to
see how long it took to drain. It lasted just over 80 hours with
no external charging. That's fantastic! 

The unit claims that it can fully recharge in about 7 hours of
sunlight. Given various seasons and overcast days, rain, etc, that
should be plenty of buffer to allow the pi to remain perpetually
active.

With that, there's only 3 things left to do:

- Update the captive portal screen to indicate to users that they
  should: 1) disable their mobile data, and 2) browse to
  http://littlefreelibrary.  The actual domain doesn't matter, but
  that one seems easy enough to remember. The mobile data thing
  came up in testing as a barrier to IP rules running on the Pi
  that would normally redirect you to 10.0.0.5 and serve the web
  content. Captive Portal may trigger, but I need a real redirect
  of a real mobile browser for downloads. If you're reading this
  and making a project that doesn't need javascript or downloads,
  just do it IN the captive portal. It's much easier.

- Build a weatherproof enclosure. The plan is to 3D print
  something that can hold the battery and pi, or just the pi glued
  on the battery, or a big glass box, or whatever. Something that
  will survive in the woods and not be blocked by snowfall.

- Take pictures and "blog" the full build instructions so others
  can replicate and share it. This is a cool project and I hope
  others can build upon it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Little Free Library Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190109-little-free-library-part-2/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Little Free Library, part 2
January 09th, 2019
----------------------------------------

I originally wrote part 1 of this build back in October [0] and
I have a few little things to add.

First, I want to call out a major hurdle I'm facing: Captive
Portal browsers don't allow users to download files. It's
a security thing. That's annoying for a library that's designed to
give you ebooks, but it might not be a barrier for your uses.
Someone on Mastodon mentioned making a video based thing, and that
should work just fine entirely in captive portal.

Second, captive portal browsers are way behind the times with
regard to css support. No CSS-Grid here, folks. Sadly I had to
fall back on some older methods to make my page pretty.

Speaking of pages, here's a link to the repository that houses my
web interface to the library [1].

If you're reading this as of the moment of posting then you'll see
that I haven't addressed problem #1 yet. If you're finding this
later in time, hopefully it's all fixed for you. Here's my current
plan of attack:

- Create a very simple captive portal page that advertises the
  little free library and instructs users to open a regular
  browser and navigate to http://littlefreelibrary.local
- The generated library page will be hosted at the root url, not
  the captive-portal location, and will allow full downloads.

This is going to take some testing to get right, but once it's all
squared away I'll update that repo to contain both pages and
deployment scripts.

Finally, I've purchased a solar battery that I'm going to try out.
It's a very basic solar charging battery pack of Amazon that I'm
not going to bother linking. It's likely not the real solution
here since they're notoriously bad at actually charging from the
sun, and when they do they overheat and destroy the battery. But
it will finish my proof of concept, and that's what's important.

Once that arrives, I'll hopefully have time this weekend to give
the project one last push and get it working in the woods.

[0] Little Free Library, Part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181014-little-free-library-part-1
[1] Little Free Library Web Source
    http://github.com/jamestomasino/littlefreelibrary
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Talkd On Ubuntu</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20190102-talkd-on-ubuntu/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
talkd on ubuntu
January 02nd, 2019
----------------------------------------

I need to save these notes somewhere. I just got talkd working on
ubuntu 18.10 and it was quite convoluted. Here's what I did:

- install openbsd-inetd (not inetutils-inetd, it's shit)
- install talkd (not inetutils-talkd, also shit)
- install ytalk (better than talk by a mile)

edit /etc/inetd.conf and add the following:

#:BSD: Shell, login, exec and talk are BSD protocols.
talk   dgram udp wait nobody.tty /usr/sbin/tcpd in.talkd
ntalk  dgram udp wait nobody.tty /usr/sbin/tcpd in.ntalkd 

note the /usr/sbin/tcpd. If talkd added content here for you,
those are probably quite different. Trust tcpd to handle the
connection for you and hand it off to in.talkd and in.ntalkd
afterwards. 

'nobody' will probably need to be added to the tty group. In truth
you should make another dummy user without a login shell named
'talkd' and add THAT user to tty, but this works.

$ sudo usermod -a -G tty nobody

Restart inetd:

$ sudo service openbsd-inetd restart

Now you should be able to use 'talk' on your server, locally at
least.

Ports 517 and 518 are for talkd, so you can open them up in your
firewall and that should be enough to talk to other servers, but
I don't have that piece of the puzzle just yet.

Good luck!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Reading Questions And Answers</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181230-reading-questions-and-answers/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Reading Questions and Answers
December 30th, 2018
----------------------------------------

These questions come from christyotwisty [0]. I'll do my best to
answer them as other's have [1].

What is the first book you remember loving?

  This is a little embarrassing now, since I've grown to discover
  what a horrific little man the author is, but the first book and
  series I grew to love was Vale of the Vole [2], book 10 in the
  Xanth series by Piers Anthony. My dad brought it home one day
  and I gave it a shot. It hooked me quick and sent me back to the
  beginning of the series. I read a bunch of them before
  graduating on to better fantasy books. It put a life-long love
  of the genre into my blood.

What book/series would you like to see adapted to film?

  The Wheel of Time has long been my answer to this. It's epic on
  a scale that many series strive for and can't quite achieve.
  It's part of the central canon of fantasy literature, love it or
  hate it, and it's never been given a fair shot at the screen.
  I would love to see it done well, but fear it as well.
  
  Adaptations no longer belong to the author. They need to
  maximize their medium and be the best they can be in that form.
  This is why Dune is so hard to put on screen. The book is
  philosophy and philosophy makes for terrible films. It causes
  directors to over-use voice-over for internal thoughts. The
  Wheel of Time would make for excellent on-screen action without
  getting too lost in translation. Even so, will a film match the
  story I love or will I be disgusted by the inevitable changes
  that need to be made?

Who are your favourite protagonists?

  I get deep satisfaction from characters that take a beating but
  keep up the snark only to eventually do something epic. Harry
  Dresden pops to mind as an example, as does Nona Grey from the
  Book of the Ancestor series. Even Helen Harper's guilty pleasure
  urban fantasy series "The Lazy Girl's Guide to Magic" has such
  a heroine in Ivy Wilde. Joe Bishop of the Expeditionary Force
  takes his knocks and then starts inter-stellar civil wars. Nancy
  A. Collins' Sonja Blue does it too.

  While they may not share the snark, characters who endure
  endless hardship with positivity, ingenuity, and resolve also
  dig into my heart for all time. The hero of Hatchet and Julie of
  the Wolves did that to me in middle school. And it's why my
  favorite character from any book is still Jane Eyre. I mean...
  the quotes!

     "Do you think I am an automaton? — a machine without feelings?
     and can bear to have my morsel of bread snatched from my
     lips, and my drop of living water dashed from my cup? Do you
     think, because I am poor, obscure, plain, and little, I am
     soulless and heartless? You think wrong! — I have as much
     soul as you — and full as much heart! And if God had gifted
     me with some beauty and much wealth, I should have made it as
     hard for you to leave me, as it is now for me to leave you. I
     am not talking to you now through the medium of custom,
     conventionalities, nor even of mortal flesh: it is my spirit
     that addresses your spirit; just as if both had passed
     through the grave, and we stood at God's feet, equal — as we
     are!"

     "I care for myself. The more solitary, the more friendless,
     the more unsustained I am, the more I will respect myself."

  Damn, son!

Who are your favourite antagonists?

  The Baron Harkonnen in all his forms and genetic memory takes
  it. He is brilliant and disgusting. Hannibal Lecter is delicious
  too. Going old-school, Lady MacBeth was the first villain to
  make me throw a book across a room (honorable mention to Iago).
  Oh, and freakin' Mars itself in the Martian. It threw everything
  it could at our hero, but took a swift sciencey kick to the
  face.

What, so far, is the best book you've read this year?

  The Collapsing Empire (The Interdependency #1) by John Scalzi.
  It's a lovely new sci-fi series that just release book #2. If
  you're into Scalzi's stuff it doesn't disappoint. There's some
  epic stuff, some really nice mysteries, and colorful characters
  gallore. I hope it goes on and on.

Can you list three to five of your favourite authors? 

  Genre greats like Brandon Sanderson, Frank Herbert, Robert
  Jordan, George R.R. Martin, Mary Stewart, and John Scalzi.
  
  Classic literature is dominated by my girl Charlotte Bronte.
  
  Poets like Mary Oliver, Christina Rosetti, and Elizabeth Barrett
  Browning.

Why are they your favourite?

  They create worlds where I can lose myself. They create
  characters who I internalize and who become a part of me. And
  they speak truth to my soul.

What are your least favourite genres to read?

  Romance is a no-go to me. Same with whatever fluffy nonsense you
  call Elin Hilderbrand's stuff. Horror is also not often on the
  list. I don't find it scary, so it's mostly just gross or
  depressing. 

What was the last book you recommended to a friend?

  Sebastien De Castell's "Traitor's Blade", book one of the
  Greatcoats Series. When did I recommend it? Why, right now of
  course. You should pick it up!  

What is your favourite film adaptation of a book?

  The Firm. It stands out as a fantastic example of the film being
  better than the book. It doesn't happen often!

What books have you read the most times?

  Dune, far and away. After that, Jane Eyre.

What fictional world or novel's setting would you like to live in?

  That's such a tricky question. So many of the fantasy worlds
  I read are amazing places, but horribly dangerous. Or they would
  be awesome to live in if I had one of the magic powers. The same
  goes for sci-fi series. If I weren't running out of air on
  a runaway space station, it might be cool!

  I've read a bunch of Star Trek novels, though, so I'm gonna take
  the easy way out and say I'd like to live in the Federation.
  Give me a future of peace where humanity struggles to improve
  itself. (Side note, The Economics of Star Trek is also an
  amazing book. Read that too.)

What are your favourite classic books?

  Oh, I should have looked ahead at this list. Jane Eyre for
  fiction, but I love a lot of others too. The classical reads of
  stoicism, like Epictetus and Aurelius's stuff is special to me.
  So is Summa Theologica, though I admit skimming large portions.
  There's Martin Chuzzlewit and the Iliad, or Introduction to the
  Devout Life. So many great reads.

What is the most recent book you didn't expect to like, yet did?

  The Trumpet of Terror! It's a Choose Your Own Adventure book and
  I picked it to read on my show because the cover looked awful,
  but it turned out to be really well written.

If you could meet one author, living or dead, whom would it be?

  Hmm, probably Frank Herbert. It's not a particular desire of
  mine in general, but I'd like to know from his own mouth where
  he wanted the series to go before his son butchered it.

What authors do you think more people should read?

  Don't be afraid of classics. Most of them have stuck around for
  a reason. :)

[0] Christina's Reading Questions
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~christina/ReadingQuestions.txt
[1] Sloum's Answers
    gopher://zaibatsu.circumlunar.space/0/~sloum/phlog/20181230-12.txt
[2] Vale of the Vole
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Vale of the Vole
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moku Pona Updates</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181226-moku-pona-updates/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Moku Pona updates
December 26th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Thanks to a great deal of help from kensanata, my moku-pona page
now supports phlog feeds. Ulcer is the first one benefiting from
it. Have a look.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolutions</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
resolutions
December 25th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A friend came up with a brilliant way to handle New Year
resolutions when we were in college. He decided that he would
resolve to do something or accomplish something that is definitely
attainable by SOMEONE, just not YOU. It makes for a fun resolution
that's also kinda hard to come up with. Here's a few we've had
over the years:

- This year I will break the sound barrier.
- This year I'll be given the KEY to the CITY!
- This year I'm going to kiss the Queen of England.

With that in mind, I'd like to let you all know that 2019 is going
to be an epic year for me. How epic, you ask? Well...

This year, I'm going to be impeached.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
