<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Re Jynx On Life Segmentation And Happiness/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180711-re-jynx-on-life-segmentation-and-happiness/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
ire: jynx on life segmentation and happiness		gopher.black	70
iJuly 11th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
ijynx wrote [0] a note about separation of life and employment and		gopher.black	70
ithe freedom it's given him. It's been an extremely helpful read		gopher.black	70
ifor me and helped me put things back in perspective. I keep		gopher.black	70
ire-reading it.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[0] jynx - On life segmentation and happiness	/users/jynx/phlog/typezero/20180709.post	gopher.club	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Freelance/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180709-freelance/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iFreelance		gopher.black	70
iJuly 09th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI'm not sure why I bother with freelance. I mean, I like having		gopher.black	70
isome extra income, but I'm so burnt out from work already, do		gopher.black	70
iI really want more?		gopher.black	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shut It Down/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180708-shut-it-down/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
ishut it down		gopher.black	70
iJuly 08th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSometimes the little frustrations add up and spill over. I tend to		gopher.black	70
iget very quiet when I'm at my breaking point. I shut down. I walk		gopher.black	70
iaway. When I was young I'd walk away in grandiose ways: from		gopher.black	70
irelationships, jobs, responsibility. I've learned how to siphon		gopher.black	70
ioff the steam before reaching that point. I meditate, I walk,		gopher.black	70
iI pray. I can roll with it a lot more than when I was a kid.		gopher.black	70
iStill, sometimes it feels like it would be easier to shut it all		gopher.black	70
idown and walk away from my life. It's not a rational thought. My		gopher.black	70
ilife is pretty damn good. The frustrations are minor things,		gopher.black	70
imeaningless really. You can't compare lives that way, though. It's		gopher.black	70
inot rational, as I said, and it's not logical.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI'm going to drink a nice glass of gin, read a bit, and go for an		gopher.black	70
ievening walk. Tomorrow will start a busy work-week and I'll be		gopher.black	70
iwalking into it already stressed. It's not a good recipe.		gopher.black	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>New Keyboard/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180706-new-keyboard/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iNew keyboard		gopher.black	70
iJuly 06th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iToday marked the arrival of my newest mechanical keyboard,		gopher.black	70
ia Planck from Massdrop. Planck is an ortholinear, minimalist,		gopher.black	70
imechanical keyboard. It's just 4 rows tall (no number row or		gopher.black	70
iFkeys). It supports multiple layers, though, so you can switch		gopher.black	70
ibetween keymaps, or meta-layers, or whatever else floats your		gopher.black	70
iboat. Right now I'm running with two layers [0]:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i - Dvorak		gopher.black	70
i - Num-pad & arrows		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThe Planck comes as a kit that you need to assemble. That means		gopher.black	70
ilaying out the PCB and base plate and popping all the key switches		gopher.black	70
iin to place (careful to align the pins just right). Then there was		gopher.black	70
ia great deal of soldering. I'm happy to say it went smoothly and		gopher.black	70
iI had no issues with my joints whatsoever. The board is then		gopher.black	70
iscrewed into the milled bottom, some rubber feet are attached, and		gopher.black	70
iyou're good to go.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIn my case I also had to flash the firmware to get my sexy layout		gopher.black	70
iinstalled. There was a hiccup there as the software I was using to		gopher.black	70
icreate the layout had placed the spacebar in the wrong location.		gopher.black	70
iEverything worked but the space! I actually took it all apart,		gopher.black	70
iremove the switch, resoldered in a replacement, only to find out		gopher.black	70
ithat it wasn't a hardware issue at all. I changed one setting in		gopher.black	70
imy firmware and we're all good again.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI'll need to practice using it, especially the layer changes.		gopher.black	70
iHere's hoping I pick it up quickly. I suspect this will become my		gopher.black	70
ifavorite little keyboard buddy.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
h[0] Tomasino's Keyboard Firmware	URL:http://github.com/jamestomasino/tomasino-dvorak-keyboard
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Space Gopher 2000/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180705-space-gopher-2000/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iSpace Gopher 2000		gopher.black	70
iJuly 05th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iWhat if quantum entaglement and spooky action at a distance allow		gopher.black	70
ifor us to create extremely long range connections, but with very		gopher.black	70
ilow bandwidth. "Why would that be the case?" you might ask.		gopher.black	70
iFrankly, I have no idea. If you don't think about the details too		gopher.black	70
imuch it seems like something you could gloss over in a story,		gopher.black	70
ithough.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI want to explore that idea in a short story as a vehicle to		gopher.black	70
ireintroduce gopher as the web of the space-future. No nonsense,		gopher.black	70
itext driven communication across vast spaces would make for an		gopher.black	70
iincredible aesthetic and a great reason to draw some attention		gopher.black	70
iback to port 70.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI think of films like Alien and their use of text for		gopher.black	70
icommunication and it makes sense to me. Local running AIs and		gopher.black	70
isuper-powerful UI crap is neat, but for anything at a distance we		gopher.black	70
ifall back on the age-old safety of text. If you imagine a universe		gopher.black	70
ipopulated by ships launched and traveling at relativistic speeds,		gopher.black	70
iwe quickly encounter vast distances in relative time, not only		gopher.black	70
ispace. These time gaps are a bigger threat to communication than		gopher.black	70
idistance. We cannot innovate because it leaves behind all those		gopher.black	70
ithat have gone out before. We cannot shift paradigms. We must		gopher.black	70
ispeak to a common level.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIsn't that a cool thought? I want to read stuff in that universe.		gopher.black	70
iI want gopher featured prominantly. I guess I should start working		gopher.black	70
ion it at some point.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iDo any of you have any ideas to pile on top? I don't have a story		gopher.black	70
ihere at all, just setting, so I could use all the help I can get.		gopher.black	70
iOr, I guess if one of you is feeling the creative juices flowing,		gopher.black	70
itake it and run. I want to read it more than I want to write it.		gopher.black	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Myths And Truth/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180705-myths-and-truth/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iMyths and truth		gopher.black	70
iJuly 05th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iJoseph Campbell was fond of saying that all myths are true. His		gopher.black	70
iline of thinking is that the myths we know and that our societies		gopher.black	70
ihave developed are culturally dependant expressions of a universal		gopher.black	70
istory. 		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIn comparative mythology or comparative religion we see the same		gopher.black	70
iaspects echoed across time and space. In his mind there were two		gopher.black	70
ipossible reasons why:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  1. There are similarities in human psychology and physiology		gopher.black	70
i     that lead us to generate the same responses to our		gopher.black	70
i     experiences regardless of culture and climate.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  2. There is a shared truth which all of our myths and symbols		gopher.black	70
i     help us to express. That expression is unique to our culture		gopher.black	70
i     but it speaks to a universal truth which itself is ineffable.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThat is a tragically simplified summary, but it should do for my		gopher.black	70
ipurposes as there's only a small point I'd like to make regarding		gopher.black	70
imyths. 		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  Myths are not true, they reveal truth.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iWhen Catholics look at the bible and read the story of creation,		gopher.black	70
ithat story is a myth [0]. It is not literal. It is there to teach		gopher.black	70
ius something about creation in language and stories that make		gopher.black	70
isense to the culture of the time. This reading with a cultural		gopher.black	70
ilens is vital to a Catholic reading of scripture, even the		gopher.black	70
iGospels.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[0] Genesis 1	/bible/Genesis/genesis-1.txt
i		gopher.black	70
iIn the book of Luke [1], there is a passage that should be		gopher.black	70
ifamiliar to even the most lapsed of Christians. It is the story of		gopher.black	70
iMary and Joseph arriving in Bethlehem for the birth of Jesus:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  In those days a decree went out from Caesar Augustus that all		gopher.black	70
i  the world should be registered. This was the first registration		gopher.black	70
i  when Quirinius was governor of Syria. And all went to be		gopher.black	70
i  registered, each to his own town. And Joseph also went up from		gopher.black	70
i  Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of		gopher.black	70
i  David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house		gopher.black	70
i  and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed,		gopher.black	70
i  who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for		gopher.black	70
i  her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and		gopher.black	70
i  wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger,		gopher.black	70
i  because there was no place for them in the inn. [1]		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[1] Luke 2	/bible/Luke/luke-2.txt
i		gopher.black	70
iI want to focus on just two phrases in this paragraph:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  "he was of the house and lineage of David"		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  and		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  "laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in		gopher.black	70
i  the inn."		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iStarting with the first phrase, this is an important note for		gopher.black	70
ia few reasons, biblically. It touches on prophecy fulfillment		gopher.black	70
ibecause it satisfies the messianic idea that the figure will come		gopher.black	70
ifrom the house of David. It is also important because of the		gopher.black	70
ipolitical implications of the house itself. The house of David was		gopher.black	70
ithe most prestigious of the Jewish people, after all. Heading to		gopher.black	70
ithe ancestral home of that people is a big deal in a culture		gopher.black	70
idominated by family value. This is a key point to remember in the		gopher.black	70
istory, too. Mary and Joseph aren't going to some small town in the		gopher.black	70
imiddle of nowhere. They're going to the home of the wealthiest,		gopher.black	70
imost prestigious family. The people of the house of David would be		gopher.black	70
imany. This is not a land of strangers for them.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIt's also important to remember that for these people at the time		gopher.black	70
ithere is a great emphasis put on the idea of hospitality. Elijah		gopher.black	70
iis going to return, and they must be ready. He may come in the		gopher.black	70
iguise of a beggar to your door. And so, welcoming in the traveler		gopher.black	70
ihas a major role in daily life. It has such a role, that it even		gopher.black	70
iaffected the architecture of first century Palestine.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThe typical home at the time was made up of two main rooms. The		gopher.black	70
ifirst was the family's room. It would be raised up off the ground		gopher.black	70
ia few feet and be all open. On one side there would be a ledge		gopher.black	70
ithat drops down to ground level as the room extends into the		gopher.black	70
ianimal enclosure. The animals would stay inside in poor weather or		gopher.black	70
iseasons, and their heat would be shared by the family. On the		gopher.black	70
ifloor by this ledge were impressions in the ground where feed was		gopher.black	70
iplaced: the manger.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThe second room was attached, often with a separate entrance. This		gopher.black	70
iwas the guest house or reception room, and it was intended for		gopher.black	70
ivisitors and extended family. We see such a room referenced twice		gopher.black	70
iin the bible by the Greek word kataluma. A kataluma is the room		gopher.black	70
iused by Jesus and his disciples during the last supper. It is also		gopher.black	70
ithe word used in this paragraph and translated as "inn".		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIn the ancient world there were no hotels. The closest you might		gopher.black	70
ifind was a tent filled with straw mats, called a caravansary. This		gopher.black	70
iword was translated to "inn" during the story of the good		gopher.black	70
iSamaritan. When the man is injured and placed in the inn for care,		gopher.black	70
ithat was a caravansary. In Luke we're talking about a very		gopher.black	70
idifferent thing.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iTaken together with our understanding of Jewish culture and the		gopher.black	70
iimportance of the family of David, it is inconceivable to imagine		gopher.black	70
ithe holy family alone in a barn on that first Christmas. The		gopher.black	70
ikataluma was full, so they were instead brought into the family		gopher.black	70
iroom in communion with many others. When the child was born he was		gopher.black	70
iplaced there in the manger where all could see him.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSo why do I bring this up? It isn't to criticize those poor		gopher.black	70
iChristmas pageants. It's to talk about the myths.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThe story of Jesus birth is not vital to the story of his teaching		gopher.black	70
ior his role within the faith. If Jesus is born in the midst of the		gopher.black	70
imost powerful Jewish family instead of alone in a barn, there's no		gopher.black	70
ifundamental truth being assaulted. In fact, if you spent your		gopher.black	70
ientire life believing one idea vs the other idea, it would have		gopher.black	70
ialmost no bearing on your understanding of Jesus at all. Does that		gopher.black	70
imean it doesn't matter? Does that suggest that a bunch of these		gopher.black	70
istories are filler and don't have an impact on us? Well, no, not		gopher.black	70
iexactly.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThe stories, the myths, and our comprehension of them are trying		gopher.black	70
ito tell us something, but it's almost never the literal histories.		gopher.black	70
iHere in the story of Christ's birth we are being made to		gopher.black	70
iunderstand his place in the culture of the Jewish people, and his		gopher.black	70
irelationship to the prophets that came before him. In this way we		gopher.black	70
ican understand that he is legitimate. His role is appropriate.		gopher.black	70
iHe's not just some guy who found a bunch of metal plates in his		gopher.black	70
ibackyard [2].		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
h[2] Problems with the gold plates	URL:http://www.equip.org/article/problems-with-the-gold-plates-of-the-book-of-mormon-2/
i		gopher.black	70
iEach myth is meant to communicate something to us that words alone		gopher.black	70
ican't. They are intricately tied to the culture of their creation,		gopher.black	70
iand when that culture changes so must the myths. Without this		gopher.black	70
ichange they become distance, misaligned, and misconstrued. Before		gopher.black	70
iyou know it you are taking words from Leviticus and applying them		gopher.black	70
ito a whole different world.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  As for your male and female slaves whom you may have: you may		gopher.black	70
i  buy male and female slaves from among the nations that are		gopher.black	70
i  around you. [3]		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[3] Leviticus 25	/bible/Leviticus/leviticus-25.txt
i		gopher.black	70
iWhether we're looking at stories of the Buddha or Brahman,		gopher.black	70
iGicelemû’kaong or Birrahgnooloo, the myths create and communicate		gopher.black	70
iour understanding of their truth. The myths are not the truth, but		gopher.black	70
ithey are true, all of them. 		gopher.black	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Essence Of Gopher/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180703-the-essence-of-gopher/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iThe essence of gopher		gopher.black	70
iJuly 03rd, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iOur dear friend cat is at it again. He recently flew the coop		gopher.black	70
ifrom SDF and has planted his seed in a new project called		gopher.black	70
ibaud.baby [0]. He's a resourceful guy and has quickly conquered		gopher.black	70
isome of the more tedious aspects of getting your own gopher hole		gopher.black	70
iup and running. Kudos, cat!		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[0] baud.baby	/phlog/fs20180628.txt	baud.baby	70
i		gopher.black	70
iHis most recent phlog touches on one of his passions, vintage		gopher.black	70
iphones [1]. In my humble opinion it is EVERYTHING that gopher		gopher.black	70
ishould be summed up into a microcosm of aussie geekdom. It has		gopher.black	70
ipassion for a vintage technology, collection, curation, more		gopher.black	70
itechnical details than you could have imagined, and a neverending		gopher.black	70
ithirst for more. It's also beautiful. His manual text layouts		gopher.black	70
ireally shine on things like his phone collection page [2].		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
0[1] A bunch of Touchfone stuff	/phlog/fs20180703.txt	baud.baby	70
1[2] Weirdly Specific Collection of Phones	/phones	baud.baby	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI've run across similarly brilliant curation in places like		gopher.black	70
imateusz's DOS software repository [3], or Logout's new ASCII table		gopher.black	70
i[4], or dbucklin's intelligence analysis documents [5]. This stuff		gopher.black	70
iis gopher gold. 		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
1[3] mateusz's DOS software repository	/abandonware	gopher.viste.fr	70
1[4] Logout's ASCII table	/en/ascii	i-logout.cz	70
1[5] dbucklin's Intelligence Analysis Documents	/users/dbucklin/files	sdf.org	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI've been really phlog focused in the past, but I think that		gopher.black	70
ioverlooked some of the best stuff around. Now I'm finally starting		gopher.black	70
ito add more links to these collections and repositories over on my		gopher.black	70
iGopher Places [6] section. Check it out and discover some awesome.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
1[6] Gopher Places	/places
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why I Use Gophermaps/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180701-why-i-use-gophermaps/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iWhy I use Gophermaps		gopher.black	70
iJuly 01st, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
imaiki just asked why I use gophermaps for my phlog instead of		gopher.black	70
iplain text. I know others at bitreich [0] have commented on the		gopher.black	70
ipractice with various opinions on why "misusing" gophermaps is		gopher.black	70
ibad. Plenty of people on gopher use plain text for their content		gopher.black	70
iand I am not going to complain. My choice is a product of style		gopher.black	70
iand philosophy.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iStyle:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iOne of the best things about hypertext is the ability to link		gopher.black	70
icontextually to relevant content. Gopher is missing this to		gopher.black	70
ia degree, but not entirely. We can't link a block of text inline		gopher.black	70
ilike in HTML but we can link a line. That functionality is		gopher.black	70
ientirely limited to gophermaps, though. Without the gophermap the		gopher.black	70
ibest we can do is include a text link and rely on the client to go		gopher.black	70
iabove and beyond the protocol to enable interaction (like VF-1 so		gopher.black	70
ivaliantly does).		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iMy choice, stylistically, was to take it upon myself to do		gopher.black	70
ia little extra work and build in the links directly into the		gopher.black	70
icontent by making my phlogs a gophermap. I first announced this		gopher.black	70
ichange [1] back in October of 2017 when I was still relatively new		gopher.black	70
iat this whole thing. In fact, I was piggybacking on the very		gopher.black	70
ibare-bones shell scripts that would later become burrow [2]. My		gopher.black	70
ifirst iteration was just a bunch of echo commands to a blank file		gopher.black	70
iand then launching vim [3]. These days I have the ability to edit		gopher.black	70
iexisting phlog entries, generate in plain text or gophermaps,		gopher.black	70
iauto-generate RSS, and a bunch of other crap.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iPhilosophy:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iFrom what I've seen over my time on gopher the biggest complaint		gopher.black	70
iabout gophermaps for content isn't about the effort involved in		gopher.black	70
icreating them. Instead it's an argument for purity in the		gopher.black	70
iprotocol. "Don't use the 'i' item type for this sort of thing,"		gopher.black	70
ithey say. "The 'i' type isn't even in RFC 1436!" And it's true.		gopher.black	70
iThe type isn't defined in 1436, and it definitely isn't pure		gopher.black	70
igopher as envisioned in the two-week sprint that a bunch of guys		gopher.black	70
iat the University of Minnesota did as much to stick it to the man		gopher.black	70
i(their school beauracracy) as they did to just get something out		gopher.black	70
ithere for the community to react to.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSee, I don't see that as something to protect through purity. The		gopher.black	70
imindset of those guys was to iterate, to share, to build, and to		gopher.black	70
imake the internet better. They didn't sit for years in planning		gopher.black	70
ibefore deploying the end-all-be-all of protocols. They cobbled		gopher.black	70
itogether some crap on top of existing tools and made improvements.		gopher.black	70
iAnd that's what type "i" did later. It enabled us to write more		gopher.black	70
idescription than would fit on one line so there was context to		gopher.black	70
ia link.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iThat's what I see myself doing when I phlog. The links below (and		gopher.black	70
inow sometimes in-line) are given context by my post. If you're		gopher.black	70
ireading and say, "hey, I should check that out!" now you can. You		gopher.black	70
ijust follow the link and boom, there you are.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iFor those folks who don't bother with it and post in plain text,		gopher.black	70
iif I really want to chase down a link I can select it and manually		gopher.black	70
ienter it. It's more difficult, but it's doable. I hold no grudge		gopher.black	70
iagainst them for their choice.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIf you are new to gopher and just want to toss up markdown files		gopher.black	70
ithat you're also using to generate a web version, go for it. I'll		gopher.black	70
ibe more happy that you've decided to add content here than		gopher.black	70
ianything else. I'm certainly not going to berate your efforts by		gopher.black	70
init-picking on whether you use type 1 or type 0. 		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
1[0] bitreich.org	/	bitreich.org	70
1[1] New Format Test	/phlog/20171003-new-format-test
h[2] burrow	URL:http://gitlab.com/jamestomasino/burrow
0[0] This is amazeballs	/phlog/20170817-this-is-amazeballs.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Sc Im/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180629-cli-tricks-sc-im/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iCLI Tricks: sc-im		gopher.black	70
iJune 29th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSC-IM - Spreadsheet Calculator Improvised		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iA vim-like modal editor for spreadsheets in the terminal (ncurses)		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIt supports the following formats:		gopher.black	70
i 		gopher.black	70
i  .sc     SC-IM's native text format		gopher.black	70
i  .xls    Microsoft Excel Spreadsheet		gopher.black	70
i  .xlsx   Microsoft Office Open XML Workbook		gopher.black	70
i  .csv    Comma-separated values		gopher.black	70
i  .tsv    Tab-separated values		gopher.black	70
i  .tab    Tab-separated values		gopher.black	70
i  .txt    Simple text files		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIt has an impressive set of features (from the README)!		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  UNDO / REDO.		gopher.black	70
i  65.536 rows and 702 columns supported. (The number of rows can		gopher.black	70
i     be expanded to 1.048.576 if wished).		gopher.black	70
i  CSV / TAB delimited / XLSX file import and export.		gopher.black	70
i  Scripting support with LUA. Also with triggers and c dynamic		gopher.black	70
i  linked modules.		gopher.black	70
i  Clipboard support.		gopher.black	70
i  GNUPlot interaction.		gopher.black	70
i  Key-mappings.		gopher.black	70
i  Sort of rows.		gopher.black	70
i  Filter of rows.		gopher.black	70
i  Subtotals.		gopher.black	70
i  Cell shifting.		gopher.black	70
i  256 color support - screen colors can be customized by user,		gopher.black	70
i      even at runtime.		gopher.black	70
i  Colorize cells or give them format such as bold or underline.		gopher.black	70
i  Wide character support. The following alphabets are supported:		gopher.black	70
i      English, Spanish, French, Italian, German, Portuguese, 		gopher.black	70
i      Russian, Ukrainian, Greek, Turkish, Czech, Japanese, Chinese.		gopher.black	70
i  Autobackup.		gopher.black	70
i  Implement external functions in the language you prefer and use		gopher.black	70
i      them in SC-IM.		gopher.black	70
i  Use SC-IM as a non-interactive calculator, reading its input 		gopher.black	70
i      from a external script.		gopher.black	70
i  More movements commands implemented !		gopher.black	70
i  Input and Output was completely rewritten.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iIt's a breeze to install on MacOS or Linux. Give it a shot.		gopher.black	70
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Federation And Gopher/</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180627-federation-and-gopher/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
iFederation and gopher		gopher.black	70
iJune 27th, 2018		gopher.black	70
i----------------------------------------		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSome of you guys were talking about a "federated gopher" on		gopher.black	70
iMastodon the other day. At first I was all into the idea and		gopher.black	70
igetting ready to chime in with support. But then I started		gopher.black	70
ithinking about what that would mean and I hit a wall. I think my		gopher.black	70
iunderstanding of federation in recent context has skewed away from		gopher.black	70
ithe community idea. With all the work on ActivityPub and the new		gopher.black	70
iclients popping up in the Fediverse I feel like I should probably		gopher.black	70
ispend the time to figure out what it is everyone is talking about		gopher.black	70
iwhen they use the word Federated.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iSince we're talking definitions here, I figured I should start by		gopher.black	70
itelneting to my happy dictionary [0] that I described in an old		gopher.black	70
iphlog post [1]. Then I ran my query: "define english federation".		gopher.black	70
iHere's what popped out:		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  <security> The establishment of some or all of business		gopher.black	70
i  agreements, {cryptographic} trust and user identifiers or		gopher.black	70
i  attributes across security and policy domains to enable more		gopher.black	70
i  seamless business interaction.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
i  As {web services} promise to enable integration between		gopher.black	70
i  business partners through {loose coupling} at the application		gopher.black	70
i  and messaging layer, federation does so at the identity		gopher.black	70
i  management layer, insulating each domain from the details of		gopher.black	70
i  the others' authentication and authorization.  Key to this		gopher.black	70
i  loose coupling at the identity management layer are		gopher.black	70
i  standardized mechanisms and formats for the communication of		gopher.black	70
i  identity information between the domains.  {SAML} is one such		gopher.black	70
i  standard.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iFrom the sound of that definition, gopher is already federated in		gopher.black	70
ithat identity information between domains is inherent to the		gopher.black	70
iprotocol because it's irrelevant. There's no authorized use		gopher.black	70
imechanism here and the act of hosting content on a server is		gopher.black	70
ienough to identify the source. Since I host on gopher.black, if		gopher.black	70
iyour use of gopher queries my server you have used standard		gopher.black	70
imechanisms and formats for the communication of that information		gopher.black	70
ibetween the domains, right?		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iMaybe the reason I'm having such difficulty is because my only		gopher.black	70
iexposure to federation as an idea has been via things like		gopher.black	70
iMastodon which have far more interoperable parts. Content from one		gopher.black	70
iindependent system is consumed and becomes content within another		gopher.black	70
ione, and the source of that content, the author, server, etc, all		gopher.black	70
ineed to be accounted for in the communication. That requires more		gopher.black	70
ithan gopher for sure.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iEven so, I'm not satisfied. I think there's more to federation		gopher.black	70
ithan that definition. The context in how people discuss it seems		gopher.black	70
ito imply something else, but I can't put my finger on exactly what		gopher.black	70
ithat might be. Distributed systems like IPFS come up a lot in		gopher.black	70
ithose discussions, but I don't see a black & white relationship.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iI guess my slow brainmeats can't get past the idea that federation		gopher.black	70
imeans I control my shiz but it can interact with everyone elses		gopher.black	70
ishiz in the same way. Am I so far off? Let me know with a reply or		gopher.black	70
iemail or mastodon or a hand written letter.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iYes! Hand written letters are my absolute favorite. They		gopher.black	70
idemonstrate all that extra effort, they're physical treasures, and		gopher.black	70
iI get to silently judge your personality through bullshit		gopher.black	70
ihandwriting interpretation that I make up on the spot. Everyone		gopher.black	70
iwins! Send me an note with a reference to a pgp key and I'll send		gopher.black	70
iyou back my mailing address on the down-low.		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
iCheers, fedi-gophers		gopher.black	70
i		gopher.black	70
8[0] Telnet to dict.org	dict	dict.org	2628
1[1] CLI Tricks: Dictionaries	/phlog/20180405-cli-tricks-dictionaries
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
