<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>The Effects Of Deleting A Social Medium</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200306-the-effects-of-deleting-a-social-medium/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The effects of deleting a social medium
March 06th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I recently removed the Instagram app from my phone. (pause for
applause).

This is not a statement about the evils of social media, or the
objectification of ketogenic foods, or whatever else you might be
guessing. It's about time.

I removed the app because of the little magnifying-glass button
next to the home feed. There was a tendency for me to fill my time
by looking at random pictures Instagram thought relevant to me.
This was really easy for their algorithm to game and optimize.
Very quickly I had an endless scroll of "neat" stuff, and that was
sucking up way too much of my time without any tangible reward.

I like my own instagram feed. Seeing photos from friends and
places that interest me is cool and relatively quick to consume.
I don't need to read much and I can "catch up" quickly in a linear
timeline. If there were a way to disable that little magnifier
icon the app would still be on my phone.

I've since started posting pictures on pixelfed [0]. There's not
much to that app except the posting of pictures, so the temptation
to check it at other times is gone. When I post something I give
the feed a quick scroll to see if anything new is there, and then
I'm done. Easy!

[0] pixelfed
    https://pixfed.com/jamestomasino

Even so, in the days following the Instagram change I went through
the usual withdrawl. I ended up closing and opening mastodon again
several times in a row as my hands tried to fill the habit with
the available tools. Now several days in I'm no longer in that
habitual loop and I've begun reclaiming my time [1].

[1] Reclaiming my time
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tqCZzs7UXIo

The first effect is my improved patience with long-form content.
I've been catching up on phlogs & blogs (RSS) more readily. That
was unexpected but appreciated. It makes me wonder about the
implications too. If cutting out one small habit that involved
short attention-span cycling has such a major effect on my overall
patience, how crippled is my current state? If I cut out Mastodon
and even IRC, would that attention continue to grow? How fast?
This might warrant some experimentation.

Another effect is a diminishing of the value of my phone.
I haven't ceased using it and there are plenty of other apps that
hold my attention for lengthy periods. Still, the change has been
tangible. Again, further experimentation is needed.

I know this community is filled with folks who have gone through
similar changes. What's your experience with cutting out a social
platform? Has it remained cut out? Do you still see the tangibles
in your life, or did those fade to some sort of "rest state"? Were
there notable negatives?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Smolderingwizard Roll Vs Roleplaying</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200306-re-smolderingwizard-roll-vs-roleplaying/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: smolderingwizard - roll vs roleplaying
March 06th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I just read a really interesting observational phlog post from
smolderingwizard [0] on his experiences in a 5th edition D&D game.
He describes everything in 5th edition coming down to a mechanic
role and that those rolls are happening constantly and distracting
from the game.

[0] smolderingwizard - roll vs role-playing
    gopher://gopher.smolderingwizard.com/0/phlog/2020-03-05-roll-vs-role-5e-vs-old-school.md

I've run into this in some games as well and feel it's ultimately
the fault of the DM/GM, though I can't judge them harshly for it.
Running a game is hard work and it's not a skill that's usually
taught. People learn in their own way, from playing with others
and emulating good GMs, or watching games online, or just doing
their best to guess their way through. 

One big influence these days is computer gaming. It's had immense
impact on tabletop RPGs over the years, going so far as to
completely screw up D&D into the mess that was 4th edition AKA
World of Warcraft on paper. But even in the early days of say, 2nd
edition, there were books and books describing mechanics that you
could turn into rolls. I remember one guidebook describing the
fall-off rate of light from various sized campfires and the impact
for low-light vision at each distance in a grid. It got silly.

But those books didn't come from a vacuum. People wanted that in
their games. There's always been a subset of gamers who want the
mechanics to rule the action. Sometimes these are reflected in
power-gaming, or just optimized buildes. Sometimes it's just
a style of play that the group enjoys.

I cannot put myself in that camp, personally. My most formative
long-term RPG was played 1-on-1 with my DM in high school. It was
a solo game and we rolled almost never. The entire game was
role-play and that has had enormous impact on my own style.

In the Fate Core System book, the game designers have this to say:

  When to Roll Dice

  Roll the dice when succeeding or failing at the action could
  each contribute something interesting to the game...

  The worst, WORST thing you can do is have a failed roll that
  means NOTHING HAPPENS--no new knowledge, no new course of action
  to take, and no change in the situation. This is totally
  boring...

  If you can't imagine an interesting outcome from both results,
  then don't call for that roll. If failure is the uninteresting
  option, just give the PCs what thy want and call for a roll
  later, when you CAN think of an interesting failure. If success
  is the boring option, then see if you can turn your idea for
  failure into [a motivation for the PC to role play their
  character that way]. 

In combat things are simple. You failed a roll or you succeed at
it have immediate consequences. If you're rolling as you walk down
a hallway, what happens if you fail? You triggered a trap? But
what if you succeed? Did you just notice the trap? That's boring
because it doesn't change anything. What if the success meant you
spotted a trap that was about to affect the party behind you. Your
quick action let you spring up and grab a counterweight. Now you
have to hold it in place so the others can get across. The
challenge has changed the dynamic of the action and given the
party a reason to interact with one another. Is your character
strong enough to hold it for the whole party? What if you this
splits you up? What if you have to choose who to drop it on before
you're pulled inside the mechanism?

Anyway, I digress. Chat with your DM and talk about the rolls. Or
talk about it with the whole group. Are they into it? Maybe so.
Maybe they're just waiting for the topic to come up.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mike Tyson S Punch Out</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200223-mike-tyson-s-punch-out/</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Mike Tyson's Punch-Out
February 23rd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Years ago there was a series of videos on youtube that outlined
the deep, deep secrets and strategies of Mike Tyson's Punch-Out in
exquisite detail. The series was quite long, if memory serves.
Perhaps 10 or 12 videos in all. I remember it from the late 2000s
but it seems to have vanished from the internet completely.

In the first of the videos the author explained some of the
fundamentals. These are things we take for granted about the game
that are so basic they set up the mind for later revelations. The
first can be demonstrated by a very basic question: which punch
does more damage, left or right? Do you know? Do you think you
have an answer? Or did you, like most people, just punch whichever
was convenient and then alternate away? Would you be surprised to
learn that there is an actual benefit for choosing one over the
other. There is indeed, and it depends upon which direction your
opponent attacked from last.

The sequence of punching, whether to stay on left or right for
a series or to alternate, also changes depending on a number of
cues that are all right there in the game. There's so much at
work, such rich programming and strategy, that it's unfathomable
that it's escaped notice for so long.

What else can I tell you about? The various techniques to gain
stars, the methods of using those stars that results in opponent
reactions you've never even seen. Seriously, there's like 10
videos worth of gold that was out there!

But now it's gone. Poof. I've looked a bunch of times without any
luck. The author pulled the videos down and vanished long ago and
no manner of sleuthing has uncovered a crumb.

It's contrary to the idea we're normally presented with that once
something is on the internet it's there forever. We gopher
dwellers know the truth, though. This is all vapour and fleeting.
How much of the web was purely in Flash and completely
inaccessible now? How much was never archived in the wayback, or
was behind a login? My own earliest websites are gone. And that's
just the web! How much of gopherspace is lost to us? These
protocols, around in force since the mid 90s only, 25-30 years of
content that seems at once like everything that has ever been, and
also a flash in the pan. How long until the next technological
upheaval closes another door to our past? How long until all of
this is fleeting memory?

We are better at archiving than many here in our burrows. It's
mostly plain text, after all, and easily stored. But it's also
difficult to index, and links vanish without a clue as to where
those backup treasure troves might be. If we lose a few
cornerstones like Cameron's Floodgap, or SDF, how much goes with
it?

Anyway, I guess what I'm saying is... have any of you seen the
Punch-Out videos? I really want to watch them again.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Green Energy In Iceland</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200218-green-energy-in-iceland/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Green Energy in Iceland
February 18th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I don't complain about many things in Iceland because, frankly,
there aren't a whole lot of things to complain about. By almost
every measure, life here is superior to the United States. In
fact, the thing I'm about to complain about in this phlog is
nitpicking. The situation in the United States is worse, frankly.

What I'm talking about in green power, or carbon neutral power, or
sustainable energy, or whatever else you want to call it. You may
be aware that Iceland's grid is pretty much 100% renewable energy.
Put a period there at the end of that sentence and things feel
pretty damn good. The island has rich resources in terms of
hydroelectric power, geothermal power, and wind. You can read all
about it on this site [0].

Why Iceland - Competitively Priced Green Energy
    https://www.invest.is/why-iceland/competitively-priced-green-energy

So what's the problem then? Two things. I'll call one the lesser
evil and the other one the great lie.


The Lesser Evil

Power distribution in Iceland is not balanced between individuals
and corporations. The rates are different, their power channels
are different, and their use and the care with which is is taken
is different. In short, companies can get away with some shady
stuff. 

Is it as bad as the US? Oh hell no. After all, we're not dumping
toxic coal ash into major waterways or anything [1] here. 

Duke Energy Coal Ash in North Carolina
    https://www.newsobserver.com/news/politics-government/article238898708.html

Even so, there's some ecological impact at stake, and a misuse or
unbalanced use of public resources that favors large capitalist
enterprise without paying back into the local economy. I could go
into more detail here, but I'm just gonna leave it vague because
I really want to focus on...


The Great Lie

Iceland sells its green resources as credits that companies can
pay for to offset their own polluting behavior. If a shitty
polluter like Duke Energy wants to seem cleaner, they can pay
Iceland and claim the renewable energy as their own despite not
using it. This lowers Iceland's real contribution to the Earth in
a major way, all but removing it as a good from the world because
it allows these other companies to continue their damage while
claiming to be better.

It's a short term gain for a country that was recently in
a financial crisis. What a great way to bring in extra funds for
doing nothing, right? Except it does have a major cost to the
world as a whole.

Is this worse than what the US is doing? Well, no. The US is
actively polluting and subsidising fossil fuel industries. But
that doesn't give Iceland a pass. This country has pinned its
reputation in the world as a Green Nation while it makes back-room
deals to sell off the fruits of that labor at the cost of our
future. There are many MPs here who are working on this and
a number of other issues. Fundamental to all of these efforts is
the new constitution that was passed by public referendum years
ago but has not been ratified by the alþingi, our parliament. It's
a powerful document that returns natural resources to the public
and out of the hands of a small number of oligarchs. You can see
why it hasn't happened yet right there.

The people all want it. Many MPs want it. It will happen. These
petty corruptions that take advantage of the fisheries, of the
power systems, of plundering the Namibian fishing quotas [2], they
will all be outed. We'll get there.

Icelandic Fishing Company Engaged In Bribery, Tax Evasion, Plundering African Resources
    https://grapevine.is/news/2019/11/13/icelandic-fishing-company-engaged-in-bribery-tax-evasion-plundering-african-resources/
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>I Don T Give A Damn</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200212-i-don-t-give-a-damn/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
I don't give a damn
February 12th, 2020
----------------------------------------

I saw some posts on HN recently in the style of "Why I quit
working at Google" or "Lessons from a former Facebook Engineer".
These things pop up pretty frequently and I'd like to share my
opinion with this hidden corner of the internet that I don't give
a damn. More than that, I find the entire situation that feeds the
ego of these people despicable. Your having worked for an evil
(yes, evil) company does not put you into a special category that
warrants extra attention. It does not prove you are on some higher
level of computing prowess, for I know so many world class
intellects who know better than to soil themselves at one of these
behemoths.

So yeah, I don't give a damn.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Repair</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200203-repair/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
repair
February 03rd, 2020
----------------------------------------

Jan posted recently [0] about the awesomeness of fixing stuff. It
was timely for me since I've been on a bit of a repair renaissance
here. 

[0] jan - on fixing stuff
    gopher://jan.bio/1/phlog/20200131-on-fixing-stuff

When we moved to Iceland I knew it was going to be problematic
finding some things, especially specialty parts and quality goods.
In the midst of that dawning situation I was also staring at my
hobbies filling multiple rooms, offices, the basement and garage.
We were moving from a very large 5-bedroom home to a cozy
apartment. If I wanted to keep active on a hobby, I thought, then
it should serve a purpose and fit in our space.

I love waterproof, locking, stackable containers. I have a bunch
of the 20 gallon ones that we use in the move and in storage (no
worries about flooding!). I have smaller ones that stack and sit
on an industrial metal shelf beside my office desk. In each of
these containers is a hobby. That's the space I give them,
generally. Flutes all fit in one with the music books. All my
electronics fit in another. All my spinning tools, accessories,
and fiber in a 3rd (the wheel itself is a special exception). Our
hand-tools and sharpening stones fit in a 4th. Everything in its
place.

I also debated on bringing my 3D printer to Iceland since it
seemed extraneous and extravagant, but later decided it would be
useful to 3-D print parts that were hard to source in-country.

So now that I've been living with this stuff for 7 months, how is
it working? Well, I've done more sewing by hand here in Iceland
than I did at home with a machine and a full room dedicated to it.
I'm constantly repairing the kid's clothes, creating stuffed
animals, toys, sleeves for tools, and so on. I 3D printed sturdy
handles for our shopping bags since we walk to-and-from the market
a kilometer twice a week. My wife's chromebook's touchpad stopped
working this week and I opened it all up, cleaned everything,
re-seated leads, and it's like new. I'm even spinning wool
regularly now!

Maintaining things is a joy. Fixing them up and not wasting money
on new things means more freedom from work. We can subsist on
lower incomes and spend more time enjoying life this way. The
world has less waste. My hobbyist yearnings are itched. Life is
good.

Now if I could find a reliable tabletop RPG group, life would be
perfect!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Film A Day And Other Mental Magic</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200116-a-film-a-day-and-other-mental-magic/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
A Film A Day and other mental magic
January 16th, 2020
----------------------------------------

In the early days of the web I had a site called A Film A Day.
Why, oh, why, did the Internet Archive fail to archive it, I shall
never know. For about 5 years I kept up a practice of watching (on
average) one film per day and reviewing it. Of course I didn't
watch something every single day, so I'd bank by watching a few on
the weekends and so on. The important part wasn't getting my
yearly quota, though. I was on a mission to prove a point in an
argument I'd had at a diner.

                      Every movie is a
                      five star movie
                      if you watch it
                      the right way.

That was my angle, you see. My reviews weren't about giving
ratings to the films. It was all about figuring out how to watch
them to get the most enjoyment. I managed it, too! with a few
notable exceptions (no one can get 5 stars from Battlefield
Earth).

You need an example? Let's take the unfortunate film, Alien Vs.
Predator. What should have been a bloody affair was hamstrung by
a PG-13 rating and a setting so isolated in the arctic that
nothing really felt at stake. But... twist it in your mind and let
it become the greatest video game trailer of all time and entire
story now has purpose and drive.

Sometimes that's all it takes. Just tweak your mind a little bit
and see things from another angle and it's awesome! Other times it
takes much more work. 

I've been thinking on the Star Wars films and how I might approach
them so they're enjoyable. I think the best angle might be through
compassion. I imagine the filmmakers as a kid in high school who
adores this fandom. He eats up everything he can about the
theories and fan-fiction. He lives his life so deep in it that he
forgets there are casual fans. There are people who watched the
movies once and then moved on. There is no place left in his world
that hasn't been taken over with esoteric knowledge of this
imagined universe.

We feel a little sorry for that kid and wish he could enjoy
something else, something more. But we know, also, that he gets
such joy from this that we feel for him and want him to experience
it where he can.

And so, these other Star Wars movies are his. They are not part of
the series. They are not "real". The universe bestowed a gift upon
that nerd and let him use real actors and studios to produce his
opus of fandom. It is filled with false nostalgia and fan theories
jumbled up into a hodgepodge. It is not there to make sense. It is
not there to complete a great epic. It is a fulfillment of
a nerd's dream, and we can compassionately enjoy it with him.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Resolution</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20200101-resolution/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Resolution
January 01st, 2020
----------------------------------------

I've got a little history [0,1] of making new years resolution
posts on this phlog. I suppose I'll continue the trend. Three
years in a row makes it a tradition, wouldn't you say?

[0] Resolution (2018)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution
[1] Resolution (2019)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20181225-resolutions

In 2018 I resolved that I'd try to avoid time traps and spend time
on things that matter. I picked up a few new hobbies and did
pretty well with the effort. In 2019 I taught the phlogosphere
about my buddy's ridiculous resolutions and said that it would be
the year I was impeached. While I didn't manage to get impeached,
at least someone did.

This year I haven't really been thinking about it much, so as the
fireworks go BANG in the background I'll do some real-time
pondering. Perhaps it might be a good opportunity to affect some
sort of ridiculous word usage, like 'whilst' or 'whomst'. That's
pretty saucy, but is it resolution material? What about something
more serious and purposeful, like de-googling completely. But one
of my contract gigs uses Google apps for everything, so that's
probably out. I could pick one of my hobbies, like yarn spinning,
and set a public goal. That might be good.

I should probably start with the silliness, though. Those come to
me more easily anyway. Lets see... what's something that would be
impossible for me but is definitely attainable by SOMEONE. Hmmm...
I've got it!

2020 will be the year Taylor Swift releases an album featuring ME!

Perfect. I'll just practice my hip-hop stylings by singing my own
name over the start of her songs. This is gonna be bangin'.

As for a real resolution, I could stand to burn some weight, pray
more, eat better, walk more. That's all a constant goal, though.
It doesn't need a special new year kickoff.

I think 2020 will borrow some sentiment from 2018 and a bit from
Dune. This will be the year of my Butlerian Jihad, if you will.
I don't want the computer to be my default place to hang out. As
much as I love you guys, it's an easy trap for me here in Iceland.
I don't need to work to inculturate, practice my language skills,
or any of that jazz. I am instantly connected to everyone and it's
too easy to let that fill my day.

So there it is, my 2020 Resolution is "Thou shalt not make
a machine in the likeness of a human mind". In this case I'll use
a (very) liberal interpretation of that to mean my own mind shall
not be trapped by machines. (Yeah, yeah, I know that's not what it
means. Shuddup!)

Never fear, dear gopherites. I still work on the computer and will
surely be around plenty even with this goal. It's inevitable.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Webmentions And Microsub</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191223-webmentions-and-microsub/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
webmentions and microsub
December 23rd, 2019
----------------------------------------

This phlog is about web stuff. Specifically it's about Indyweb
things and microformats.

I use my website https://tomasino.org as an IndieAuth [0] portal.
When logging into sites that understand the IndieWeb concept,
I provide my "Home" URL as an identifier. Then the site scrubs
through all the various links I have on that page and picks out
those that it can understand for authentication. In most cases
I get GPG and GitHub hits, though occasionally a site will support
more. I oAuth in, and bam... identified. It's pretty neat and
requires very little effort on my side.

[0] IndieAuth
    https://indieauth.com/

There are much fancier IndieWeb doodads though, and I wanted to
start taking advantage of some. In particular Webmentions had
drawn my attention. It's a different way to handle commenting
that, honestly, reminds me of what we do here in gopherspace.
Instead of leaving a comment on a post somewhere, you just write
your own blog post and "notify" the original. The original page
can then choose whether to add a link to yours or ignore it or
whatever. Everyone maintains control of their own words and all is
well!

So I opened up the IndieWeb sites and went digging into
Webmentions [1]. I was immediately reminded why I abandonded this
the last time around. While the concept is incredibly simple, the
implementation is annoyingly complex and the terminology for
things is as bad as git [2].

[1] Webmentions
    https://webmention.net/
[2] Git Man Page Generator
    https://git-man-page-generator.lokaltog.net/

Since my sites are all static I wasn't looking for a plugin or
even something that automatically displayed anything on the
front-end at all. I just wanted something to process webmentions
and give me a way to see that they happened. For my low traffic
sites, a Webmention-to-Email system would have been perfect.

There are a number of things out there already. Some support the
Webmention client role and others the server because--did I not
mention this?--you need webmentions set up on both sides for it to
work. So to actually do it you need reading, writing, discovery
and parsing. There are a handful of projects doing the various
points and most of them are "in development" to varying degrees.
Almost all of them have complex esoteric documentation that only
makes sense if you're already familiar with the protocol enough to
write your own software. Lovely!

There are a few 3rd party services that offer the basics without
charge. I don't know if they work or not, but that's what I ended
up trying. I really don't want to spend the whole Christmas break
figuring this stuff out. I don't expect to get many, if any,
mentions anyway. Webmention.io is the service I went with. I used
IndieAuth to log in and then grabbed the links it gave me to paste
on my various blogs. I have no idea how to "use" Webmentions from
the other side, and no idea how to test if I'm set up correctly.

I wonder if I need to IndieAuth with the blog URL itself and then
use webmention.io directly to that property only and then repeat
the process for the other site. It says I should be able to use it
on many sites though, so hopefully it's fine. Time will tell.

Webmention.io provides a microformat feed of the mentions you
receive. I was going to grab the RSS one and plug it into my RSS
reader until I noticed the mention of this other IndieWeb format,
Microsub.

Oh joy! Another one. :D

Microsub seems like an abstraction layer above microformats that
can be interpretted as feeds or notifications. RSS and Atom are
valid inputs, but so are other bits. Like other IndieWeb things,
there's a big push to separate client & servers. In this case
I found Aperture [3] as a server and I'm using a couple different
clients to see the front-end.

[3] Aperture
    https://aperture.p3k.io/

Most of these projects are also "in development", but they seem
functional enough that I was able to dupe my tt-rss contents over.
As I mentioned in my last post [4], I'm looking for a replacement
for that software anyway so maybe this will work out.

[4] Poisoning the Well
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20191216-poisoning-the-well

Eventually I'd like to run all these services myself (though
I have no desire to write the software to do so myself). I have
nginx running on this webserver already so if I can dockerize the
bits & pieces together into an IndieWeb multi-container and
reverse proxy everything that would be perfect. For now I'm
putting a pin in it. Things are good enough.

- - - - -

Are any of you running IndieWeb goodness? Have thoughts or
suggestions? Wanna vent? Send me a mention in the lovely gopher
style!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
