<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Apple Nonsense</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20211102-apple-nonsense/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
apple nonsense
November 02nd, 2021
----------------------------------------

My son has in iPad. It's actually one that I nabbed from work when
we left the states. It's his only tech device. He uses it and
abuses it as only a kid can.

I recently picked up an iPad for work. I build sales aid things
that live on them and needed one for testing. That brought our
total apple devices in the house to two, so I figured it was time
to get us set up on the family stuff.

I was logged into both iPads with my apple ID because my kid is
a kid and didn't have his own. When I created the family thingy
I added him and now he's got his own apple identity. The only
problem is, the process didn't ask for a password creation. 

I realized yesterday that both iPads are still under my ID, so
I went to switch his to his ID and got stuck at the login screen.
I didn't have a password for him, so I followed the link to reset
it. After verifying the request via his email address and my phone
(text) Apple informed me that I'd get a note about the reset in
a few days.

In a few days?

Well I just got the email, a full day later, and I'm not
impressed. Apparently someone from Apple is going to call my phone
number on November 15th at a very specific time (quite late,
actually). That's my reset process? Seriously? Apple, the richest
company on Earth, and that's the plan?

I've never been a fan of Apple. I just don't understand the appeal
at all. Even the stuff they're supposed to be good at is utter
shit. I really wish I could go from 2 devices to 0.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Onlyfans</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210820-onlyfans/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
onlyfans
August 20th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I just heard that Onlyfans will be banning sexually-explicit
content on their network soon. Wow, just wow. The groups behind
the effort include Mastercard and by groups like Exodus Cry and
the National Center on Sexual Exploitation (NCOSE), which have
waged years-long campaigns against sex-work.

What's truly remarkable is that the site caved to this pressure
rather than seek out alternative payment options. This will
utterly destroy them, clearly, but they've gone ahead with the
decision anyway. I would love to have a bug in that board room.

Time will tell where the mass exodus of those artists will lead.
Much like the Tumblr diaspora there will likely be some time of
flux as different platforms are explored. An enterprising startup
could clearly step in here and inherit a wealth of business.

In the meantime, I'm going to do my part. Gopher Black isn't
a prude and isn't afraid of sex-work. See?


                              Boobs

                           ( • )( • )
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Talk Talk</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210625-talk-talk/</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
talk talk
June 25th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I've got a talk daemon running on cosmic.voyage. That's right, the
old one-on-one real-time chat program 'talk(1)'. In fact, I've got
ytalk(1) installed, which is even better. This morning I was
talking about talk and realized I'd never seen an RFC for it. So
I went looking...

And found nothing. There is no RFC for talk. At all. Others did
some searching too and came up with the same result. I _did_ find
some forums talking about their own search for and RFC and coming
to the same conclusion. As best I can tell, the only way to figure
out how it works is to look at the code running the clients and
the servers and work backwards. [0]

[0]Like this
    https://www.cs.columbia.edu/~hgs/internet/talk.html

So what? Well, in our little corner of internet history it seems
like quite an oversight. How did this awesome little tool get
missed. It's mentioned by name in the netequette RFC [1] and
discussed at length, but there's no implementation rules actually
codified anywhere. Wild!

[1] RFC 1855
    https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc1855

It's also a missed opportunity to breath new life into something
ancient. With a bit better documentation we could have new talk
daemons and clients in a heartbeat. Look at that first link above
and ask yourself how long it would take you to code your own today
in C or Go or Python or Lua or Perl or Forth or whatever your
party language is? We could have sexy clients and robust servers
next week. With the recent finger revival discovery of users is
super simple again in the tildeverse and other pubnixes. Layer in
some good ol' fashioned talk and now we're cooking with gas.

And hey, since there's no bloody RFC to hold us back, why not slap
some TLS on that bad-boy and make a neotalk that's secure, runs on
UDP, has full unicode support, and I dunno... washes your car?

Someone out there needs a pet project. How about this challenge:

  Write up the docs!

Seriously! As the first step to help EVERYONE else, take a tour of
search engine results, the links up above, and put together a mini
RFC-like doc on implementation. Share it around and lets see how
many new talk developments we can get this summer. The summer of
talk!

Talk Talk!
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lLdvpFIPReA
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Christyotwisty 5 Questions June 2021</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210603-re-christyotwisty-5-questions-june-2021/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: christyotwisty - 5 questions (june 2021)
June 03rd, 2021
----------------------------------------

I'm so, so happy right now. I was just wondering if there was
anything new in the phlogosphere and struck pure gold. Christy
posted a new set of questions[0] for the month. These started out
on gopher but lately she's moved them to gemini where, sadly,
I have a tendency to miss them. Not this month, though! Huzzah!

[0] christyotwisty - 5 questions
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/christyotwisty/phlog/2021-06-01.txt

So, let's see here...

1. Whom would you like to be for one day?

Oooh, good one. If I were Bezos for a day how much money could
I redistribute and how much is just tied up in stocks? I guess my
choices here are "who is using their life stupidly and me popping
in for a day could fix it?" or "who has a really interesting life
I want to experience for a day?" or "what would be totally silly?"

I'd like to be a woman for a day, I think. That would be
interesting from an experiential stand-point. Or maybe someone who
is super physically fit so I could use the body-machine to do
things I'm not normally able to do. Maybe a combo? A female rock
climber, perhaps?

2. What did you yearn for in your childhood that your parent(s) never gave you?

I think this would have been easier to answer when I was younger.
The further the distance grows the less of that sort of thing
I remember. I wanted a Sega Genesis when they bought me an NES.
I'm not upset with that, though. The NES was better for me in the
long run and I got so much joy from it. Maybe there's something
beyond the material I wanted but never got? I remember plenty of
arguments and yelling, but I can't think of anything now that has
lingered with me. Good job, parents!

3. How do you know when it's time to ask for help?

Oof, that's a hard one and I'm not great at it. Professionally
it's easier. I weigh whether it's more likely to hurt me to ask or
fail and then act. In those cases a conversation feels easy. But
there's a heavier burden when it's a private thing. I'll deal with
it for much longer than is necessary because it feels like I'm
putting a burden on others to ask for help. There's probably an
aspect of pride inside saying I should be able to do this myself,
also. I like that feeling of independence.

I guess the simple answer is, once something is going to affect
someone else I break down and ask for help. For instance a couple
months ago when I threw out my back, at first I tried to deal with
it and stretch things and shuffle around, but I quickly realized
I was a mess and couldn't function. It was inevitable that I was
going to need my wife, so I spoke up. I probably should have
raised a flag earlier when I felt things being not quite right,
though.

4. Recommend, and provide a recipe if you have one, a refreshing summer beverage.

Um, I don't have a name for it, but make an Arnold Palmer and then
add a dash of grenadine and a slice of lime. Better yet, make
sweet tea, southern style, then add in the lemonade, THEN the
grenadine. It's ridiculously sweet and probably will give you
diabetes with a single glass, but there you go.

5. Which childhood things do you still enjoy? 

I still draw. I still play video games. I like puzzles. I play
pretend (tabletop role playing games). I like to cuddle up and
watch shows. I like to explore by hiking off-trails and looking at
interesting things. I love to find a good rock. I like to sneak
away with a friend and share secrets. :)

Thank you, Christy. This was a joy.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Driving Test Take 1</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210601-driving-test-take-1/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
driving test take 1
June 01st, 2021
----------------------------------------

I took my written driving test on Monday. I did not pass.

This isn't a surprise, though. In fact, it's the norm! My wife
also failed to pass on Monday and it was her second attempt. No
one in the room passed during her first testing. Only one person
passed on the day we took it together.

Why is that? Well, it's a very hard test! The driving exam in
Iceland covers a lot more material and subject matter than
anything I saw in the United States in the various states I lived
in. It also goes into greater detail on those topics and is
incredibly pedantic. Do _you_ know the minimum mm depth tire tread
can be to pass inspection? Do you know the maximum towing capacity
for your driving license class? There are also quite a few
questions about insurance policies, the various road and safety
agencies and their roles, and even first aid.

The reason we didn't pass, though, is not just because of the
material, but the scoring itself. The test is 30 questions long
with part A being the first 15 and mainly being focused on signage
while part B is the second 15 and is focused on everything else.
You are allowed two mistakes on part A and five mistakes on part
B. Any mistakes unused on part A can be applied to part B, such
that if you had no mistakes on A you can have up to 7 on B.

But what constitutes a mistake? Ahh, here's where things get
tricky. The questions are multiple choice and you mark a mistake
for each incorrect response, not each incorrect question. Since
each question has three choices that means you can get three
mistakes per question!

In fact, that's what I did to fail mine. I got everything correct
on the test in both sections except for a single question on
section A where I misidentified a road marking, choosing option
"C" while the correct answer was "A & B". Thus, 3 mistakes on one
question and a fail.

I'll test again at the end of the month and hopefully pass this
time around. Once that's done I still have to meet with a driving
instructor, deal with their manditory lessons, and then finally be
allowed to take the behind-the-wheel portion of the exam. Yeesh!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Neovim Language Server Protocol Goodness</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210529-neovim-language-server-protocol-goodness/</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
neovim language server protocol goodness
May 29th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Yesterday was a big day for my text editor. Neovim 0.5 is about to
drop into full release and it has integrated the language server
protocol (LSP) support natively. I went ahead and grabbed it ahead
of release and spent the day resetting my config with the new
plugins that take advantage of everything.

Neovim 0.5
    https://github.com/neovim/neovim/milestone/19

Don't worry, this post isn't going to deep-dive into my config or
anything. I just wanted to say how excited I am about LSP in
general. What a fantastic idea it is to decouple the language
inspection and tooling from the editor. As someone explained it,
the programmers who use neovim to program in javascript are only
a subset of all javascript programmers. The same goes for VSCode,
or any IDE or editor. Why fragment your efforts at better
javascript tooling by focusing on the specific tool. Better to
build it as an API and let all the tools consume it.

I also went in on a thing called telescope which does what I was
using FZF to do, but with a much prettier interface. It doesn't
affect too much of my coding ability (not like LSP) but it's
aesthetically awesome and that has its place too.

Telescope.nvim
    https://github.com/nvim-telescope/telescope.nvim
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Swimming Thoughts</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210525-swimming-thoughts/</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
swimming thoughts
May 25th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I had a good time swimming this afternoon. I got into a good
headspace for the first time in months and was able to just go and
not pay attention to lap count or even time. That's a great
feeling because I can push myself further and my brain starts to
crave going more. It's the cycle of action and activity that
usually helps anchor me in overall healthier habits.

Last year I had a really good run until we started hitting
lockdowns and the pools closed. That killed my momentum and set me
back. Summer is here, though, and the mixture of the vitamin D and
physical activity is doing wonders. Soon I'll get back into hiking
in the evenings as well. (I usually swim in the morning.)

One of my favorite things to do while swimming is let my mind
wander on writing projects or role playing games. I'm running one
Pathfinder game that was the focus of today's mind wanderings.
I think I came up with two good hooks for the next session and
some excellent flavor. I'll leverage what I came up with today to
build up some scene prompts that I can toss in my box-o-tricks.
I don't want to railroad this group but instead encourage them to
have full power of choice to impact the world around them as they
see fit. It's a boring game to just say, "You're in a town, what
do you do?" however. I'll have two major hooks to draw them in
certain directions as motivation and then a collection of
narrative encounters and challenges I can mix and match to
sprinkle throughout. It'll be glorious.

I can't wait to get back underwater tomorrow and continue thinking
on it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Irc Migration</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210519-irc-migration/</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
IRC migration
May 19th, 2021
----------------------------------------

Wowza! Freenode is in meltdown. There's some major drama about
a for-profit company snaking control from under the community.
Well, the ircops revolted and all resigned and went to form a new
network at libera.chat. I've moved my few channels over there and
left freenode behind. You can find me in:

  #stutter - for my browser speed-reading add-on
  #gopher  - a more elegant weapon for a more civilized time
  #gemini  - for unofficial chat

Peace.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Re Rss</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210429-re-rss/</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
re: RSS
April 29th, 2021
----------------------------------------

sloum just wrote about RSS [0] wondering what happend to it and
why nobody links to their feeds anymore. It's a good question.
I have an RSS feed on my blog and my labs blog, but I don't have
a link in the webpage to them. The <link rel='alternate' is in
there.

[0] sloum - RSS
    gopher://circumlunar.space/0/~sloum/phlog/20210428.txt

I do publish the feed links on cosmic, but that's sort of
a byproduct of doing it on gopher where there's no link element to
do it behind the scenes. So why don't I link to them on more
sites? I think it's partially habit. Browsers just used to expose
RSS feeds and subscription buttons so naturally in the browser
interface I got used to it. When they stopped that I didn't
retroactively promote it on my pages.

Now that I'm thinking about it actively, that's pretty stupid. I'm
going to spend some time to add feed links back onto my pages
soon. The attack on RSS/Atom has been ongoing and should be fought
on all levels including individual action. Google Reader shutting
down and the major browsers removing feed reading were arguably
the biggest blows to the standard, but the efforts haven't won out
yet. Podcasts have a stronghold still and there are still plenty
of readers out there. I'll do my part.

If you want my blog & labs feed, here they are to copy/paste:

  https://blog.tomasino.org/index.xml
  https://labs.tomasino.org/index.xml

Oh, and this gopher phlog has a feed at:

  gopher://gopher.black/0/rss.xml

which you can reach via proxy or by piping it through curl if your
rss reader can't do gopher.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Python Virtualenv Invoking Without Activate</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20210426-python-virtualenv-invoking-without-activate/</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
python virtualenv invoking without activate
April 26th, 2021
----------------------------------------

I like python. I do not like python packaging. I run into the same
problem again and again: I want to make a useful tool like
'burrow' that can be distributed and used by others (or myself on
other systems). Inevitably I'll need to use other packages,
though, so I'll need to pip-install those. I don't want to pollute
the system, though, so I'd better create a virtual environment and
install those there. So now I have my requirements.txt file and
can do things inside this little container, but now what?

Do I bundle this thing and put it in pip? Am I now expecting
someone else will pip install it globally to run it on their
system? Of course not, because everything python should be safely
stored away in a virtual environment. But I don't want them to
write a program that uses my program as a library. I just want to
invoke it? Does that change the rules? Will my app's dependencies
then pollute their system?

And then I throw my hands in the air and give up and do something
else.

Well, recently I decided I wanted to work on a side-project on
cosmic that khuxkm started in python: an anonymous remailer that
actually works over email. We'd gone down this path in the past
and it almost worked. I had motivation and wanted to see it
through. Immediately I knew I was about to hit that problem from
above, though. In fact, I was going to hit it with even more
complications.

See, in order to handle incoming mail and pass it off to a script
I was using a feature of ~/.forward that lets you do that. The
.forward file works just like the aliases system file, but only on
the right-hand side of an alias definition. That means you can do
more than just specify an email or emails to deliver the mail to,
you can pipe it to a script like so:

  |/home/anonhmmst/mailhandler/parse_email.py

That leading pipe is important. It's also important to know that
scripts invoked this way are passed the contents of the incoming
mail, but invoked by the 'nobody' user. That's a security thing
and for the best, but it complicated my script running.

If I used the anonhmmst user and installed python packages for
this parse_email.py script at the user-level they wouldn't work
when invoked by nobody. I needed to set up a virtual environment
to get everything bundled, but I also needed a way to invoke it
without having to manually activate the virtual environment first.

The solution turned out to be pretty simple:
  - make the python script executable
  - point the hashbang at the virtual environment python binary

In my case:

  #!/home/anonhmmst/mailhandler/env/bin/python3

I had to do a bit more work on cosmic with the sudoers file to
enable the nobody user to run some cosmic-specific scripts, but
the virtual-environment setup was the big take-away. It doesn't
solve all my python packaging woes, but it fixed this one nicely.

What about you? What do you do in these situations? Do you pip
install binaries as your user without virtual environments for
utilities or do you wrap them in a virtual environment somehow?
How do you distribute your own projects?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
