<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Re Tfurrows Reliable Tech</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-re-tfurrows-reliable-tech/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Re: tfurrows - Reliable tech
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

First let me offer my condolences to tfurrows for the loss of
a long phlog post. [0] Your loss is also ours.

Second, let me suggest a slight modification to your workflow:
- Generate a tmp-file for authoring
- Process tmp-file in a secondary stage for formatting

If the formatting fails, you still have your temp file.

Alternatively, vim will save everything you type to a swap-file as
you type it, and preserve undo states. Come to the dark side.

[0] tfurrows - Reliablility of Tools
    gopher://sdf.org/0/users/tfurrows/phlog/2018/ajt_reliabilityOfTools.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On The Default Of Democracy</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-on-the-default-of-democracy/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
On the default of democracy
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Richard Stallman found himself in nerd-headlines today when an
article circulated on Hacker News and Lobste.rs titled "Who
Controls glibc?" [0]

[0] Who Controls glibc?
    http://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/753646/a6ebb50040c5862c/

In short, some of the maintainers of glibc attempted to remove
a comment that Stallman had added to the source in the 90s. This
comment was a reference to censorship in the form of hyperbole
about the function being named "abort". Sensationalized headlines
refer to it as a bad abortion joke, but that is clearly
a mischaracterization. Regardless of the content of the comment
itself, it was Stallman's response that created a minor
controversy.

The maintainers claim they had consensus in the community that the
comment (they refer to it as a joke) was unnecessary in the code
and should be removed. Stallman stated firmly that it will not be
removed. This created an abrupt conflict in the eyes of the
maintainers who believed that the project is community controlled.
Stallman stated unequivocally that he is the de facto decision
maker of the GNU Project, which trumps community.

Now I've previously mentioned that I'm a monarchist [1], and not
in favor of democracy as a general rule. You will therefore
understand why I inherently support Stallman's position. But lets
dive a bit deeper anyway.

[1] Confessions of a Monarchist
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180315-confessions-of-a-monarchist

The glibc maintainers are upset that Stallman, who in their eyes
is not contributing code to the project, has authority over it.
They feel that a majority rule (or at the very minimum,
a consensus of the vocal maintainers) should decide how the
project proceeds. We see this in a lot of open source projects
these days, and it's promoted in the form of community guidelines
more and more often. The struggles that happen within communities
as a result of actions against the community guidelines is often
public and brutal. In most cases it involves the ostracising of
individuals and occasionally forks in code bases. In some more
extreme cases it involves doxxing and personal attacks.

In all these cases the problem is pointed at the individual who
broke outside the line of acceptable behavior according to the
group. This is bread-and-butter stuff for democracy, especially in
the age of maximized sensitivity. Let me give you a real example:

Just a few weeks ago there was honest conversation and debate, in
some places heated, about whether or not a variable name within
the Mastodon source code should refer to the "dark web" by that
name. Never mind that the dark web is not something named by
Mastodon, the community at large converged on the idea that it was
inherently racist because it suggested some sort of evil, and by
including the name "dark" it was somehow also inferring that black
people are bad. I'm not exaggerating here. This was the actual
conversation and the community as a whole moved in the direction
of "yes, that's racist and we should rename the variable name."

There's so many things wrong with the specific argument, but I'm
not going to address them at all. Instead I'm going to focus on
the structure of community projects themselves. They are almost
always created by someone. Not some group, some one. Even when
a group is involved, there is almost always a leader, whether
defined or naturally as a part of that group. If the leader is the
ultimate decision maker, then these conflicts have an authority
which can address issues that arise. If there is no authority, the
issue must be raised to everyone. In many cases, the very act of
raising an issue to everyone is going to escalate that issue, and
once it is escalated, there's no bringing it back to Earth.

In a group which has an authority, the whims of the masses are
normalized. The fad of the day is quietly passed by and the
project avoids moving with tides of opinion. If given over to the
mob, the loudest will prevail or destroy.

Democracy's lie is that everyone gets an equal voice. This isn't
true because not everyone is equally aware and equally
understands, and has the equal background to make their equal
decision. Instead, the group relies on those who stand tall and
shout to the masses. "Rally around me!" they cry. "I understand
what needs to change." And so the democratic individual is
presented with a choice. It is not a choice born of her natural
inclination and understanding of the world, but a response to
a loud individual. This spark invites other loud individuals to
chime in and steer the conversation. Their voices are not equal
still. The ability to speak may be equal, but that is all.

(Small aside: I live next to a canal with a lot of wildlife. A fox
just managed to sneak up on a goose and it is being loudly
murdered outside my window. It's rather distracting.)

Where was I? Oh right.

Stallman is in charge of GNU. This is good. Without someone in
charge, GNU would float on the eddies of popular opinion. Instead,
it is a bulwark standing for freedom. Freedom as in liberty.
Liberty, which I've previously discussed, is diametrically opposed
to equality. Of course that's how he runs things. Any other way
would be as ridiculous as the idea of censoring a joke about the
overreach of censorship in a project dedicated to fighting fucking
censorship.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deliberate Practice</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180507-deliberate-practice/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Deliberate Practice
May 07th, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's a fantastic article circulating on the typical nerd
portals today regarding "deep work" and "deliberate practice" [0].
Give it a read if you haven't already.

[0] The Importance of Deep Work
    http://azeria-labs.com/the-importance-of-deep-work-the-30-hour-method-for-learning-a-new-skill/

One of the things I enjoyed most about the post was the summary of
methods of deep work taken from a great book on the subject [1].

[1] Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World
    http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25744928-deep-work

  Monastic: 
  "This philosophy attempts to maximize deep efforts by
  eliminating or radically minimizing shallow obligations."
  — isolate yourself for long periods of time without
  distractions; no shallow work allowed. 

  Bimodal: 
  "This philosophy asks that you divide your time, dedicating some
  clearly defined stretches to deep pursuits and leaving the rest
  open to everything else." – dedicate a few consecutive days
  (like weekends, or a Sunday, for example) for deep work only, at
  least one day a week.

  Rhythmic: 
  "This philosophy argues that the easiest way to consistently
  start deep work sessions is to transform them into a simple
  regular habit." – create a daily habit of three to four hours
  every day to perform deep work on your project.

  Journalistic: 
  "in which you fit deep work wherever you can into your
  schedule." — Not recommended to try out first, since you first
  need to accustom yourself to deep work.

This put into words a struggle I've had with my own strategies.
I've tried dedicating a set amount of time, sort of like "Rythmic"
but that time hasn't been long enough to establish a deep work
flow. I've set aside days of the week for it like Bimodal, but
rarely with the isolation necessary to really dig in. Occasionally
I'm successful, but I think it's more to do with luck, or
a motivation I happened to find that day, than any deliberatet
planning.

In the past I've spoken about freezing up when an opportunity for
exploration appears [2]. I'm combatting that with organization of
lists so I can refer back to these projects I have moving and
I don't waste time spinning my wheels. All of it is a part of the
effort to get back the time that should belong to me that I give
away out of a combination of laziness and poor planning [3].

[2] Stuck
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180501-stuck
[3] Resolution
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180101-resolution

Ultimately, there are skills I want to improve. The top of that
list are my writing craft and the Shakuhachi [4]. In reality the
list is quite a bit longer. Even so, I have the ability, I have
the time, and I have the necessary components to make a go of it.

[4] Shakuhachi (UTF-8)
    gopher://gopher.black/1/explorations/shakuhachi

Deliberate practice, not just sitting around fiddling with crap,
is the difference I'm missing. I've told it to my son a lot, and
I'll continue to do so in the future. You can't just go along with
things and expect to learn and grow. You need to do the hard
things [5]. When I practice with the Shakuhachi, I can't just go
sit on the porch and play improvisations for twenty minutes.
I have specific things I need to improve: timing, embouchure,
breathing dynamics. My writing is the same. I'm working on
a writing exercise and I've given myself a specific goal to focus
on brevity. This is good.

[1] Do the Hard Thing
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20171108-do-the-hard-thing

It's not just about doing things with my hobby time. It's work in
itself and I need to commit to it, at least a significant portion
of the time, if I want to improve.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fbi Files</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180505-fbi-files/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
FBI Files
May 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I was sorting through some of my bookmarks tonight and I ran
across something that I pinned for myself and completely forgot
about. It's a site called "Get My FBI File". [0]

[0] Get My FBI File
    http://getmyfbifile.com/

It's a simple form that generates you a bunch of letters that you
can print off and mail in under the Freedom of Information Act to
request government agency files on you. (The FAQ states you can
send the requests even if you aren't a US citizen, with a few
modifications).

I filled out all of them and will drop them in the mail Monday
morning. I doubt there's much in those files on me, if anything,
but I just don't know for sure. That's enough reason in itself to
send the requests.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Minor Writing Update</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180504-minor-writing-update/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Minor writing update
May 04th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I managed to add a bit more to my "storymatic" [0] writing
exercise. For those that missed that one, it's a thing where
I draw some cards out of a box that give me an idea for
a character and a story hook and I write a short story from there.
It's your typical writing prompt deal, but it's all fancy and
randomized. 

Swing over and check it out if you're in the mood. [1] I think
I like how this one is turning out. I need to decide how I want to
wrap it up.

I've also been re-reading where I left off with Emergence [2].
I may insert some other content before the current chapter three.
I think the revelations in that chapter came too soon and I have
more to add before it happens.

I'm glad to feel the writing itch come back.

[0] phlog - storymatic
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180304-storymatic
[1] story - storymatic 0001
    gopher://gopher.black/0/writing/exercises/storymatic0001.txt
[2] story - emergence
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/emergence
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Games We Play</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180501-the-games-we-play/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The games we play
May 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

There's been a lot of people talking recently about games they're
playing, whether on the computer, board game, or pencil-based
RPGs. It's been really inspiring.

I love RPGs so much, and I'm happy that I've got a monthly game
going with a local crew. We're playing online with Discord and
Roll20.net and it's... fair. I prefer no electronics involved in
my table-top, and everyone around the same table. Still, I'll take
what I can get.

At work I spent a little bit of my team-building budget to buy
a couple board games. Charterstone, a fancy new legacy game, and
a casual game called Lattice are the first purchases. I'll report
back on how they work soon.

I've also been thinking about other games I play or have played
with my friends over the years. Some are easily categorized, like
the D&D campaigns I've run or played in. Others are hard to pin
down, like the De Profundis writing-game I've got here on
gopher.black [0].

[0] De Profundis
    gopher://gopher.black/1/writing/deprofundis

This is a game of sorts, but it's also collaborative writing. It
started with the first letter when I wrote it in an email to my
friend Dan. I didn't give much explanation other than, "you get to
write from the other side and move the story along." We don't
communicate about our plans for each letter and we can introduce
characters as we see fit. We meticulously research historical
locations and events to prepare each one, and try to keep to the
style of the time as best as we're able. Dan's got the next letter
coming my way soon and I'm thrilled.

My game experience isn't all table-top or computer based, of
course. When I was a teen in Boy Scouts we did a lot of
night-gaming. Usually it was something akin to capture the flag,
or a moderately violent hide-and-seek variant we called Man Hunt.
My favorite thing was what I called "Flee-running". If you're
familiar with Free Running or Parkour, it's more in line with the
latter. It wasn't about flourishes, but rather about getting from
point A to point B as efficiently as possible. The only difference
was, you were being chased. It's a combination of tag & parkour
usually played deep in the woods, often in the dark. It's skill
based only so much as it takes a lot of skill not to stop running
when you take a branch to the face in the middle of the night. It
was so thrilling, though. I've lept from cabin roofs, tarzan'd
across creeks, and jumped through windows. So dangerous, and so
fun.

We also had really stupid high school games. There's one that
I picked up on in college that started from a friend's high school
time. It's really simple, if someone says the word "bogwan" you
have to freeze exactly where you are in the position you're in for
thirty seconds. If it's dangerous or whatever, then you don't...
but once you're clear of danger you have to freeze. It was mostly
used to emphasize some stupid expression you were making at the
time. Make some embarrasing face and you're bound to be bogwan'd.
It's still active and on rare occasion I'll get a bogwan text from
that crew.

There's so many other stupid games from that time. A lot of them
involve getting punched in the balls, for some reason. High school
again, I guess.

Board games are coming back into my life again which is great.
I've got one RPG going and will likely run a Numenera game
sometime in the next year. I'm doing a retro-gaming playthrough of
the complete Zelda franchise and occasionally twitch stream it.
I'm 8bitino on Twitch, but I rarely go on. I'm about halfway
through Zelda II: The Adventure of Link. It's hard! Next up will
be the Game Boy games, and I'm really excited.

I also am in a slow retro-playthrough of the Quest for Glory
series. I rocked QFG1 in style on Twitch not too long ago. I have
my saved character for QFG2, but I'm going to restart it now that
I found a VGA version. The most exciting thing about this
playthrough is that I've never played QFG5. I stopped at #4 and
loved it so much, but 5 came out after I'd moved on to other
things. EEEk, so much fun!

In a future post I'd like to cover off on some of the RPG
campaigns I've run in the past. The Assassini is probably my best
one, so I think I'll start there. 

Assassini

Setting: 1716 Paris 

Mission: Two agents of the Catholic Church, armed with Papal
dispensation, have been dispatched to undermine the political
power in the region, uncover a religious mystery, and combat
agents of the British Crown who seek to disrupt their plans.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Stuck</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180501-stuck/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Stuck
May 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

I've been sitting at my desk for 20 minutes tabbing back and forth
between virtual desktops, tmux sessions/windows/panes, weechat
channels, etc. I feel like I had something I wanted to do, or
maybe say, but I can't remember what it is. It's paralyzing me.

I have 30,000 things I could be doing right now but my inability
to remember this one specific thing has me stuck. Stupid brain.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Proper Mirroring</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180429-proper-mirroring/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Proper mirroring
April 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

A few folks were kind enough to let me know that my recent
experiments with tor [0][1] broke my gopher hole mirrored on SDF
and tilde.town. In reality, those mirrors weren't all that useful
in the first place. All the links in my gophermaps to internal
resources were using full, complete hostnames & ports. Thus, if
you went to SDF, after link #1 you were really over on
gopher.black anyway.

[0] gopher.black on tor, part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-gopher-black-on-tor-part-1
[1] gopher.black on tor, part 2
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180428-gopher-black-on-tor-part-2

This wasn't ideal, but it was low priority. It worked well enough,
right? When I removed the explicit hostname & port info from
gophermaps to allow my dual server goodness for tor, suddenly SDF
and tilde.town thought that my links were legitimately local.
There was just one problem... my content paths are different on
all three systems.

On gopher.black, / is mine. Everything starts there.
On SDF, /users/tomasino is mine.
On tilde.town, /~tomasino is mine

The fix didn't take a ton of work since I already had a pretty
solid foundation for mirroring the content. I have a local copy of
my gopher git repo on those boxes and a cron-job that pulls it
four times a day. Simple! Well, now I have a little extra goodness
in there.

The update process looks like so:

  - Fetch the remote
  - Check the SHA of the latest commit in HEAD vs origin/master
  - If different:
    - force reset the local head
    - pull origin/master
    - find all gophermaps and use sed to replace root paths
    - touch the local folder (for SDF's phlog list)

Here's the code [2]:
[2] sdf-update-gopher
    http://gist.github.com/jamestomasino/8241f9e3daf2a0fa49e5a9d35679a427

It's not the cleanest. I could remove the pushd/popd stuff. It's
legacy from a much more complex process time. The sed command is
cumbersome as well. I could have matched \t/[^\t]*$ instead, but
it works. So, like most of my stuff... good enough.

A final note:

Moku Pona & my reading lists are local cron tasks on gopher.black
that update quite often. To avoid a bajillion commits to my gopher
repo I don't include them at all. That means my moku-pona list and
reading lists are not available on SDF or tilde.town. All the rest
of the goods are there, though.

Enjoy & stuff!
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gdpr</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180429-gdpr/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
GDPR
April 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

******************************************************************
******************************************************************
******************************************************************
***                                                            ***
***                       N O T I C E                          ***
***                           O F                              ***
***                         G D P R                            ***
***                 C O M P L I A N C E (1)                    ***
***                                                            ***
******************************************************************
******************************************************************
******************************************************************

1. Because Gopher
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gopher Black On Tor Part 2</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180428-gopher-black-on-tor-part-2/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
gopher.black on tor, part 2
April 28th, 2018
----------------------------------------

This gopher site is finally available as a tor hidden service with
the production onion address: blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion [0]

[0] gopher.black (tor)
    gopher://blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion/1/

In my last post [1] I mentioned three problems I had left:
[1] gopher.black on tor, part 1
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180427-gopher-black-on-tor-part-1

1) Ugly onion addresses
2) Internal links kick you out of tor
3) Port 71

Here's how that got resolved.

I used Eschalot to generate my onion address. I let the app run
a full day trying to get something that started with gopherblack,
but the pattern was too long to find a match. I figure "black" is
good enough for folks to remember. I had about
15 different ones starting with black, but this had the best
looking pattern.

I ended up installing Gophernicus as a second gopher server next
to motsognir and configured it to serve up my same content. This
install was a tiny bit tricky since I already have a service
listenining on port 70. I also wanted Gophernicus to use my tor
address, not my actual hostname. Finally, I wanted it to run on
port 71, but act like links were still port 70. Doing all this
involved changing 3 files in the repo before I ran make install:

  gophernicus.env

  Uncomment options and give it the onion host and whatever else
  is necessary to your liking: 
  
    OPTIONS="-h blackgviz2y4nhrd.onion -nf -nt"


  gophernicus.socket

  Change port to listen on to 71 or 1138 or whatever you'll be
  using with the tor proxy.


  gophernicus@.service

  There's a line in there that looks like this:

    ExecStart=/usr/sbin/in.gophernicus -h %H $OPTIONS

  Remove the -h %H bit. We set that in options.

Now you can 'sudo make install' and it should "Just Work".
Remember to update your torrc to use port 70 and proxy to 71. This
will give you your content back on port 70 over tor and all will
be good in the world.

The last hurdle to fix were the internal links. My sexy burrow
helper wants to be a good partner, so it generates gophermaps with
full \tHOST\tPORT\r\n line endings. That's overkill for motsognir
and gophernicus, and doesn't allow them the flexibility to add
those bits itself. 

On Motsognir I can exclude the full line ending as long as
I prefix the line with type "i" and it will work.

On Gophernicus I can get rid of any type at the start of the line
and it will work.

To make both happy I need to include the type "i" at the start of
the line and add a single tab character at the end. Not two tabs
or three, just exactly one with nothing after it. This makes both
servers happy and lets them fill in the gaps.

I'll need to add a switch to burrow to generate this style in the
future, but in the meantime I can manually clean it up as I add
posts.

find . -name "gophermap" -exec sed -i 's/\tgopher.black.*//g' {} \;
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
