<?xml version="1.0"?><rss version="2.0"><channel>
<title>gopher.black</title>
<link>gopher://gopher.black/</link>
<description>Tomasino's Gopher Hole</description>
<item>
  <title>Space Gopher 2000</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180705-space-gopher-2000/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Space Gopher 2000
July 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

What if quantum entaglement and spooky action at a distance allow
for us to create extremely long range connections, but with very
low bandwidth. "Why would that be the case?" you might ask.
Frankly, I have no idea. If you don't think about the details too
much it seems like something you could gloss over in a story,
though.

I want to explore that idea in a short story as a vehicle to
reintroduce gopher as the web of the space-future. No nonsense,
text driven communication across vast spaces would make for an
incredible aesthetic and a great reason to draw some attention
back to port 70.

I think of films like Alien and their use of text for
communication and it makes sense to me. Local running AIs and
super-powerful UI crap is neat, but for anything at a distance we
fall back on the age-old safety of text. If you imagine a universe
populated by ships launched and traveling at relativistic speeds,
we quickly encounter vast distances in relative time, not only
space. These time gaps are a bigger threat to communication than
distance. We cannot innovate because it leaves behind all those
that have gone out before. We cannot shift paradigms. We must
speak to a common level.

Isn't that a cool thought? I want to read stuff in that universe.
I want gopher featured prominantly. I guess I should start working
on it at some point.

Do any of you have any ideas to pile on top? I don't have a story
here at all, just setting, so I could use all the help I can get.
Or, I guess if one of you is feeling the creative juices flowing,
take it and run. I want to read it more than I want to write it.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Myths And Truth</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180705-myths-and-truth/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Myths and truth
July 05th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Joseph Campbell was fond of saying that all myths are true. His
line of thinking is that the myths we know and that our societies
have developed are culturally dependant expressions of a universal
story. 

In comparative mythology or comparative religion we see the same
aspects echoed across time and space. In his mind there were two
possible reasons why:

  1. There are similarities in human psychology and physiology
     that lead us to generate the same responses to our
     experiences regardless of culture and climate.

  2. There is a shared truth which all of our myths and symbols
     help us to express. That expression is unique to our culture
     but it speaks to a universal truth which itself is ineffable.

That is a tragically simplified summary, but it should do for my
purposes as there's only a small point I'd like to make regarding
myths. 

  Myths are not true, they reveal truth.

When Catholics look at the bible and read the story of creation,
that story is a myth [0]. It is not literal. It is there to teach
us something about creation in language and stories that make
sense to the culture of the time. This reading with a cultural
lens is vital to a Catholic reading of scripture, even the
Gospels.

[0] Genesis 1
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Genesis/genesis-1.txt

In the book of Luke [1], there is a passage that should be
familiar to even the most lapsed of Christians. It is the story of
Mary and Joseph arriving in Bethlehem for the birth of Jesus:

  In those days a decree went out from Caesar Augustus that all
  the world should be registered. This was the first registration
  when Quirinius was governor of Syria. And all went to be
  registered, each to his own town. And Joseph also went up from
  Galilee, from the town of Nazareth, to Judea, to the city of
  David, which is called Bethlehem, because he was of the house
  and lineage of David, to be registered with Mary, his betrothed,
  who was with child. And while they were there, the time came for
  her to give birth. And she gave birth to her firstborn son and
  wrapped him in swaddling cloths and laid him in a manger,
  because there was no place for them in the inn. [1]

[1] Luke 2
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Luke/luke-2.txt

I want to focus on just two phrases in this paragraph:

  "he was of the house and lineage of David"

  and

  "laid him in a manger, because there was no place for them in
  the inn."

Starting with the first phrase, this is an important note for
a few reasons, biblically. It touches on prophecy fulfillment
because it satisfies the messianic idea that the figure will come
from the house of David. It is also important because of the
political implications of the house itself. The house of David was
the most prestigious of the Jewish people, after all. Heading to
the ancestral home of that people is a big deal in a culture
dominated by family value. This is a key point to remember in the
story, too. Mary and Joseph aren't going to some small town in the
middle of nowhere. They're going to the home of the wealthiest,
most prestigious family. The people of the house of David would be
many. This is not a land of strangers for them.

It's also important to remember that for these people at the time
there is a great emphasis put on the idea of hospitality. Elijah
is going to return, and they must be ready. He may come in the
guise of a beggar to your door. And so, welcoming in the traveler
has a major role in daily life. It has such a role, that it even
affected the architecture of first century Palestine.

The typical home at the time was made up of two main rooms. The
first was the family's room. It would be raised up off the ground
a few feet and be all open. On one side there would be a ledge
that drops down to ground level as the room extends into the
animal enclosure. The animals would stay inside in poor weather or
seasons, and their heat would be shared by the family. On the
floor by this ledge were impressions in the ground where feed was
placed: the manger.

The second room was attached, often with a separate entrance. This
was the guest house or reception room, and it was intended for
visitors and extended family. We see such a room referenced twice
in the bible by the Greek word kataluma. A kataluma is the room
used by Jesus and his disciples during the last supper. It is also
the word used in this paragraph and translated as "inn".

In the ancient world there were no hotels. The closest you might
find was a tent filled with straw mats, called a caravansary. This
word was translated to "inn" during the story of the good
Samaritan. When the man is injured and placed in the inn for care,
that was a caravansary. In Luke we're talking about a very
different thing.

Taken together with our understanding of Jewish culture and the
importance of the family of David, it is inconceivable to imagine
the holy family alone in a barn on that first Christmas. The
kataluma was full, so they were instead brought into the family
room in communion with many others. When the child was born he was
placed there in the manger where all could see him.

So why do I bring this up? It isn't to criticize those poor
Christmas pageants. It's to talk about the myths.

The story of Jesus birth is not vital to the story of his teaching
or his role within the faith. If Jesus is born in the midst of the
most powerful Jewish family instead of alone in a barn, there's no
fundamental truth being assaulted. In fact, if you spent your
entire life believing one idea vs the other idea, it would have
almost no bearing on your understanding of Jesus at all. Does that
mean it doesn't matter? Does that suggest that a bunch of these
stories are filler and don't have an impact on us? Well, no, not
exactly.

The stories, the myths, and our comprehension of them are trying
to tell us something, but it's almost never the literal histories.
Here in the story of Christ's birth we are being made to
understand his place in the culture of the Jewish people, and his
relationship to the prophets that came before him. In this way we
can understand that he is legitimate. His role is appropriate.
He's not just some guy who found a bunch of metal plates in his
backyard [2].

[2] Problems with the gold plates
    http://www.equip.org/article/problems-with-the-gold-plates-of-the-book-of-mormon-2/

Each myth is meant to communicate something to us that words alone
can't. They are intricately tied to the culture of their creation,
and when that culture changes so must the myths. Without this
change they become distance, misaligned, and misconstrued. Before
you know it you are taking words from Leviticus and applying them
to a whole different world.

  As for your male and female slaves whom you may have: you may
  buy male and female slaves from among the nations that are
  around you. [3]

[3] Leviticus 25
    gopher://gopher.black/0/bible/Leviticus/leviticus-25.txt

Whether we're looking at stories of the Buddha or Brahman,
Gicelemû’kaong or Birrahgnooloo, the myths create and communicate
our understanding of their truth. The myths are not the truth, but
they are true, all of them. 
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Essence Of Gopher</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180703-the-essence-of-gopher/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
The essence of gopher
July 03rd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Our dear friend cat is at it again. He recently flew the coop
from SDF and has planted his seed in a new project called
baud.baby [0]. He's a resourceful guy and has quickly conquered
some of the more tedious aspects of getting your own gopher hole
up and running. Kudos, cat!

[0] baud.baby
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20180628.txt

His most recent phlog touches on one of his passions, vintage
phones [1]. In my humble opinion it is EVERYTHING that gopher
should be summed up into a microcosm of aussie geekdom. It has
passion for a vintage technology, collection, curation, more
technical details than you could have imagined, and a neverending
thirst for more. It's also beautiful. His manual text layouts
really shine on things like his phone collection page [2].

[1] A bunch of Touchfone stuff
    gopher://baud.baby/0/phlog/fs20180703.txt
[2] Weirdly Specific Collection of Phones
    gopher://baud.baby/1/phones

I've run across similarly brilliant curation in places like
mateusz's DOS software repository [3], or Logout's new ASCII table
[4], or dbucklin's intelligence analysis documents [5]. This stuff
is gopher gold. 

[3] mateusz's DOS software repository
    gopher://gopher.viste.fr/1/abandonware
[4] Logout's ASCII table
    gopher://i-logout.cz/1/en/ascii
[5] dbucklin's Intelligence Analysis Documents
    gopher://sdf.org/1/users/dbucklin/files

I've been really phlog focused in the past, but I think that
overlooked some of the best stuff around. Now I'm finally starting
to add more links to these collections and repositories over on my
Gopher Places [6] section. Check it out and discover some awesome.

[6] Gopher Places
    gopher://gopher.black/1/places
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why I Use Gophermaps</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180701-why-i-use-gophermaps/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Why I use Gophermaps
July 01st, 2018
----------------------------------------

maiki just asked why I use gophermaps for my phlog instead of
plain text. I know others at bitreich [0] have commented on the
practice with various opinions on why "misusing" gophermaps is
bad. Plenty of people on gopher use plain text for their content
and I am not going to complain. My choice is a product of style
and philosophy.

Style:

One of the best things about hypertext is the ability to link
contextually to relevant content. Gopher is missing this to
a degree, but not entirely. We can't link a block of text inline
like in HTML but we can link a line. That functionality is
entirely limited to gophermaps, though. Without the gophermap the
best we can do is include a text link and rely on the client to go
above and beyond the protocol to enable interaction (like VF-1 so
valiantly does).

My choice, stylistically, was to take it upon myself to do
a little extra work and build in the links directly into the
content by making my phlogs a gophermap. I first announced this
change [1] back in October of 2017 when I was still relatively new
at this whole thing. In fact, I was piggybacking on the very
bare-bones shell scripts that would later become burrow [2]. My
first iteration was just a bunch of echo commands to a blank file
and then launching vim [3]. These days I have the ability to edit
existing phlog entries, generate in plain text or gophermaps,
auto-generate RSS, and a bunch of other crap.

Philosophy:

From what I've seen over my time on gopher the biggest complaint
about gophermaps for content isn't about the effort involved in
creating them. Instead it's an argument for purity in the
protocol. "Don't use the 'i' item type for this sort of thing,"
they say. "The 'i' type isn't even in RFC 1436!" And it's true.
The type isn't defined in 1436, and it definitely isn't pure
gopher as envisioned in the two-week sprint that a bunch of guys
at the University of Minnesota did as much to stick it to the man
(their school beauracracy) as they did to just get something out
there for the community to react to.

See, I don't see that as something to protect through purity. The
mindset of those guys was to iterate, to share, to build, and to
make the internet better. They didn't sit for years in planning
before deploying the end-all-be-all of protocols. They cobbled
together some crap on top of existing tools and made improvements.
And that's what type "i" did later. It enabled us to write more
description than would fit on one line so there was context to
a link.

That's what I see myself doing when I phlog. The links below (and
now sometimes in-line) are given context by my post. If you're
reading and say, "hey, I should check that out!" now you can. You
just follow the link and boom, there you are.

For those folks who don't bother with it and post in plain text,
if I really want to chase down a link I can select it and manually
enter it. It's more difficult, but it's doable. I hold no grudge
against them for their choice.

If you are new to gopher and just want to toss up markdown files
that you're also using to generate a web version, go for it. I'll
be more happy that you've decided to add content here than
anything else. I'm certainly not going to berate your efforts by
nit-picking on whether you use type 1 or type 0. 

[0] bitreich.org
    gopher://bitreich.org/1/
[1] New Format Test
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20171003-new-format-test
[2] burrow
    http://gitlab.com/jamestomasino/burrow
[0] This is amazeballs
    gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/20170817-this-is-amazeballs.txt
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Cli Tricks Sc Im</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180629-cli-tricks-sc-im/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
CLI Tricks: sc-im
June 29th, 2018
----------------------------------------

SC-IM - Spreadsheet Calculator Improvised

A vim-like modal editor for spreadsheets in the terminal (ncurses)

It supports the following formats:
 
  .sc     SC-IM's native text format
  .xls    Microsoft Excel Spreadsheet
  .xlsx   Microsoft Office Open XML Workbook
  .csv    Comma-separated values
  .tsv    Tab-separated values
  .tab    Tab-separated values
  .txt    Simple text files

It has an impressive set of features (from the README)!

  UNDO / REDO.
  65.536 rows and 702 columns supported. (The number of rows can
     be expanded to 1.048.576 if wished).
  CSV / TAB delimited / XLSX file import and export.
  Scripting support with LUA. Also with triggers and c dynamic
  linked modules.
  Clipboard support.
  GNUPlot interaction.
  Key-mappings.
  Sort of rows.
  Filter of rows.
  Subtotals.
  Cell shifting.
  256 color support - screen colors can be customized by user,
      even at runtime.
  Colorize cells or give them format such as bold or underline.
  Wide character support. The following alphabets are supported:
      English, Spanish, French, Italian, German, Portuguese, 
      Russian, Ukrainian, Greek, Turkish, Czech, Japanese, Chinese.
  Autobackup.
  Implement external functions in the language you prefer and use
      them in SC-IM.
  Use SC-IM as a non-interactive calculator, reading its input 
      from a external script.
  More movements commands implemented !
  Input and Output was completely rewritten.

It's a breeze to install on MacOS or Linux. Give it a shot.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Federation And Gopher</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180627-federation-and-gopher/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Federation and gopher
June 27th, 2018
----------------------------------------

Some of you guys were talking about a "federated gopher" on
Mastodon the other day. At first I was all into the idea and
getting ready to chime in with support. But then I started
thinking about what that would mean and I hit a wall. I think my
understanding of federation in recent context has skewed away from
the community idea. With all the work on ActivityPub and the new
clients popping up in the Fediverse I feel like I should probably
spend the time to figure out what it is everyone is talking about
when they use the word Federated.

Since we're talking definitions here, I figured I should start by
telneting to my happy dictionary [0] that I described in an old
phlog post [1]. Then I ran my query: "define english federation".
Here's what popped out:

  <security> The establishment of some or all of business
  agreements, {cryptographic} trust and user identifiers or
  attributes across security and policy domains to enable more
  seamless business interaction.

  As {web services} promise to enable integration between
  business partners through {loose coupling} at the application
  and messaging layer, federation does so at the identity
  management layer, insulating each domain from the details of
  the others' authentication and authorization.  Key to this
  loose coupling at the identity management layer are
  standardized mechanisms and formats for the communication of
  identity information between the domains.  {SAML} is one such
  standard.

From the sound of that definition, gopher is already federated in
that identity information between domains is inherent to the
protocol because it's irrelevant. There's no authorized use
mechanism here and the act of hosting content on a server is
enough to identify the source. Since I host on gopher.black, if
your use of gopher queries my server you have used standard
mechanisms and formats for the communication of that information
between the domains, right?

Maybe the reason I'm having such difficulty is because my only
exposure to federation as an idea has been via things like
Mastodon which have far more interoperable parts. Content from one
independent system is consumed and becomes content within another
one, and the source of that content, the author, server, etc, all
need to be accounted for in the communication. That requires more
than gopher for sure.

Even so, I'm not satisfied. I think there's more to federation
than that definition. The context in how people discuss it seems
to imply something else, but I can't put my finger on exactly what
that might be. Distributed systems like IPFS come up a lot in
those discussions, but I don't see a black & white relationship.

I guess my slow brainmeats can't get past the idea that federation
means I control my shiz but it can interact with everyone elses
shiz in the same way. Am I so far off? Let me know with a reply or
email or mastodon or a hand written letter.

Yes! Hand written letters are my absolute favorite. They
demonstrate all that extra effort, they're physical treasures, and
I get to silently judge your personality through bullshit
handwriting interpretation that I make up on the spot. Everyone
wins! Send me an note with a reference to a pgp key and I'll send
you back my mailing address on the down-low.

Cheers, fedi-gophers

8[0] Telnet to dict.org	dict	dict.org	2628
[1] CLI Tricks: Dictionaries
    gopher://gopher.black/1/phlog/20180405-cli-tricks-dictionaries
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Modafinil And Ketosis</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180626-modafinil-and-ketosis/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Modafinil and Ketosis
June 26th, 2018
----------------------------------------

 Ketosis
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Ketosis

Ketosis is a metabolic state in which some of the body's energy
supply comes from ketone bodies in the blood, in contrast to
a state of glycolysis in which blood glucose provides energy.
Generally, ketosis occurs when the body is metabolizing fat at
a high rate and converting fatty acids into ketones.

 Modafinil
    gopher://gopherpedia.com/0/Modafinil

Modafinil is a medication to treat sleepiness due to narcolepsy,
shift work sleep disorder, or obstructive sleep apnea (OSA). While
it has seen off-label use as a purported cognitive enhancer,
evidence for any benefit is lacking.

Common side effects include headache, anxiety, trouble sleeping,
and nausea.

   -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  - 

As mentioned previously in my phlog, I eat a ketogenic diet in
order to stay in a state of nutritional ketosis (a blood
concentration of β-hydroxybutyrate ketones in the range of 0.5-3.5
millomolar). Eating this way and staying in ketosis gives me
a number of benefits:

  - Less hunger
  - Easy avoidance of sugary foods
  - Easy intermittent fasting
  - Even energy levels throughout the day (no afternoon crash)
  - Smoother, healthier skin (eczema goes away)
  - Less inflamation in my joints
  - Lower incidence of restless leg syndrome
  - Increased mental clarity
  - Lots of sexy food-porn on my Instagram
  - Ability to talk about my diet for hours an annoy coworkers
  - Easier weight loss

In order to stay properly in ketosis and avoid the normal pitfalls
I need to eat and drink a certain way. In short:

  - Manage my macronutrients:
    - Eat less than 20 grams of net carbs per day
    - Hit my protein goal (~100 grams)
    - Eat fat only until feeling sated

  - Manage my micronutrients:
    - Eat between 3-5 grams of sodium (yes, that's a lot)
    - Eat at least 2 grams of potassium
    - Get enough magnesium to avoid sleep and heart issues
    - Otherwise make sure to hit my normal dietary needs for
      vitamins & minerals

If I do those things, ketosis happens. It's that simple. I don't
bother to log anything in a food tracker anymore because it's
become so intuitive. Huzzah!

I also occasionally take the drug modafinil as a cognative
enhancer when I need to GET SHIT DONE. Based on my current supply,
last order, and a bit of math I average 1 dose every 3 weeks. Not
too shabby, if I do say so myself. In the past I've had stretches
where I've found it helpful to take more, and I've had holidays
from it where I forget I even have it.

The effects of modafinil are interesting. If I were to boil it
down to the essence I would say it increases your ability to focus
and quickly manage task-switching. A side benefit of that focus is
that I seem to have more motivation to do the tasks in front of
me. I can juggle more projects and input at once. Writing is
smoother and more efficient, and often much longer than it would
be otherwise. If I have a pile of work that really needs my full
attention and I want to tear through it with gusto, that's when
I'll pop the pill. 

Its primary purpose was for use by the military to enable high
congnative functioning without sleep. It does that very well. If
I take a pill anytime after 9am, I will not get to sleep before
1am. It is very easy to pop one in the afternoon and coast on
through the night without noticing. I don't use it that way, but
many others do. I generally wake up early on days I plan to take
a pill and pop it around 6am, then get to work.

Since it functions in similar ways to caffiene, I've found it's
best for me to avoid coffee while "modded up". It triggers anxiety
in me which is detrimental to GETTING SHIT DONE. Modafinil also
makes it easy to forget about food and drink. It's an appetite
suppresant and your focus on work can distract you from healthy
habits like drinking water. This is a big mistake, too. Modafinil
will crush your brain with suck if you don't drink a crapload of
water. Headache central over here.

Since I need a lot of water for ketosis and also for modafinil
I made sure to focus on that today while I was doing both. So far
I'm sharp as a tack, motivated, and clear of headaches. The
effects of mental clarity from modafinil and ketosis do seem to
stack somewhat. All in all, they seem well suited to one another.

Now I'm off to drink another liter of water to keep it that way.


</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Solar Hydroponics</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180624-solar-hydroponics/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Solar Hydroponics
June 24th, 2018
----------------------------------------

I'm doing some mental planning toward a very small hydroponics
experiment. I will likely start with just one plant, an herb, in
a solo environment. I know I can do a self-contained system
without aeration at that scale, but I want to build it as if it
were a larger system, but in miniature. I want the system to be
off-grid as well. I'd like it to be as mechanical as possible, in
fact.

I found one little video oh a solar radiation powered aerator.
Basically, it was an empty air chamber that was darkly colored and
had no-return valves that forced air in one hole only and out
through the "pump". The out-bound port was covered in a bubbler
rock. When the sun hit the bottle it heated the air inside, which
forced the air forward out into the reservoir. When the bottle
cooled it would draw more air back in through the outer valve. If
the sun cycled exposure at a fairly regular interval, it seems
like it might help circulate some into the reservoir over time.

There were lots of problems with it, of course. The pressure of
the temperature change didn't create that much air flow. If the
light were fairly constant it would only expel once and then be at
rest. It needs some work to draw and billow more air. I was
thinking about having a radiometer inside the chamber, as air flow
inside would force it to work as a more continuous air pump, but
I think those barely create enough force to spin in a vacuum. I'm
close to a solve here that does not involve electronics at all,
but I'm just not quite there.

Once that's fixed, my next line of inquiry will be nutrients. What
exactly goes into those fertilizer bits and how can I generate my
own source without a store. Is that even a reasonable thing to do?

If I can solve for solar powered aeration (not using solar panels
& electronics) and nutrient creation, then I should be able to
construct a fully off-grid, automated hydroponics rig. I am just
awful at remembering to do things on a regular basis, so if this
is to succeed I absolutely must automate.

Other things to consider:

- Auto-balancing water distribution to the correct levels
- Rotation / cycling position for sun exposure
- Portability of net systems for transferring between small
  & larger rigs
- Auto-timing of nutrient injection & mixing

Do any of you have experience in hydroponics? Anything to add?
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Weight Update</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180622-weight-update/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Weight update
June 22nd, 2018
----------------------------------------

Quick note today to mark my 40lbs loss milestone. I'm feeling
great and need to stick with it forever and ever. Addicition has
never been a part of my personality, but I'm coming to accept that
I need to treat carbs the way an alcoholic treats the drink. There
is no such thing as just one taste for me. Abstinance brings me to
a better version of myself.

Disclaimer: Ketogenic diets are not a magic pill for everyone. It
works very well for me and I'm happy to talk to anyone about it,
but if you're into something else that's working for you, keep on
kicking butt. Now, back to more bacon & butter...
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Moleskine</title>
  <link>gopher://gopher.black/0/phlog/./20180621-moleskine/gophermap</link>
  <pubdate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubdate>
  <description><![CDATA[<pre>
----------------------------------------
Moleskine
June 21st, 2018
----------------------------------------

In 1997, Modo & Modo reintroduced the Moleskine notebooks to the
world, taking the design from 19th & 20th century french designs
as described in the writings of Bruce Chatwin. There's a lot of
mystique surrounding the design and use, but what they really
represent is a mass-market blank book with a solid design for
pocket use.

I started carrying Moleskine notebooks in 1998 and still carry
them today. In fact, in 2001 I bulk ordered them and have
a stockpile stored away just in case something weird happens in
Italy. They're fantastic books, not because of some magical
quality of manufacturing or design, but because they are cheap and
moderately well constructed. If they were built to last I would
have a harder time using them. That's the point I want to get at
in this phlog.

When I first started keeping a journal it was just that, a diary.
I wrote thoughts in it and dated them. They were serious and
heartfelt as only a teen can produce. They were horribly
embarrassing and trite. I wrote six pages one night on the deep
philosophy behind wanting to grow out my hair, a work of literary
genius that boiled down to the essence: "I like Highlander."

It took me a while to develop a system for using the notebooks
that really worked for me. In the end, my system boiled down to,
"turn the page and write". The key to using the notebooks
effectively was to not have a category or a use or anything.
I pick out one book at a time, turn the page, write whatever
I need, then turn the next page. There is no system beyond that.

I keep all of my Moleskines. They line a shelf in my office,
multiple rows and stacks. If you were to pick one up and thumb
through it you'd find ideas for stories, notes from D&D games,
shopping lists, phone numbers, sketches, notes from phone calls,
and any number of other random things. This is not a problem, this
is the heart of the notebook. It is a book for using, a book for
capturing the moment in the written word (or drawing) and moving
on. That's what makes it special.

Whenever I doubt myself in this, I'm reminded of Leonardo Da
Vinci's notebooks. He was possibly the greatest polymath in human
history and his greatest works are scribbled next to shopping
lists. He sketched anatomy next to questions about the volume of
water traveling in a river. The juxtaposition came from
a practical desire to not waste paper, and that's a bit of what
drives my choice as well. I don't want to spend a lot of money on
a blank book. If I do, I'll be scared to write in it for fear that
my words won't do it justice. I'll set it aside and give it
a grand purpose. I'll say to myself, "You can write only your
observations from meditation here." Or maybe, "This will be your
travel journal on your next trip to Iceland." In the end, it will
stay on my shelf, unused. Instead, the Moleskine in my pocket will
capture those notes along with everything else.

If the Moleskine design isn't for you, check out the US Army Green
Logbook. They're a standard with any quatermaster and can be found
in many places around the globe. They're cheap, plentiful, and get
the job done. You'll be hard pressed to find a military officer
that doesn't have a shelf of them at home.
</pre>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
